<xml><body><div>@r79@ @n31@</div>
<div>Judge into thand<em>es</em> of your officers, your Comissary</div>
<div>wolde have deliv<em>er</em>ed her by <em>pro</em>clamac<em>i</em>on as a gynteles</div>
<div><em>per</em>son, whereapon I cam in and said to Mr. Comissary</div>
<div>ye do not well to deliv<em>er</em> her by <em>pro</em>clamacion, ffor her</div>
<div>awn confession hath condempnid her</div>
<div>Than said Mr. Comissary be you able to <em>pro</em>ve that</div>
<div>you have spoken, And so caused me w<em>ith</em> many other</div>
<div>wurshipfull folke to Justifie, Than said I Sir awne</div>
<div>Confession is in your regestorie, Than Mr. Comissary</div>
<div>$n$ made answer and said I have enquired for theym, but</div>
<div>I cannot finde theym, but I will loke them oute for</div>
<div>shorting of the matter</div>
<div>Apon this the palme weke nexte after maister</div>
<div>Comissarye calling furthe many of his witnes</div>
<div>And did examen, So then he sent for me to examen</div>
<div>me. When I came to hym I said Ser I marvaile</div>
<div>why ye do thus troble yourself and other / yf ye</div>
<div>had sent to yo<em>ur </em>officer for her confession, ye sholde nede</div>
<div>$n$ no other besynes, than said he I have don so but I</div>
<div>cannot fynde theym, Than I made hym answer Sir</div>
<div>it ys not so for w<em>ith</em>in this ii daies thei were forth co<em>m</em>myng</div>
<div>Than said Mr. Comissary, can you fetche theym, And</div>
<div>I made answer no, I thinke Mr. Dra<em>per</em> will not deliv<em>er</em></div>
<div>theym unto me, but if it please you to send your <em>ser</em>v<em>a</em>nte</div>
<div>w<em>ith</em> me I am suer he will deliv<em>er</em> theym, And so he sent</div>
<div>his <em>ser</em>v<em>a</em>nte w<em>ith</em> me and I brought theym, And assone as</div>
<div>he had redde theym he dischargid v or mo of thair</div>
<div>examynac<em>i</em>on / And as all we toke it whiche were or</div>
<div>shoulde have ben exa<em>m</em>i<em>n</em>ed, yf o<em>ur</em> talis had not byn</div>
<div>according, it had ben for her discharge and to o<em>ur</em> high</div>
<div>rebuke</div>
<div>Then nexte Courte daye Appoynted for that matt<em>er</em></div>
<div>he declared her to be an heretique, both by her co<em>n</em>fession</div>
<div>and also by witnes, whiche thing she utterly denied</div>
<div>But then said he, you cannot deny it, but said to her</div></body></xml>