<xml><body>@r283@<br />$9$ It<em>e</em>m whyther they that woolde speke A gaynst Evyll/opynyons<br />dar not for yff they doo they be co<em>m</em>playned <del data-tag="del">off </del>on and called <del data-tag="del">seydyous</del><br />Sedyciouse personnes stieryng the people to co<em>m</em>mocions And by whom <br />they be so Callyd<br />To thys I sey I Remembre not to kno of Any such persones<br />$10$ It<em>e</em>m whether complayning to ther ordynarye at hys handys they gete<br />nothyng but dyplasure. And the party Evyll prechyng mych ffavor<em>e</em><br />and Boldener. And who hath had dysplesure of the ordynarye for<br />co<em>m</em>playnyng A gaynst yll prechers. And what yll p<em>re</em>chers hath had<br />ffav<em>or</em> &amp; Booldenes at ther<em>e</em> ordynares handes<br />To thys I awnswere that I remembre off no co<em>m</em>playntes made to <em>the</em> ordynary<br />other then Swych that mr Sayntleger &amp; I dyd put up A Booke at <br />my lordes graces co<em>m</em>maundement co<em>n</em>cernyng prechyng. As co<em>n</em>cernyng dysplesure<br />that we had or shall have for that I do / not kno of Any<br />$11$ It<em>e</em>m wher ii ymages off Cryst and ii of o<em>ur</em> lady where unto nether oblacyon<br />was done. nether lyght Standyng. were taken downe by tharchbysshoppys<br />co<em>m</em>mawndement. both by mowght &amp; by letters. And what Theffecte<br />of the letty<em>re</em>s was<br />To thys I Awnswere that I dyd not kno any oblacyon <del data-tag="del">and</del><add data-tag="add">nor </add>lyghtys set<br />be fore any of the seyd ymages. as y Remembre mr Co<em>m</em>myssary dyd <br />co<em>m</em>mawnded them to be pullyd downe yn my lorde Archbysshoppys Name<br />Thys was my lordes lett<em>er</em> as I can call to Remembrence co<em>n</em>cernyng the seyde<br />ymages // As I am Credably ynformyd that ther<em>e</em> be yn yo<em>ur</em> church<br />ymages Abused. Al such y wolde yo<em>u</em> sholde <del data-tag="del">pully </del>pul them <br />downe<br />$12$ It<em>e</em>m what woord my Baker sent from london by mr Serlys<br />To thys I Awnswere. I donot Remembre that the seyde mr Baker<br />dyd send any woord by <em>the</em> seyd mr Serlys</body></xml>