<xml><body><div>@r11@ @n3@</div>
<div>Upon this text, you must pray w<em>ith</em>out int<em>er</em>mission, he said</div>
<div>Som felowes say <em>that</em> this is impossible, but I shal tel you</div>
<div>good chris<em>ti</em>anes how to <em>per</em>forme this. It is a co<em>m</em>mon sayinge</div>
<div>in <em>the</em> lawe. That <em>that</em> a man doth by his <em>pro</em>ctor, he doth</div>
<div>it by hy<em>m</em>selfe. Wherfore whan thou art in <em>the</em> felde at</div>
<div>thy labour or otherwise occupied, hire <em>the</em> church to</div>
<div>pray for the (the church he called the preistes) &amp; so shalt</div>
<div>thou co<em>n</em>tinually pray.</div>
<div>He counceled laborynge men to divide their labour into</div>
<div>iii partes. To gyve one peny to <em>the</em> poore, an o<em>ther</em> to the</div>
<div>preistes to pray for they<em>m</em>, &amp; <em>the </em>iiide to kepe for they<em>m</em>selfes</div>
<div>&amp; their howseholdes.</div>
<div>He did discorage men fro<em>m</em> prayinge in <em>the</em> mother tonge,</div>
<div>sayinge. Som of you say <em>that</em> men can not pray in an</div>
<div>unknown tonge, bicause thay understonde not what</div>
<div>thay say. But I say <em>that</em> no man understondeth what</div>
<div>he prayeth, as saynt Paule saith. Nescit ho<em>mo</em> quom<em>odo</em> ora<em>n</em>du<em>m</em></div>
<div>sit, sed spiritus ho<em>m</em>inis docet quomodo orandum sit. And therfore</div>
<div>though you do not understande what you pray, yet</div>
<div>pray so stil.</div>
<div>16 Septembris in <em>the</em> chapt<em>er</em> howse.</div>
<div>$decrees$ Al the co<em>n</em>stitutions decrees &amp; ordina<em>n</em>ces of o<em>ur</em> holy mother</div>
<div>the church ar most godly, most holy, &amp; therfore ar to</div>
<div>obs<em>er</em>ved of al her children christen peple w<em>ith</em>out</div>
<div>disputynge or reasonynge of any of they<em>m</em>.</div>
<div>$III$ God dyd ingrave the hole power &amp; wisedome of the</div>
<div>trinitie in lucifer.</div>
<div>Sandwich al<em>ias</em> Gardin<em>er</em> at wye in lent was</div>
<div>xii month in <em>the</em> faire.</div>
<div>$+$ He playnly affirmed <em>the</em> state &amp; co<em>n</em>dition of <em>the</em> sowles de<em>par</em>ted.</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ Upon palme sonday <last past=""> last past he dyd execute in the cathedral church of</last></div>
<div>Canturbery &amp; halowed <em>the</em> palme &amp; songe hye masse w<em>ith</em>out decla-</div>
<div>ringe the ceremony</div>
<div>In festo pasche</div>
<div>He said ther be som <em>that</em> be no preistes, <em>that</em> do take opon they<em>m</em> to</div>
<div>minister <em>the</em> sacrame<em>n</em>tes.</div>
<div>2do septembris</div>
<div>Only love grafted Paule &amp; Mary Magdanele in Christ.</div>
<div>$ii$ He moved <em>the</em> peple to take away ageyne their beades &lt;matens, evynsonge &amp; vii psalmes&gt;, which</div>
<div>of late they had cast away by they<em>m that</em> p<em>re</em>ched agaynst al vocal</div>
<div>prayer</div></body></xml>