<xml><body>My lord I be sech yo<em>ur</em> grace be leve the Trewth / I kno that Many &amp; dyv<em>er</em>se<br />yn Caunt<em>erbury</em> doyth ffav<em>ur</em> me but lytylle. they <del data-tag="del">woolde </del>/ woolde fayne put me to<br />dysplesure. Thys do I ynsure yo<em>ur</em> grace, that for ev<em>er</em>y one <em>that</em> hath co<em>m</em>playned<br />unto yo<em>u</em> on me. I wyll bryng vi that shuld Testify that I p<em>re</em>ched <em>chr</em>istianly<br />&amp; quyatly And at <em>that</em> tyme <del data-tag="del">he </del><add data-tag="add">I</add> preched a gaynst such as woold <em>that</em> al prayer yn an<br />unkone Tung sholde be but Bablyng &amp; a gaynst such as semyth not to ffav<em>ur</em> the <br />erectyo<em>n</em> of ymages.<br />Item whether co<em>m</em>playing to <em>the</em> ordynary at hys handes they gete nothyng but<br />displesure and the <em>par</em>ty Evyll p<em>re</em>chyng mych ffav<em>ur</em> &amp; boldenes. And who he<br />had dysplesure of the ordynary for co<em>m</em>playnyng A gaynst Evyll p<em>re</em>chers and<br />what Evyll p<em>re</em>chers hath had ffev<em>ur</em> &amp; boldenes at <em>the</em> ordynares hendes<br />To thys I Awnswered that I <add data-tag="add">dyd </add> Reme<em>m</em>bre of no co<em>m</em>playntes made to the ordynares<br />other then such that mr Sayntleger &amp; I dyd put up yn A Booke ofto my<br />lord<em>es</em> grace at hys com<em>m</em>awndement co<em>n</em>cernyng p<em>re</em>chyng. As co<em>n</em>cernyng any dysple<br />sure that we have or shold have for hyt I do not kno of Any. <br />How be hyt syns that tyme I reme<em>m</em>bre the seyng of mr Garden<em>er</em> that he <br />$Gardin<em>er</em>$ co<em>m</em>playnyd &amp; p<em>re</em>sentyd <add data-tag="add">to my lordes grace</add> <em>the</em> Articles of mr Scory &amp; meyst<em>er</em> Rydley by <br />mowth. Resonyng wyth my lordes grace upon the same The seyde meyster<br />Garden<em>er</em> <add data-tag="add">y</add> had these woordes of my lord / mr Garden<em>er</em> yo<em>u</em> and yo<em>ur</em> Cu<em>m</em>pany doo<br />holde me Short. I wyll holde you as short.<br />I Richard p<em>ar</em>kehurst</body></xml>