<xml><body><div>@r123@</div>
<div>What co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on he had w<em>ith</em> parkehurst or Mr. Millis syns he</div>
<div>was put at libertie or w<em>ith</em> any other concernyng them that</div>
<div>cam to offer themselffes to testifie for Serls and Shether</div>
<div>What co<em>mmun</em>icat<em>i</em>on he had, or hard concernyng his co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on w<em>ith</em></div>
<div>tharchebisshop at London in passion weke was xii moneth</div>
<div>What co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on he had of any that had displeas<em>ur</em> of thordinary</div>
<div>for complaynyng of evill preachers / or favo<em>ur</em> of hym toward<em>es</em></div>
<div>evill preachers</div>
<div>What co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on he hadd or hard of doctour willoughbie</div>
<div>What co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on was hadd w<em>ith</em> my lorde wardens Chapleyn</div>
<div>What co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on he had or hard off Milles Scorye</div>
<div>Serls, Shether, or of any other /</div>
<div>What he said of the booke, that he delivered to my Lorde</div>
<div>syns his commyng to Canterburye</div>
<div>What movid hym to have conference w<em>ith</em> other in theis mattiers</div>
<div>contrarie to his othe and allegiaunce</div>
<div>What he knowith to be true of tharticles p<em>re</em>sentid againste</div>
<div>tharchebisshop of Canterburye, of his awn knowledge</div>
<div>Whither Mr. Smyth <em>par</em>son of Saincte Marie Mawdelen in</div>
<div>Canterburye had co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on with doctour Barbo<em>ur</em> in the</div>
<div>north courte of Christis churche of Canterburye, the same</div>
<div>daye, that Serls and Shether were callid before my Lorde</div>
<div>and what the co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on was</div>
<div>It<em>e</em>m why the same Smyth made as thoughe he wolde have</div>
<div>gone home, and than returned againe, and went to Maist<em>er</em></div>
<div>Parkehurste chamber, and there being Mr. Parkehurste</div>
<div>Mr. Gardener, Mr Milles, Mr. Serls, and Mr. Shether</div>
<div>It<em>e</em>m at that tyme whan my lorde sent for Mr. Serls and</div>
<div>Mr. Shether, why thei denied theym to be there / And what</div>
<div>co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on thei harde at that tyme /</div></body></xml>