<xml><body>@r281@<br />Articles send to me Richard parkehurste to make <del data-tag="del">A</del> Awnsswere<br />unto/by my lord off Caunt<em>erbury</em><br /><br />$1$ In p<em>ri</em>mis whether they p<em>re</em>sented unto Tharchbysshopp off Caunt<em>erbury</em> the selfsame<br />Arti<em>cles</em> that be co<em>n</em>teyned yn the Boke of co<em>m</em>playnt. or whether be more<br />or ffewer <del data-tag="del">off </del>or Su<em>m</em> Alt<em>er</em>ed by addycyon off woordes<br />To thys y Awnsswere. I had nev<em>er</em> the Boke off co<em>m</em>playnt yn my handes nor dyd<br /><del data-tag="del">here </del>Thorowly her<em>e</em> the<em>m</em> Red and but <del data-tag="del">very </del>ffew of them / same soych as <br />mr sayntleger &amp; I dyd put up to my lordes grace / Ther<em>e</em> ys yn the Boke off<br />co<em>m</em>playnt sum Addycyo<em>n</em> of woordes mo then mr Sayntleger &amp; I dyd put up<br />to my lord<br />$2$ It<em>e</em>m whether the wytnes browght yn. dyd <em>pro</em>ve al the Seyde Arti<em>cles</em>. <br />To thys I sey that I have no knolege whether <em>the</em> wytneses dyd <em>pro</em>ve the seyde<br />Arti<em>cles</em> or no. for y dyd nev<em>er</em> se the Booke off Examynacyo<em>n</em><br />$3$ It<em>e</em>m whether they lefte owte thre Arti<em>cles</em> that be for wer p<em>re</em>sented <br />To thys y sey that I was not of knolege what they wer <add data-tag="add">that were</add> lefte owte nether<br />yete why nor wherefor<em>e</em> the were lefte owte<br />$4$ It<em>e</em>m whether Tharchebysshopp of Caunt<em>erbury</em> dyd Rebuke Serlys for <em>that</em> he p<em>re</em>ched<br />that ymages myght be <em>per</em>mytted yn the Churche as rep<em>re</em>sentors off Saynttes <br />and not ydollys<br />To thys y sey that my lordes grace dyd challe<em>n</em>ge mr Serelys for p<em>re</em>chyng but I<br />do not Remembre that hys grace dyd Rebuke or chalenge the seyde mr Serelys<br />for that he p<em>re</em>ched that ymagys myght be <em>per</em>mytted yn the Church as repre-<br />sentors off Saynttes. thys I reme<em>m</em>bre well that my lordes grace Asked off mr<br />Serelys seyng / <del data-tag="del">Cuid</del> quid e<em>st</em> Idolu<em>m</em>. mr Serelys Awnsswered &amp; seyd. Idolum <br />est nich<em>i</em>ll / then seyd my lord / after the Greke ydolum &amp; ymago ar all one. then<br />Seyde mr Garden<em>er</em> <del data-tag="del">I ca<em>n</em>not tel</del> I kno not the Greke. But that ys Idolu<em>m</em> to<br />when hon<em>er</em> ys Gevyn wych sholde be Gevyn to cryst // Aft<em>er </em>that my lord seyde<br />that he had put yn iii prechers off the oolde lernyng &amp; iii of the new. The<em>n</em> <br />seyde mr Garden<em>er</em> that ys a mene to set A dyvysyon. then my lordes grace<br />seyde <add data-tag="add">as I remebre now</add> that hyt was the kynges plesure or the kynge woolde have hyt so / for the <br />Second parte that my lordes grace shold so sey yn the Co<em>n</em>systory. Threwly I was<br />not ther<em>e</em> wher<em>e</em> for y ca<em>n</em> sey nothyng to that<br />$ It<em>e</em>m whyther tharchBysshop dyd of <em>&lt;end of line missing&gt;</em><br />consystory <em>that</em> the kynges plesure was to have iii prechers of the new lernyng &amp; iii of tholde<br />Thys <del data-tag="del">Aw </del>ys Awnssweryd to yn the Arti<em>cle</em> wher<em>e</em> my lord dyd Rebuke mr Serlys for p<em>re</em>chyng$</body></xml>