<xml><body>@r221@<br />Int<em>er</em>rogatories for Gardin<em>er</em><br />how many bokes he knoweth have made of co<em>m</em>playntes<br />in this dioces, &amp; delyv<em>er</em>ed to any of the cowncel.<br /><del data-tag="del">ligne barrée illisible</del><br />what tyme th<em>at</em> booke was <add data-tag="add">first </add>delyv<em>er</em>ed to Doctor willoughby<br />&amp; what tyme it was aft<em>er</em> subscribed, &amp; what tyme he<br />w<em>ith </em>mr Parkehurst &amp; mr Shether. were sent for. to<br />com up to london.<br /><del data-tag="del">what letteres he wrote to the byshope of wynchester<br />by mr Shetheres <em>ser</em>vaunt</del><br />what tyme he co<em>m</em>maunded yonge Thacker to ryde<br />straight wayes to <del data-tag="del">my</del> the Bussshope of winchest<em>er</em>,<br /><del data-tag="del">as I</del> yf tharchbusshope of Cantturbery dyd sende for.<br />this deponent, &amp; for what purpose he so co<em>m</em>maunded hym,<br />&amp; what he willed hy<em>m</em> to say to the Busshope of <br />wynchest<em>er</em>, &amp; what co<em>n</em>forte he loked for. at hys handes<br />what tyme <em>the</em> boke called <em>the</em> un<em>per</em>fite boke, was<br />delyv<em>er</em>ed to Petitt<br />what was the teno<em>ur</em> of the last lettre of mr Shether.<br />unto the Busshope of wynchest<em>er</em>.<br />What notes he wrote for mr Shether<br />what he can say further of <del data-tag="del">my lect</del> tharchbusshope<br />lecture ad hebreos.<br />what co<em>mmun</em>ication he had w<em>ith</em> petitt of the article of the<br />sacrament of <em>the</em> aultare p<em>re</em>sented agaynst Scory.<br />Ad 1m<br />I know butt off one boke delyv<em>er</em>yd unto doctor wyllyby<br />butt whether he delyv<em>er</em>yd hytt unto <em>the</em> cowncell or nott I know<br />nott : Off an o<em>ther</em> boke <em>that</em> mr schether delyv<em>er</em>yd I knew<br />butt nott untyll he had delyv<em>er</em>yd hytt : and whatt was<br />co<em>n</em>taynyd In hytt. I know butt lytyll.<br />ad 2m<br />In the aft<em>er</em>weke the boke was delyv<em>er</em> unto doctor wyllyby : and w<em>ith</em><br />iii wekes aft<em>er</em> subsc<em>ri</em>byd. and uppo<em>n</em> sayntt georges day mr <em>par</em>khurst<br />mr schether &amp; I were In london w<em>ith</em> mr baker</body></xml>