<xml><body>@r273@<br />$E.$<em> Par</em>kehurst. <br />The second day off octobre yn the xxxvth yer<em>e</em> of o<em>ur </em>Suffere<em>n</em> lorde kynge henry<br />the viiith I Rychard parkehurst clerke was cu<em>m</em>mawnded upo<em>n</em> my Alegence<br />by my lord off Caunt<em>erbury </em>&amp; doctor lee to wryte such thyng<em>es</em> as I did kno co<em>n</em>cer-<br />nying A Booke sende up to the Cowncell. Thys I sey that A Booke<br />was delyv<em>ere</em>d to doctor wyllowby other by mr Garden<em>er</em> or mr Shether<br />to be <em>pre</em>sented to the Cowncell. And ansherd doctor wyllowby sey <del data-tag="del">he dyd</del><br /><del data-tag="del">delyver</del> the seyde Boke was delyu<em>er</em>ed to my lord off wynchestre / Mor<em>e</em> ov<em>er</em><br />mr Garden<em>er</em> Mr Schether &amp; I was send for by lett<em>re</em> off Mr deane off<br />Caunt<em>erbury</em> to cu<em>m</em> to london wher we al thre dyd Apere be ffor<em>e Sir</em> John Baker<br />knyght yn hys howse ther<em>e</em>. At the wych tyme the sayde John Baker dyd<br />Examen us off the <em>pre</em>chynges &amp; the <em>contro</em>versy off the same at Caunt<em>erbury</em> / And<br />as I Reme<em>m</em>bre the seyde Sir John Baker had a Booke of the same or we came <br />ther<em>e</em>. Then wylyng us to make a Boke of Suche thyng<em>es</em> as we dyd kno<br />wher upon at such tymys as I was yn Busenes w<em>ith sir</em> John Gagg knyght<br />ffor such mat<em>er</em>s as was by twene hym &amp; Me. Ther was a boke made<br />by the seyde mr Gardener &amp; mr Schether. the<em>n</em> we met al thre agayne<br />at the seyde sir John Bakers howse. wher<em>e</em> mr Garden<em>er</em> or mr Schether<br />woolde have had me to p<em>re</em>sent the seyde Booke / wych y dyd deny seyng<br />to them thyse woordes / yo<em>u</em> heve made thys Booke. What yo<em>u</em> heve put yn <br />hyt y am nott Sure. loke what I kno to be Trew I wyll Surely Testyffy<br />the same. Then dyd mr Schether p<em>re</em>sent the seyde Boke to <em>sir</em> John Baker <br />mr Garden<em>er</em> &amp; I beyng p<em>re</em>sent. Then the seyd <em>sir</em> John Baker seyde unto us<br />that he dyd kno the kyng<em>es</em> plesure wyllyng us to seythe Trewth fferyng <br />no Ma<em>n</em>. <del data-tag="del">Aft<em>er</em> thys doctor wyllowby at Caunt<em>erbury</em> seyde unto us theyse woord<em>es</em><br />that he had speke wyth the Cowncell Namyng Sir Antenye Brewne put you<br />in dowght yn hit yo<em>u</em> shall have goode sped yn hyt the mat<em>er</em> &amp; yo<em>u</em> mey<br />be glad that ev<em>er</em> yo<em>u</em> dyd Mene hyt</del>. Aft<em>er </em>that the seyde sir John Baker wyllyd <br />us to goo to my lord of Wynchestre to take hys Cowncell upon the Boke &amp; to see<br />whether <em>the</em> Boke was well set owt or No. &amp; so we dyd / Aft<em>er</em> <em>that</em> my lord off<br /></body></xml>