<xml><body><div>@r33@ @n8@</div>
<div>Orphewe curate of lyd.</div>
<div>$the bisshope of Rome$ he hath p<em>re</em>ched many tymes, &amp; yet he nev<em>er</em> p<em>re</em>ched agaynst </div>
<div>the usurped power of the Bushoppe of Rome, &amp; set</div>
<div>furth the kynges majesties sup<em>re</em>micie, or at the lest ev<em>er</em>y</div>
<div>quart<em>er </em>of a yeare, accordynge to the kynges <em>pro</em>clamations</div>
<div>and letteres</div>
<div>$pilgrimages$ he hath been a grete sett<em>er</em> forth of pilgrimages, fayned</div>
<div>reliques, &amp; other such su<em>pers</em>titions, &amp; yet never recan-</div>
<div>ted <em>the</em> same accordynge to <em>the</em> kynges inju<em>n</em>ctions</div>
<div>he hath not declared in goinge of <em>pro</em>cession that better it</div>
<div>were to omitt <em>the</em> letany, than the other suffrages</div>
<div>folowinge, accordynge to <em>the</em> said inju<em>n</em>ctions.</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ Opon <em>the</em> sondayes, candlemas day, Ashwednesday,</div>
<div>palme sonday &amp; good friday, he hath not declared</div>
<div><em>the</em> true use of holy breade, holy wat<em>er &amp;</em> other cere-</div>
<div>monies used those dayes, accordynge to <em>the</em> said <em>pro</em>clama-</div>
<div>tions. Thomas Strogle. Eve Bat. Thomas Atye.</div>
<div>Mr Barowe towne clerke. Mr Moore wi<em>th</em> other of lyd.</div>
<div>The curate of Stodm<em>er</em>sh.</div>
<div>$lent$ he dyd dissuade men from etynge of whytmeate the</div>
<div>last lent, &amp; rebuked they<em>m that</em> dyd eate whyt meate.</div>
<div>wytnes Godfray w<em>ith</em> other of <em>the</em> parish.</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ Opon candlemas day<ash wensday="" palme="" sonday="" good="" friday=""> Ashwensday, palme sonday, good friday he dyd not declare the true use</ash></div>
<div>of <em>the</em> ceremonies used those dayes, as he is bownde</div>
<div>by <em>the</em> kynges <em>pro</em>clamations.</div>
<div>About al halowe tyde was xii month he p<em>re</em>ched in saynt</div>
<div>Du<em>n</em>stanes church beside Canturbery, <em>that</em> men sholde be</div>
<div>$n$ love god &amp; feare god, must but not to trust hy<em>m</em> to moch.</div>
<div>william laflynge, Michel wryght, willi<em>a</em>m Reve, John</div>
<div>Bodwarde, Christofor henry, &amp; other of <em>the</em> same</div>
<div>parish</div>
<div>Turno<em>ur</em></div>
<div>$holy wat<em>er</em>$ In <em>the</em> tyme of his being at Chartam he dyd cast no holy</div>
<div>wat<em>er</em> neither bifore <em>the</em> sacrament, not opon any aultar</div>
<div>in <em>the</em> church, nor also bifore <em>the</em> crucifix in <em>the</em> rode loft,</div>
<div>accordynge to <em>the</em> laudable ceremonies etc.</div>
<div>he christened iii children opon on day, &amp; dyd not anoynt</div>
<div>$holy oyle$ they<em>m</em> with holy oyle, neither opon <em>the</em> backe nor bely.</div></body></xml>