<xml><body><div>The viker of Betrisden</div>
<div>$holy water$ he dyd send a lett<em>er</em> to a woman of his parish <em>that</em> sent to</div>
<div>hy<em>m</em> for counsel for a disease, that she sholde take holy water</div>
<div>&amp; say certen wordes w<em>ith</em> other sorcery.</div>
<div>John Thatcher the younger.</div>
<div>He said <em>that the</em> bible was made by <em>the</em> devil.</div>
<div>The vicar of saynt paules in Canturbery</div>
<div>$lent$ He dyd dissuade one Cruse of his parish fro<em>m</em> etynge of</div>
<div>whitmete in lent last past, &amp; rebuked hy<em>m</em> therfore</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ He hath not declared <em>the</em> good use of the good <good> ceremonyes</good></div>
<div>used of Ashwednesday, palme sonday, good friday, cand-</div>
<div>mas day etc.</div>
<div>$n$ He said, this is now <em>the</em> iiide tyme <em>that</em> Englande hath</div>
<div>been out of the feith.</div>
<div>Estwell</div>
<div>$Images$ There is an ymage of our Lady at Eastwell yet standinge wherunto was</div>
<div>contynuall oblacion in tymes past of monney whiche ymage had also a</div>
<div>coote fixed w<em>ith</em> pence.</div>
<div>The ymage of saincte George in saincte Georges church in Caunterbury</div>
<div>whiche was taken downe by the kinges l<em>ett</em>re is nowe set up agayn</div>
<div>unto the whiche ymage before that tyme was oblac<em>i</em>on made</div>
<div>William Quylter of Staple gentilman</div>
<div>$Injunctions$ $n$ Whatsoever was doon in the name of god was well doon.</div>
<div>The same William being churchewarden and hed of the parrishe hath</div>
<div>neclected the kinges maiesties Iniunctions geven the xxviiith of yere</div>
<div>of his Reigne and is not yet fulfilled, wheras every parrishe is</div>
<div>not yet fulfilled is commaunded to prepare a chest w<em>ith</em> ii lockes</div>
<div>and ii keyes of the co<em>m</em>mune goodes of the churche for the same keping</div>
<div>of a booke or Regestre of the names of all them that be married,</div>
<div>christened and buried</div>
<div>The parsonne of Milton besides Caunterbury</div>
<div>$Images$ He had in his churche of Milton an ymage of sainct margaret to</div>
<div>whiche was a co<em>m</em>mon pilgremage, and caused it to be taken down</div>
<div>And uppon saincte margaretis day last past Mr John Cros somtyme</div>
<div>$n$ Cellerer of Christchurche cam to the same churche and did set up</div>
<div>the same ymage agayn w<em>ith</em> a garland of flowers on the hed of it</div>
<div>$thys chaplane was a ob<em>ser</em>vand &amp; he a mogke$ and did strowe the churche and said mas there.</div></body></xml>