<xml><body>@r255@<br />Edmond Schethers answer ot the 13 Articles<br />To <em>the</em> first : I know not <em>the</em> begynn<em>er</em>s of thes matters at london but I think<br />$1$ t<em>hat</em> Mr serles talked w<em>ith</em> doctor london of them as he cam fro<em>m</em> cant<em>erbury</em> to oxon<em>ford</em> And<br />$D willoughby$ I think also t<em>hat</em> mr Williby moved such matt<em>er</em>s much ther by reson he said <em>that</em><br />he had spoken w<em>ith </em>many of the king<em>es</em> cownsell in it &amp; that he wold take upon<br />him to be the hole sett<em>er</em> forth of <em>the</em> matt<em>er</em>. Aft<em>er </em>the w<em>hich</em> woordes Mr baker did <br />send for mr p<em>ar</em>khurst mr garden<em>er</em> &amp; me. <br />$2$ I know none <em>that</em> gave cownsell ther but I think <em>that</em> mr williby did much of his<br />own hedde.<br />$3$ I know not who consend ther in the matt<em>er</em> other wise then as I have said <em>that</em><br />$Mr Baker vintomen D. london$ mr baker shewd us the book the which my lord of wy<em>n</em>chest<em>er</em> rede &amp; doctor lo<em>n</em>don<br />took the names of <em>the</em> witnes of the same.<br />I know no grownd thei hadd but I think t<em>hat </em>the co<em>m</em>mi<em>n</em>g of S<em>ir</em> t<em>ur</em>ner &amp; S<em>ir </em>a<em>n</em>thony<br />$4$ p<em>ar</em>son &amp; other owt of other dioces in to this. And the resort <em>that</em> was so fare<br />of : to Sir t<em>ur</em>ners s<em>er</em>mons: And the s<em>u</em>bscribing of Sir bland to his articles as it <br />is said: And the redi<em>n</em>g of sir anthony p<em>ar</em>son of <em>the</em> bible &amp; other w<em>ith</em> addi<em>n</em>g ther<br />expositions to <em>the</em> same was a gret occasion of it/<br />$5$ I know not who declared any grownd ther but I think mr williby shewd<br />the book &amp; moved the mat<em>ter</em> much ther<br />$n 6$ I know no matters ony in london knoweth my lord<em>es</em> grace culpable in but <br />in such articles as mast<em>er</em> baker willed us to say what we hard we did<br /><br />$Coxson Gardin<em>er</em>$ I know not the begyn<em>er</em> of it in cant<em>erbury</em> but I suspect Mr coxston &amp; Mr garden<em>er</em> by <br />$1$ reyso <em>that</em> coxston did use to write all such matt<em>er</em>s And many articles of the <br />book wer known only to Mr gardener./. As for other matt<em>er</em>s the fame was grete<br />$2$ I know none t<em>hat</em> was the p<em>ro</em>moter but Mr garden<em>er</em> &amp; williby as towchi<em>n</em>g <em>the</em> booke<br />$Gardin<em>er</em> Willoughby$ befor such tyme that it was subscribed then the witnes wer all of cownsell.<br />t<em>hat</em> mr williby hadd the book<br />Mr garden<em>er</em> &amp; williby co<em>n</em>ferd to gither befor Mr williby receved the book &amp; after <br />$3$ such as s<em>u</em>bscribed talked of the articles sometyme &amp; of other articles as we <br />hard them spoken.<br />I know no grownd but I thinke as I have said in the 4 article above and<br />$4$ also bicause the <em>pro</em>rses aganst Mr rydley &amp; scory went not forth as against <br />mr serles &amp; me: Also bycause Joan barnes, gilles barra<em>m</em>, bukm<em>er</em> &amp; o<em>ther</em> of whom<br />much talking was of: wer not poonisshed. &amp; other matt<em>er</em>s w<em>hich</em> I reme<em>m</em>ber not t<em>hat</em><br />men said wer much borne<br />$5$ I do not know what knowledge other me<em>n</em> hadd.<br />$n$ I have hard me<em>n</em> say many thing<em>es</em> as that my lord did know of bukm<em>er</em>s opynio<em>n</em><br />$6$ of Joan barnes opynio<em>n</em>: that gilles of barram used the office of a prest being no<br />prest &amp; other thing<em>es</em> w<em>hich</em> wer not reformed but thes thing<em>es</em> manye wer done befor<br />I cam in to thes p<em>ar</em>tes &amp; wherin <del data-tag="del">he </del>my lord<em>es</em> grace is culpable it is not in <br />me to say nor I know not what other do know my lord to be culpable in</body></xml>