<xml><body>$4$ It<em>e</em>m whether Serlys and Schether wer Accused by men wych wer<em>e</em> notyd<br />by co<em>m</em>mon ffame to be off Evyll opynyon for p<em>re</em>chynge &amp; who they wer<em>e</em> <br />that dyd accuse them<br />To thys I Awnsswere that I dyd not kno ther<em>e</em> Accusers<br />$6$ It<em>e</em>m whether the honest of ther<em>e</em> Audyence offerd them Selvys to<br />Testyfye that they wer ffalsly Accused. and that wych was leyde <del data-tag="del">age</del><br />Agaynst them was not Trewe. And Althow they wer<em>e</em> a grete Nu<em>m</em>bre<br />yete cowde not be Admytted. And who they wer<em>e</em> that so offred theme<br />Selvys. And whyther they offered them Selvys or Serelys Requyred <br />the<em>m</em> to be Examyned<br />To thys I sey as I remebre that ther<em>e</em> was dyv<em>er</em>se <del data-tag="del">dyv<em>er</em>se </del>came. I thynke browght<br />yn by mr Serlys. and wer<em>e</em> not Examyned. Whether they offered them<br />Selvys to Swere or any requyryng for them to be Sworne I am not Suer<br />ther<em>e</em> off but ther<em>e</em> certen <add data-tag="add">that dyd</add> Apere. I thynke Surely for <em>the</em> Same purpose<br />$7$ It<em>e</em>m whether ffalce <em>per</em>sonnes men of Evill fame for suspecte opynyons<br />Though they wer<em>e</em> but ii or iii wer<em>e</em> admytted<br />To thys I Awnsswere as I dyd Afore I dyd not kno ther<em>e</em> Accusers<br />$8$ It<em>e</em>m whether Serelys <add data-tag="add">&amp; Schether </add>wer<em>e</em> Innocent p<em>re</em>chers. and so beyng Innocent<br />were co<em>n</em>dempned Thone to preson. and Thother to Reade a declara<em>ci</em>on <br />off ffalce Surmysed Arti<em>cles</em> &amp; by whom thone was co<em>m</em>mytted to p<em>re</em>son. <br />To thys I sey for the ffyrst <em>par</em>te I my selffe have herd the<em>m</em> dyv<em>er</em>se Tymys<br />prech. I nev<em>er</em> dyd <em>per</em>ceve yn my heryng but that they dyd preche well and<br />war Innocence for p<em>re</em>cheyng yll / mr Schether was Co<em>m</em>mawnded to <br />declare hys Articles upon A Stole I thynke by My lord of Cant<em>erbury</em>. mr<br /><del data-tag="del">Schether </del><add data-tag="add">Serlys </add>co<em>m</em>mawnded to preson at Whoys co<em>m</em>mawndement I ca<em>n</em> not tell<br />but by my lordes grace seyng at shall be by the Cowncell</body></xml>