<xml><body>@r305@<br />At my last beyng wyth yo<em>ur</em> grace. you requyryd me to say whether <em>that</em> I dyd<br />subscrybe to certay<em>n</em> artycles wych mr shether dyd affyrme my hand to be unto<br />wych <del data-tag="del">to be true</del> as then I dyd not reme<em>m</em>bre <del data-tag="del">that </del>to be true. So I do not <del data-tag="del">more </del>yet<br />reme<em>m</em>bre that to be true <em>that</em> I have subscrybyd to any other artycle the<em>n</em> one<br />But yff heraft<em>er</em> mr shether or any other ca<em>n</em> put me yn reme<em>m</em>bra<em>n</em>ce theroff  <br />&amp; <em>that</em> I have subscrybyd wych yff yt be was don off my part unadvysedly<br />Thys shall be to desyre yo<em>ur</em> grace to take thys my delyberatyd a<em>n</em>swer to one<br />off the ynterrogatorys take<em>n</em> owt off thone artycle co<em>n</em>cerny<em>n</em>g yo<em>ur </em>grace hys co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n<br /></em>wyth mr serlys to the wych so sode<em>n</em>ly for lake off full reme<em>m</em>bra<em>n</em>ce I could not the<em>n</em> <br />fully a<em>n</em>swer And my a<em>n</em>swer ys thys. <em>that</em> serlys sayd <em>that</em> ymages puttyng<del data-tag="del">es</del> us yn<br />reme<em>m</em>bra<em>n</em>s by the waye off representecyo<em>n</em> off the actes &amp; factes off say<em>n</em>tes wer<br />ymages &amp; no ydolles. And the<em>n</em> yo<em>ur</em> grace sayd <em>that</em> an ymage &amp; an <del data-tag="del">ydyll </del>ydoll<br />wer one. Then sayd serlys Idolu<em>m</em> nihil e<em>st</em>. The<em>n</em> sayd yo<em>ur </em>grace I tell you<br />they be all one. Then sayd mr garden<em>er</em> an ymage ys no Idoll except <br /><em>that</em> a ma<em>n</em> do put <em>quid numinis</em> yn yt The<em>n</em> sayd yo<em>ur</em> grace you kwo not the <br />greke for yn the greke Idolu<em>m</em> &amp; Imago be one. Then sayd he thoze I kow<br />not the greke yet I trust <em>that</em> I do kowe the troth. And thys ys as mych as<br />I ca<em>n</em> say, to <em>that</em> artycle whether my hand be to yt or not.  <br /><br />And to the other I do desyre yo<em>ur</em> grace to accept thys a<em>n</em>swer <em>that</em> at one tyme<br />I yntreatyng off the meane <add data-tag="add">places </add>as yt was setforth by the kynges boke <em>that</em> was<br />subscrybyd by yo<em>ur</em> grace &amp; dyv<em>er</em>s off the clergy, &amp; dyd nothyng by <em>con</em>fyrme the<br />same. I aft<em>er</em>ward was <em>com</em>playny<em>n</em>g on to yo<em>ur</em> grace &amp; yo<em>ur</em> grace gave me then<br />a <em>comm</em>ande<em>me</em>nt to set <em>that</em> matt<em>er</em> no otherwyse <del data-tag="del">forth othe</del> then the latt<em>er</em> <em>par</em>t off the usage<br />off p<em>r</em>yyng dyd lede nother addy<em>n</em>g ther unto nor dymynyshy<em>n</em>g And yn other<br />matters yo<em>ur</em> grace <em>com</em>au<em>n</em>dyd <em>that</em> no ynveacyo<em>n</em> shulde be off any <em>par</em>t yn the pulpett<br />wherfor I as other durst not ynvay agay<em>n</em>st su<em>m</em> (as we thogt) suspect preachy<em>n</em>g<br />lesse we shuld be notyd authors off sedytyo<em>n</em> as mr garden<em>er</em> was accusyd to yo<em>ur</em> grace<br />as he sayd to have made ii sedytyouse <em>ser</em>mo<em>n</em>s, &amp; mr garden<em>er</em> I mr serlys &amp; shether<br />have be<em>n</em> callyd kavys by one hiero<em>m</em> oxe<em>n</em>bryge bruar yn say<em>n</em>t georges yn ca<em>n</em>te<em>rbury</em><br />for o<em>ur</em> p<em>re</em>chyng<em>es</em>. as boyton <em>ser</em>vant to mr cryppys &amp; dwelly<em>n</em>g yn norgate ca<em>n</em> testyfy<br />And that <del data-tag="del">any man</del> <add data-tag="add">sum </add>shuld have dyspleasure off yo<em>ur</em> grace amo<em>n</em>gst us. mr garden<em>er</em>s ha<em>n</em>d<br />apperyth yn mr sentlegers kepyng wych exp<em>re</em>ssyth <em>that</em> yn co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em> betwyxt yo<em>ur</em> grace<br />&amp; hy<em>m</em> yo<em>ur</em> grace shuld say <em>that</em> ther was a sort sett agay<em>n</em>st you but you wold<br />be evyn wyth them. But for <em>com</em>playntes made to theordynary &amp; no <del data-tag="del">ys</del> yust redy<br />fownd. I kowe not except yt be sayd for the non ponyshyment off rydly<br />&amp; scory. or for the undecent behavy<em>or</em> yn hys apparell off gyles off bara<em>m<br /></em>off whom mr hardes certyfyyd yo<em>ur</em> grace as I herd hy<em>m</em> saye ; And thys ys<br />asmych as I ca<em>n</em> now reme<em>m</em>bre to certyfye yo<em>ur</em> grace to the other artycle <em>that</em> mr <br />shether shulde say <del data-tag="del">me </del>my hand to be unto wych I reme<em>m</em>bre not ;<br /><br />By me John myllys<br /><br /><br /><br />  <br /><br /></body></xml>