<xml><body><div>@r77@ @n30@</div>
<div>$Imag<em>es</em>$ He pulled down the Images in Northgate churche</div>
<div>and had home to his house the pictures of o<em>ur l</em>ady / with</div>
<div>the tabernacle, Hewid her all in pec<em>es</em> w<em>ith</em> div<em>er</em>s oth<em>er</em></div>
<div>pictures of thappostells</div>
<div>He co<em>m</em>manded Anthony <em>par</em>sons to reade and expounde</div>
<div>the bible upon palme sondaye last paste in alhalowe</div>
<div>churche of Canterburye, whiche when the <em>par</em>son denied</div>
<div>$n$ he brought a token frome Mr. Comissary so to do /</div>
<div>wherby he did reade, and it is said that by suffer<em>a</em>unce</div>
<div>of hym and suche other evill <em>per</em>sons, hath caused such</div>
<div>myscheve in his Dioc<em>ese</em></div>
<div>$Imag<em>es</em>$ He caused Images to be hewen in pec<em>es</em> at Assheforthe</div>
<div>and compellid the curate there to saye that he did it</div>
<div>John Norton. Tho<em>mas</em> Burvier. S<em>ir</em> John Calton. Antony Bourne. Ro<em>bert</em> Hal.</div>
<div>It<em>e</em>m he did caste the <em>par</em>son of pevyngtons bead<em>es</em> into <em>the</em></div>
<div>fure in dirision and gave hym a peny for theym</div>
<div>Mr. Docto<em>ur</em> Nevenson in lent was xii monethe</div>
<div>$Confession$ Rebuked one Sir Johne write preiste dwelling</div>
<div>in saincte Alpheis, because he wolde not absolve</div>
<div>Barthylmew Joye w<em>ith</em>oute any confession made</div>
<div>of any cryme or fawte, As the said S<em>ir</em> wryght</div>
<div>can testifie</div>
<div>Raynolde Buckemer of Boxley taken before S<em>ir</em></div>
<div><em>Christ</em>ofer hall<em>es</em> knyght at maidestone the xxxii</div>
<div>yere of the kyng<em>es</em> moost honorable reign for a</div>
<div>sacramentary was deliv<em>er</em>ed in wryting to Mr.</div>
<div>Nevynson Comissary by harry Cleke servant to</div>
<div>the said S<em>ir Christ</em>ofer w<em>ith</em> his detection by Raf Joneson</div></body></xml>