<xml><body><div>@r15@ @n5@</div>
<div>The vicar of Chillam.</div>
<div>$inco<em>n</em>tine<em>nc</em>ie$ The fame is <em>that</em> he kepeth an other manes wife.</div>
<div>He hath not declared to his parish <em>that the</em> evyns of abrogate</div>
<div>holydayes be no fastynge dayes, as <em>the</em> kynges co<em>m</em>maundment is, </div>
<div>neither he hath declared <em>the</em> good use of the ceremonies, beringe</div>
<div>of candelles &amp; palmes, crepinge of the crosse on good friday,</div>
<div>gyvinge of Ashes on Ash wednesday, nether he hath decla-</div>
<div>red <em>the</em> ceremony of holy brede &amp; holy wat<em>er</em>, accordynge to</div>
<div><em>the</em> kynges graces <em>pro</em>clamation.</div>
<div>Mr <em>Par</em>kehurst <em>pre</em>bendary.</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ Opon palme sonday was xii month he did execute in <em>the</em></div>
<div>cathedral church, &amp; halowed <em>the</em> palmes, &amp; songe hye masse,</div>
<div>&amp; did not declare the use of that ceremonie accordynge to</div>
<div>the kynges graces <em>pro</em>clamation</div>
<div>He hath ii benefices w<em>ith</em> cure Ashforth &amp; limmynge, &amp; hath no</div>
<div>$n$ dispensation. The institutions wil declare this matt<em>er</em>.</div>
<div>He may dispende in benefices &amp; o<em>ther</em> sp<em>irit</em>ual<em> pro</em>motions C £ by</div>
<div>yere &amp; above, &amp; yet he doth fynde no scoler. at the univ<em>er</em>-</div>
<div>sities accordynge to the kynges maiestie inju<em>n</em>ctions.</div>
<div>$Memorandum to examyn hy<em>m</em> ageyn opon a bil p<em>re</em>sented Andrewe Rayne. and And to examyn thies wytnesses Henry Hawker. William Gibbes. Tho. Woroit<em>er</em>. Willi<em>a</em>m Horden. Rog<em>er</em> Hal. Henry Reg and <em>the</em> mydwife$ Sir laurence curat of Chalocke</div>
<div>whan, He wil not christen childre untyl he have</div>
<div>taken <em>the</em> mydwife aside, &amp; ther doth make her to swere</div>
<div>opon a boke to answer to certen questions, nether he</div>
<div>nor the mydwife wil shewe the questions but to <em>the</em> </div>
<div>ordinary.</div>
<div>The vicar of Tenterden</div>
<div>He hath not put out of the mannel which he dayly</div>
<div>$the Busshope of Rome$ useth the Busshope of Romes name, his usurped auto-</div>
<div>ritie &amp; pardon expressed in the rubricke &amp; last absolution</div>
<div>of extreme unction.</div>
<div>The <em>par</em>son of Riple</div>
<div>$pater noster in English$ He said openly in his parish. I am co<em>m</em>maunded to shewe</div>
<div>$n$ you <em>the</em> pat<em>er</em> nost<em>er</em> in English, you may do as you wil</div>
<div>in lernynge of it, but it is agaynst myn opinion.</div>
<div>ffor I licken <em>the</em> pat<em>er</em> nost<em>er</em> in English to the harde shel</div>
<div>of a nutt, &amp; <em>the</em> pat<em>er</em> nost<em>er</em> in laten to <em>the</em> swete kernel.</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ He dyd not declare the use of halowed palmes, asshes, </div>
<div>candelles, holy brede &amp; holy watt<em>er</em>.</div></body></xml>