<xml><body><div>@r37@ @n10@</div>
<div>The Vicar of Chilham named</div>
<div>Doctour willoughbye</div>
<div>$a Shryne$ In primis why the said vicar of Chilham having speciall</div>
<div>comandement by vertue of the kinges highnes le<em>tt</em>res frome hull,</div>
<div>doith yet kepe in his churche a certeyn Shryne gilted named </div>
<div>saincte Austens shryne, w<em>hi</em>ch shrine was conveyed frome saincte</div>
<div>$n$ Austens in Canterbury unto the parishe churche of Chilham at</div>
<div>the suppression of the monesterye, of saincte Austens</div>
<div>$Images$ It<em>e</em>m a rode there w<em>hi</em>ch had shoes of sylver, being a monume<em>n</em>t</div>
<div>of pilgrymage or offering standith yet still, being only</div>
<div>spoiled of the monumente / Mr. Co<em>m</em>myssary can tell of it</div>
<div>$Images$ It<em>e</em>m he said that ymages had powre of god to helpe sicke</div>
<div>people vowing unto theym, the example co<em>mmun</em>ication then being </div>
<div>of o<em>ur</em> ladie of Cutupstrete, betwene the said vicar and one</div>
<div>Dawson of Charteham myller, being present Mr. petite</div>
<div>the chauntry preste of Chiham, and the parishe preiste of</div>
<div>Chih Chilham</div>
<div>$Inco<em>n</em>tine<em>n</em>cie$ M<em>emorandum</em> of his incontynencye to examen Stryngar and his wife</div>
<div>and the curate of Molishe</div>
<div>M<em>emorandum</em> that Potters wife was banyshed oute of ffev<em>er</em>sham for</div>
<div>her susspecte lyving with Docto<em>r</em> Willoughby, and also was</div>
<div>compellid to forsake Chilham for the same aboute ii or iii</div>
<div>yeres paste, and yet she remayneth in the company of</div>
<div>the said docto<em>r</em></div>
<div>Wherfore he reported in Canterbury and Chilham aboute</div>
<div>Whitesontide laste paste, that iii or IIII of<iiii of=""> my lorde of Canterburys</iiii></div>
<div>servantes wolde have bett hym, and howe thei knewe that thei</div>
<div>were my lorde of Canterburies servantes. ffriderickes widowe</div>
<div>of saynte Elphies, leonarde Stryngar.</div>
<div>It<em>e</em>m whither thei he did not ymagen that thei were his serv<em>a</em>untes</div>
<div>to bring hym and his <em>ser</em>v<em>a</em>untes into slander</div></body></xml>