<xml><body>@r195@<br />then I w<em>ith</em> other schuld abyde the utt<em>er</em>most : Thys fferyng. I desyryd<br />hys lordshypp yff remedy mygthe be : thatt we mygthe (yff nede wer have <br />lyberty to apele : I wrote also thatt I was examynyd beffore doctor cokkes<br />ffor the boke delyv<em>er</em>yd unto the cowncell : And my answere was thys.<br />thatt I was w<em>ith</em> the cowncell att london : butt <add data-tag="add">whatt </add>I saw ther : whatt I sayde<br />ther : and whatt was sayde unto me : I dyrst nott dysclose : unlesse the<br />cowncell wold have me to dysclose :. I desyryd hym also thatt yff I<br />had nede : thatt he wold so labor and doo ffor us : thatt ffor ow<em>r</em> trewgth<br />we mygthe nott be undon.<br />My lordes answere nott by l<em>ettr</em>es : butt by mowgthe<br />sentt by mr Schethers <em>ser</em>vantt : nott unto me / as<br />by the wordes hytt dothe apere : but rather <br />made unto mast<em>er</em> schether.<br />When my lord had redd my l<em>ett</em>res (as the <em>ser</em>vantt sayde) he askyd : whoo<br />browgthe thes l<em>ett</em>res : The <em>ser</em>vantt sayde : I : my lord then wentt a<br />way. and as the <em>ser</em>vantt supposyd) Into <em>the</em> cowncell chamber. when<br />came fforthe: The <em>ser</em>vantt requyryd hys plaesure : he sayde : have me :<br />co<em>m</em>mendyd unto yowr m<em>aster</em> : The <em>ser</em>va<em>n</em>tt desyryd hys lordshypp to have<br />sume co<em>n</em>ffortable answere off hym : my lord sayde : I can make yow<br />noo answere (as yett) The nextt day or II dayis after : when the <em>ser</em>va<em>n</em>tt<br />came a gen ffor hys answere my lord : sayde unto hym : yow<em>r</em> m<em>aster</em><br />semythe to be a chyld : he weptt be ffore my lord when he schuld<br />have answeryd : Byd hym <add data-tag="add">nott </add>wepe ffor schame : but answere lyke a<br />man : wyll he be a chyld now : lett hym take a good hartt unto <br />hym : yff he have nede : he schall ffynd ffrendes : Then sayde<br />the <em>ser</em>vantt : I p<em>ra</em>y yow<em>r </em>lordschypp be good unto hym : my lord sayde :<br />have me co<em>m</em>mendyd : unto hym : I wylnott fforgett : hym : and doo<br />as myche ffor hym as I can : I must know off the cowncell :<br />what I schall doo : I warra<em>n</em>tt yow. I wylnott fforgott hym : have<br />me co<em>m</em>mendyd also unto the p<em>re</em>bendarys : he namyd none &amp; so dymy-<br />ssyd the <em>ser</em>vant :<br />$forde$ Ther stode one by brother In law unto mr Schether : whoys name ys fforde<br />And my lord de<em>par</em>tyd he had communycatyon w<em>ith</em> mr schethers <em>ser</em>vantt : off whatt</body></xml>