<xml><body><div>Mr<em> Par</em>kehurst p<em>re</em>bendary.</div>
<div>He hath not made yerly <em>the</em> ten <em>ser</em>mons in <em>the</em> co<em>n</em>trey,</div>
<div>which he is bownde to do by <em>that</em> he is p<em>re</em>bendary.</div>
<div>$the busshope of Rome$ He hath not in his own <em>per</em>son <em>pre</em>ched in his church</div>
<div>at Ashforde agaynst <em>the</em> usurpation of the Busshope of</div>
<div>Rome, &amp; set out the kynges maiestie sup<em>re</em>micie accordynge</div>
<div>to his maiesties lettres, inju<em>n</em>ctions, &amp; <em>pro</em>clamations, nether</div>
<div>hath he declared to his parish the difference bitwene</div>
<div>ceremonies &amp; workes co<em>m</em>maunded by god, nether hath</div>
<div>he shewed the right use of the said ceremonies &amp;</div>
<div>the sup<em>er</em>stitions used hertofore by they<em>m</em>, accordynge to</div>
<div>the said letteres, inju<em>n</em>ctions and proclamations</div>
<div>$proclamations$ He hath not declared in his parish <em>that</em> the evyns of</div>
<div>such sayntes as be abrogated to be no fastynge dayes.</div>
<div>Henry laurence of Rayname</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ He co<em>m</em>maunded the clerke to brynge no holy wat<em>er</em> to his</div>
<div>howse, &amp; sayd it was good to fray <em>the</em> spretes of the buttr</div>
<div>Bartilmewe the surgeon</div>
<div>$images$ He said to Willi<em>a</em>m Burges gen<em>er</em>al apparitor. Thou art he</div>
<div><em>that</em> wolde have pulled downe our saynt George, but</div>
<div>yo<em>ur</em> mast<em>er</em> lyeth by <em>the</em> hele, &amp; we have shewed the</div>
<div>takynge downe th<em>er</em>of to the kynges cowncel, &amp; were byd</div>
<div>set it up agayne.</div>
<div>Blande <em>the</em> iiii of ffebruary last at Boughton</div>
<div>$Thomas Hawkins, Thomas Porrich. Raynolde Smith, Sir John Legate. &amp; <em>the</em> vicar there of Boughton$ ffastynge <em>pro</em>fiteth no thynge one tyme mor than other.</div>
<div>He rayled of <em>the</em> light bifore <em>the</em> sacrament, and <em>the</em> cloth</div>
<div><em>that</em> lay bifore <em>the</em> aultar, of <em>the</em> orname<em>n</em>tes of <em>the</em> church.</div>
<div>he defaced a chaple at Ospringe, pulled downe <em>the</em> images, and solde al the stuff.</div>
<div>Thomas Gymlot al<em>ias</em> Barbo<em>ur</em></div>
<div>The parish of Buckland co<em>m</em>playneth <em>that</em> he beinge</div>
<div>a lay man hath <em>the</em> vicarege ther gyven unto hy<em>m</em></div>
<div>under <em>the</em> kynges brode seale, &amp; he causeth not <em>the</em> cure</div>
<div>to be <em>ser</em>ved as of right apperteyneth, but they be</div>
<div>fayne of their own charges to fynde a curate.</div></body></xml>