<xml><body>@r215@<br />then In hartt desyrusse to have a godly quyetnesse<br />Whatt petytt the clerke off the paece<br />or any other towardes the law hathe <br />sayde or don : as tochyng Indyteme<em>n</em>ttes<br />Impanelyng off questes And by whatt<br />occasyon and by whoys motyon or co<em>m</em>mawndme<em>n</em>tt<br />I can say noo thyng In thys matt<em>er </em>: ffor I know noo thyng<br />off Indyteme<em>n</em>ttes and Impanelyng off questes : savy<em>n</em>g att a tyme<br />I herd petytt say : thatt : one Bugn<em>er</em> off maydstone : schuld be <br />Indytyd : ffor spekyng off wordes a yenst the sa<em>cra</em>mentt off <em>the</em> awlt<em>er</em><br />Butt by whoys motyon he schuld be Indytyd. In good ffaygthe I <br />know nott : : ffor the Indyteme<em>n</em>tt off any oother <em>per</em>son or <em>per</em>sons : <br />as I doo reme<em>m</em>ber. I nev<em>er</em> herd hym. nor none o<em>ther</em> speke.<br />Unto whatt end or effectt they<br />Intendyd to bryng thes matt<em>er</em>s <br />In good ffaygthe I know nott : oth<em>er</em>wyse then w<em>ith</em>ow<em>t</em> any manes hurtt<br />or hynderawnce : to have a godly quyetnesse<br />By whatt auctoryte they began<br />and <em>pro</em>cedyd In thes matt<em>er</em>s :<br />$Twaith hardes$ In good ffaygthe I know nott : Butt as I have sayde mr thwayttes<br />sayde : thatt he was w<em>rit</em>yn unto : And lykewyse mr herdes sayth : ffor<br />hys <em>par</em>tt also : thatt they schuld gather : suche matt<em>er</em>s as were<br />here abusyd : and worthy to be refformyd : Butt who wrotte unto<br />them : and wyllyd them so to doo : off my ffaygthe : I know not<br />As co<em>n</em>c<em>er</em>ny<em>n</em>g the w<em>ri</em>tyng off the boke : onely zele unto quyetnesse movyd :<br />w<em>hich</em> schuld nev<em>er</em> have gon fforthe so ffarr : yff that mr baker had <br />rebukyd us : when we were <em>with</em> hym : schewyng unto us the dang<em>er </em>theroff<br />By me Willi<em>a</em>m Gardn<em>er</em></body></xml>