<xml><body>@r243@<br />At this o<em>ur</em> being at london Mr serles also sent me a l<em>ettre</em> showing t<em>hat </em>he<br />could not conveniently come to london in the w<em>hich</em> l<em>ett</em>re he willed<br />us that wer ther to <del data-tag="del">called </del>cause doctor thornden to be called befor<br />$Mr Napper$ the cownsell saing t<em>hat</em> Mr nap<em>per</em> of oxon hadd told him t<em>hat</em> if ther said<br />$D. Thorden$ doctor thorndon wer called he wold tell a knavysh tall of my lordes<br />grace / (as I thinke thes wer his termes) And in the same l<em>ett</em>re he willed <br />us 3 to repare to doctor london at silv<em>er</em> strete / but we did not so <br />but de<em>pa</em>rted owt of london./.<br /><br />And within lit<em>t</em>le more then a weke aft<em>er </em>mr serles co<em>m</em>mi<em>n</em>g fro<em>m</em> oxon to cant<em>erbury<br /></em>said to me t<em>hat</em> he spake at londond w<em>ith</em> Mr baker who willed me to come <br />to him And to bring the books formably drawn accordi<em>n</em>g as he willed<br />me At the w<em>hich</em> message I m<em>er</em>veled gretly &amp; rode up to london to him<br />carying w<em>ith</em> me the names of the witnes to e<em>ve</em>ry article shewing<br />him t<em>hat</em> he willed me not at o<em>ur</em> dep<em>ar</em>ting to draw the booke in ony<br />other mann<em>er</em> of forme w<em>ith</em> the which answer he was contented./. And<br />ther declaring to him that mr batterst of cant<em>erbury</em> said in the tyme <em>that</em><br />trooble: In entreting of certayn articles of S<em>ir</em> bland &amp; other: he said<br />that it wer well done t<em>hat </em>one book wer maid of all such articles<br />as wer detected &amp; told me t<em>hat</em> doctor london hadd maid a p<em>er</em>fecte<br />booke &amp; said that I shuld do well to declare to my lord of wynchest<em>er</em><br />Mr batterst<em>es</em> woordes &amp; Sir blandes article of missa n<em>on</em> e<em>st</em> sac<em>ri</em>fitiu<em>m</em> p<em>ro</em><br />p<em>e</em>c<em>ca</em>tis Addi<em>n</em>g mor ov<em>er</em> t<em>hat </em>I shuld notte as dilige<em>n</em>tly as I could <br />the chefist fautoors &amp; berers of erroneouse doctryn &amp; m<em>ar</em>ke ther<br />names &amp; so I dep<em>ar</em>ted from him./. <br />Aft<em>er</em> this I went to my lord of wy<em>n</em>chest<em>er</em> &amp; shewed him the witnes names<br />of ev<em>er</em>y articles &amp; also of Mr batterst<em>es</em> woordes unto the w<em>hich</em> he said<br />only he mused that Mr batterste wold so use him selfe. And I<br />delyv<em>er</em>ed him Sir blandes bill subscribed w<em>ith </em>his hand conc<em>er</em>ning the<br />article missa no<em>n</em> e<em>st</em> sacrificiu<em>m</em> <add data-tag="add">etc.</add> &amp; he reserved the bill &amp; so I left him<br />And going to doctor london I shewd him the copie of the booke t<em>hat</em> we<br />hadd delyv<em>er</em>ed to Mr baker the which he said he was gladd to se bicause<br />of the witnes whos names he caused to copied owt And after he <br />shewd me the mann<em>er</em> of maki<em>n</em>g of his book w<em>hich</em> was a gret thing &amp;<br />hadd articles I hadd not befor hard of. but I dep<em>ar</em>ted fro<em>m</em> hy<em>m</em> &amp; we<em>n</em>t home.</body></xml>