<xml><body>Ffor ev<em>er</em>y one thatt hathe co<em>m</em>playnyd on me : I trust to bryng VI<br />to testyffye thatt my p<em>re</em>chynges have byn accordyng unto godes<br />lawys and the kynges : yff hytt plaese yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce to here them<br />I dow<em>t</em> nott butt to bryng them : Then sayde yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce : I<br />warra<em>n</em>tt yow I wylnott be to hasty.<br /><br />ad 3m<br />I have had no co<em>m</em>munycatyon w<em>ith</em> none that hathe had dysplesur<br />att thordynarys hand att any tyme : savy<em>n</em>g ons mr schether<br />and I dyd co<em>m</em>myn : (long tyme past) thatt he sayde unto <br />yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce : thatt he &amp; serles : were blamyd ffor p<em>re</em>chyng : and<br />hytt was ot<em>her</em> thatt offendyd : And suche as had auctoryte ffor<br />to p<em>re</em>ache : yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce dyd aske : how they were : he namyd the<br />vycar off Ospryng : yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce sayde : he had auctoryte to p<em>re</em>che<br />Then sayde schether : And <em>the</em> co<em>n</em>tre a bow<em>t</em> wher he hath<br />p<em>re</em>chyd can testyffye : thatt he hathe nott p<em>re</em>chyd well : yow<em>r</em><br />g<em>ra</em>ce was gretly dysconted w<em>ith</em> hym : ffor hys so sayng : as he schewyd<br />unto me : Also he sayde unto me : att hys returne from croydon<br />ffrom yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce : thatt yow<em>r </em>g<em>ra</em>ce wold be evyn wi<em>th</em> me schortly<br />by cause I dyd reason with yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce In serles cause. <br /><br />Ad 4<br /><br />Off doctor wyllyby. I herd no man speke butt all onely mr schether<br />he sayde unto me thatt : wyllyby was a besy tu<em>n</em>gyd man and<br />came oft unto canterbury w<em>ith</em> tales untrew : and oftyn tymys he<br />made moo wordes uppo<em>n</em> grett mennes mowthes then were trew. Then<br />sayd I : ys thys hys co<em>n</em>fessyon : I herd say soo : sayde schether<br />I sayde : unto hys owne parell be hytt : I p<em>ra</em>y god send hym<br />as he hathe de<em>ser</em>vyd. I thanke god : I nev<em>er</em> had com<em>m</em>unycation<br />w<em>ith</em> hym sec<em>re</em>tly : Butt yett I wold <em>that </em>I had never seyn hym.</body></xml>