<xml><body>Unto thys Int<em>er</em>rogatory  : wheth<em>er </em><br />I have had : or herd com<em>m</em>unycacyo<em>n</em> <br />off mylles  : scory : serles and schether<br /><br />Now I reme<em>m</em>ber I dyd co<em>m</em>myn w<em>ith</em> mr <em>par</em>khurst off scory sayng I wysh <br />noo wytnesse a yenst scory : ffor yff I may wylbe exceptyd<br />And so I thynke I may : ffor as myche as I am yett now In<br />troble and nott clere my selffe : And hensfforth I wyll make <br />an othe ; thatt whyls I leve a gen I wyll nev<em>er</em> be wytnes <br />a yenst any man : nor accuse any man : And I trust <br />thatt I wyll so use my selffe : thatt I wyll nev<em>er</em> des<em>er</em>ve<br />to be accusyd : Then sayde mr <em>Par</em>khurst : I p<em>ra</em>y yow speke <br />unto hym thatt he doo exceptt me also. <br /><br />Att an o<em>ther</em> tyme I <em>per</em>ceyvy<em>n</em>g mr <em>par</em>khurst very sadd : sayde unto hym why<br />yow mery mr parkhurst : I trust : yow shall have no cause unto the<br />co<em>n</em>trary : My lord ys good I <em>pro</em>myse yow : I had wonders good words <br />off hym And off mr doctor ley lykewyse : In good ffaygthe as I doo <br /><em>per</em>ceyve : they Intend charytably I am so co<em>n</em>ffortyd by them so <br />thatt I am mery : I thanke god : lett us care ffor ow<em>r</em> owne<br />As ffor mr serles I thynke he hathe byn a doer a bove w<em>ith</em> dr <br />london : butt I am nott sewar of hytt : And mr schether hath he <br />ov<em>er</em>mych occupyd w<em>ith</em> hys pen : I wyll say noo thyng ffor ther.<br />Be yow mery I p<em>ra</em>y yow : I trust all schalbe well. Thes<br />wordes co<em>n</em>fortyd hym soo : <del data-tag="del">that</del> thatt oftyn tymes he wold say<br />unto me aft<em>er</em> : I am glad : thatt yow have had good co<em>n</em>ffort<br />bothe off my lord also off mr docto<em>r</em> ley : hytt co<em>n</em>ffortyth my hartt<br />mych : I sayd : Be yow co<em>n</em>tentyd : And I wold thatt we had never <br />seyn wyllyby : and sum<em>m</em>e other</body></xml>