<xml><body>@r337@<br />J<em>ehus</em> c<em>hris</em>t<br />W<em>ith</em> any man thatt wold testyffyi ffor serles or schether. I have<br />had no co<em>m</em>munycatyon : sethe I have byn att lyberty :<br />butt emo<em>n</em>gst ow<em>r</em> selvys we have oftyn tymes wyschyd<br />thatt they mygthe be att lyberty so hytt were yow<em>r </em>g<em>ra</em>cyusse <br />p<em>l</em>aesure : w<em>ith</em> mr p<em>ar</em>khurst I have had no man<em>er</em> co<em>m</em>munyca<br />tyon : sethe I was <add data-tag="add">att</add> lyberty savy<em>n</em>g one tyme : And thatt<br />came by hys motyon : he askyd whatt dysplesure men<br />had att thordynarys hand thatt co<em>m</em>playnyd : I sayde ev<em>er</em>y man<br />knowghe hys owne g<em>re</em>ffe : my lord sayd unto me ons when <br />he was nott co<em>n</em>tentyd : gardin<em>er</em> yow and yow<em>r</em> co<em>m</em>pany doo hold me<br />shortt I wyll hold you as schortt : Mr p<em>ar</em>khurst sayde thatt<br />he wold bynd uppo<em>n</em> thes wordes : I sayde he schulde nott : ffor<br />yff he dyd : he was nott my ffrend : nor I wold nott take<br />hym ffor my ffrend : And I sayde yff he dyd : he dyd<br />unto me hyge dysplesure &amp; wold cause me to have grett<br />hynderance : w<em>ith</em> mr mylles. I reme<em>m</em>ber no co<em>m</em>munycatyon thatt<br />I had savy<em>n</em>g ons uppo<em>n</em> the artycle off aurycyler co<em>n</em>fessyon<br />maeny<em>n</em>g no hurtt : noo busynesse : a yenst no p<em>er</em>son : butt<br />Indyfferenttly dyd co<em>m</em>myn off that matt<em>er</em> : In the way off lerny<em>n</em>g<br />Att an o<em>ther</em> tyme : In dede he sayde unto me thatt beyng att <br />bekesborne w<em>ith</em> my lord: he saw In hys off artyclys notyd<br />mendac<em>ium</em> : noo mans name namyd : and wherffor hytt was<br />w<em>ri</em>ten he cowd nott tell : ff treugthe he dyd nott schew.<br /><br />Ad 2m<br />Att lambhyth xii monthes past <add data-tag="add">&amp; more</add> when I was w<em>ith</em> yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce : yowr grace<br />sayde unto me thatt I was co<em>m</em>playnyd on ffor p<em>re</em>chyng (and as <br />yow were Infformyd) a sedytyusse s<em>er</em>mon : I sayde unto yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce <br />my lord Ther be In cant<em>er</em>bury w<em>hich</em> wold putt me unto hyndera<em>n</em>ce<br />w<em>ith</em> a good wyll : Butt I trust yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce wyll beleve <em>the </em>treugthe</body></xml>