<xml><body><div>ffirste what co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on by wourde or wryting you have hadd w<em>ith</em></div>
<div>Mr Roper, Balthasar the Surgian, Heywood, Mr Moore, Jermen</div>
<div>Gardiner, Mr Bekensale, or with either of theym and to what </div>
<div>effecte suche co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on was hath ben,</div>
<div>In primis Whither you came to Serls and saied unto hym</div>
<div>$n$ theis wourdes or like in effecte. Take hede to thyself, or</div>
<div>els thou arte like to be undon</div>
<div>It<em>em</em> Whither you did not procure of Anthony Hussey </div>
<div>the copies of Sandewiches and Serles Articles and</div>
<div>caused theym to be delivered unto the said Sandewich</div>
<div>and Serls, before thei were callid to examinac<em>i</em>on, Or </div>
<div>$n$ sent theym or either of theym worde, that thei ought to</div>
<div>have the copie of thair articles</div>
<div>It<em>e</em>m Whither you said theis wourdes or like in effecte. That</div>
<div>tharticles of Serles and Shether, ar not sufficiently</div>
<div>nor full provid, for the whiche thei were co<em>m</em>mitid and</div>
<div>contynue in prison</div>
<div>It<em>e</em>m What co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on, conference and l<em>ett</em>res you have had</div>
<div>with doctour London, or any other in his name, as</div>
<div>towching me, or the newe opinions and enormities in</div>
<div>kente</div>
<div>It<em>e</em>m Whither you saied theis wourdes or like in effecte</div>
<div>$n$ That Doctour London was at the courte, for <em>pro</em>motio<em>n</em></div>
<div>at the kynges hande, and what knowledge you had therof</div>
<div>and by whome</div>
<div>It<em>e</em>m Whither you saied theis wourdes or like in effecte</div>
<div>$n$ That if ev<em>er</em>y man were so handelid as Docto<em>ur</em> London</div>
<div>was handelid, there wolde be many papo<em>r</em>s worne</div>
<div>and to what entent you spake those wourdes, and what</div>
<div>you meant therbye</div>
<div>It<em>e</em>m Whither you knowe or harde, that Docto<em>ur</em> London </div>
<div>$n$ that Doctour Barbo<em>ur</em> and Mr Talbote, whiche w</div>
<div>of my lordes counsaile and chamber, can tell a shre</div>
<div>tale if thei were examined, ffor it was not for n</div>
<div>[nought] that thei were put oute of service, and of whome</div>
<div>the same.</div>
<div></div></body></xml>