<xml><body><div>@r125@</div>
<div>On monday last past</div>
<div>I Will<em>ia</em>m gardin<em>er</em> havy<em>n</em>g co<em>m</em>munycatyon w<em>ith</em> Mr. <em>par</em>khurst hytt</div>
<div>chawnsyd us to comyn off ow<em>r</em> Int<em>er</em>rogatoresse last mynystred</div>
<div>he sayde thatt he made hys Im<em>per</em>ffytt and thatt he reme<em>m</em>bryd</div>
<div>more then: then he dyd whatt tyme: he made hys answere</div>
<div>&amp; sentt them unto you<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce att bek<em>es</em>borne: And sayde. I</div>
<div>doo nott well know: how they <em>that</em> co<em>m</em>playne unto ther ordynary</div>
<div>gett no thynge butt dysplasure: I sayde thatt I dyd ons</div>
<div>co<em>m</em>playne unto yo<em>ur</em> g<em>ra</em>ce: and you dyd say unto me: yow</div>
<div>and yo<em>ur</em> co<em>m</em>pany doo hold me schortt I wyll hold yow</div>
<div>as schortt: ItI Mr schether sayde unto me att hys retInyIg</div>
<div>ffrom Croydon: when he had receyvyd hys InjuIctyons to</div>
<div>declare: <em>that</em> gardn<em>er </em>toke serl<em>es</em> <em>par</em>tt In my chamber: I</div>
<div>wyll be evyn <em>with</em> hym: It<em>em</em> thatt yo<em>ur</em> g<em>ra</em>ce sayde unto Mr.</div>
<div>sentleger: thatt yow ar a bund. I wyl breke the bund &amp;</div>
<div>make you leve you<em>r</em> mumpsim<em>us</em>: And thys com<em>m</em>unycatyo<em>n</em></div>
<div>I and Mr. <em>par</em>khurst lykewyse had w<em>ith</em> Mr. myll<em>es</em></div>
<div>It<em>em</em> Mr. mylles told me when he came last ffrom yo<em>ur</em> g<em>ra</em>ce</div>
<div>that he saw the boke off the artyclys beffore you<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce lying</div>
<div>and ther he sawe mendatiu<em>m</em>: Att thys word I reme<em>m</em>bryng</div>
<div>myne answere beffore made w<em>ith</em>ou<em>t</em> delyberatyon: and bett</div>
<div>reme<em>m</em>bryng my selffe: <em>pur</em>posyd as I have done to make</div>
<div>a more delyberatt answere: so to awoyde danger and</div>
<div>Inco<em>n</em>venyence thatt mygth happyn unavysydly unto me</div>
<div>by myne answere be ffore made: ffor beffore In myne answere</div>
<div>I gave way rather unto you<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ces word<em>es</em>: and wrott as you</div>
<div>sayde unto me: And nott<nott> soo as afterward uppon my conscyence I</nott></div>
<div>Juggyd trewe</div></body></xml>