<xml><body>@r187@<br />co<em>m</em>munycatyon off hytt. I nor none off my co<em>m</em>pany (so ffarr as I doo know) <br />ys able to say: Butt sone aft<em>er</em> aester : Mr <em>par</em>khurst: Mr Schether: and I <br />willi<em>a</em>m Gardn<em>er</em>: were sentt ffor unto london, by l<em>ett</em>res : sentt unto us<br />from ow<em>r</em> daene: Mr doctor wotton: wyllyng us w<em>ith</em> all spede to repare<br />unto london: and ther to apere be ffore one off the p<em>ri</em>vy cowncell<br />namy<em>n</em>g noo man<em>es</em> name det<em>er</em>mynatt: hys l<em>ett</em>res declaryd thatt he<br />was co<em>m</em>mawndyd to w<em>ri</em>te unto us: In hys l<em>ett</em>res: he also declaryd thatt<br />he wold schew unto us hys name. thatt wyllyd us to apere: when<br />we came unto london: Unto london when we were cume we were<br />co<em>m</em>mawndyd by Mr Daene to goo unto Syr John Baker knygthe: unto<br />whom: when we came: he schewyd unto us a copy: off the boke: w<em>ith</em><br />namys nott subscrybyd: and sayde here ys a boke: delyv<em>er</em>yd unto<br />me: and hytt ys thowght: thatt yow have knowlege off hytt: I<br />requyre yow In the kyng<em>es</em> majesteys name: thatt yow goo to gyther<br />and thatt thatt yow know to be trew: and to be abyddyn by: theroff<br />make a ffayer boke: And the kyng<em>es</em> plaesure ys: thatt yow ffare<br />none: and spare nott to tell the trowthe. ffor ffere off ony man<br />he wyllythe yow. In thys matt<em>er</em> to ffere none: butt god and hym<br />And doo hytt trewly and ffayzthfully w<em>ith</em>owt all drede: off ony<br />under hys majestye: We so co<em>m</em>mawndyd <em>per</em>usyd the boke thorowly<br />and so myche as we knew to be trew: and <add data-tag="add">with handes subscribyd </add>to be abyddyn by: we dyd<br />putt Into a boke new w<em>ri</em>ten: <del data-tag="del">and </del> <add data-tag="add">the boke </add>dyd goo unto my lord off wynchest<em>er</em><br />w<em>ith</em> <del data-tag="del">the boke</del>: butt he wold nott kepe <del data-tag="del">hytt</del>: butt <add data-tag="add">lokyd on<with> hytt</with></add> qwykly dymyssyd us: <br />and byd us goo unto Syr John Baker knythe: off whom we hadd<br />the boke:<add data-tag="add"> and then to delyv<em>er</em> hytt</add> And so unto Syr John Baker we returny<em>n</em>g: (by the<br />hand<em>es</em> off Mr Schether / Mr <em>par</em>khurst and I standyng by) hytt was<br />delyv<em>er</em>yd unto the ffore namyd Syr John Baker knygthe: Thatt<br />done we were dymyssyd and sentt home a gen: And so we have<br />co<em>n</em>tyneneyd: (I trust trew) unto god: and unto the kyng<em>es</em> hyghnesse<br />unto whom: god grawntt long lyffe and <em>pro</em>sperusse<br /><em>per </em>me william Gardn<em>er</em> clericus<br /><br />In margin to be inserted possibly at line 22<br />butt we schuld<br />have done and <br /><!--?re--> &lt;&gt;ore unto the <br /><!--?charge--> discharge off<br />&lt;&gt; selffe yff althogh<br /><he> &lt;&gt;e dyd thys and<br /><!--??ayd--> &lt;&gt;ayd as a good<br />&lt;&gt;le yff we had <br /><!--?rst--> &lt;&gt;rst gon unto<br />&lt;?&gt; lordes grace our<br /><ordynary> ordynary : well<br />&lt;&gt; dyd we nott<br />&lt;&gt; more ffoly In <br />&lt;&gt; : : The boke<br /><!--??--> &lt;&gt;we :c:<br /><br /><br /></ordynary></he></body></xml>