<xml><body>@r297@<br />Mylles<br />Your grace wyllyng me to answer unto certay<em>n</em> ynterrogatorys<br />sent unto me fro<em>m</em> yo<em>ur</em> grace Thus I do answere unto the<em>m</em> as folowyth. <br /><br />To the ffyrst I do say <em>that</em> I do not knowe off any matters begonne at londo<em>n</em> <br />nother the begyn<em>n</em>ars off the<em>m</em> ther.<br /><br />$2$ And to the second I answer <em>that</em> I do not know by whose advyse matters hath byn<br />set forthe (except (wych I ca<em>n</em> not certay<em>n</em>ly saye) by the yustycys off thys shyre<br />as by mr moyle mr twaytes &amp; such other wych (as I herd say) dyd gretly <add data-tag="add">fer <em></em></add><em>that</em> <br />sedycyous prechyng and occapyyng off corrupt bokys. by the wych ii <br />thynges. scysme dyd engendre amo<em>n</em>g the people. opy<em>n</em> dysputa<em>cyo</em>n was yn <br />alehowsys ; &amp; yn howseholdes <del data-tag="del">reasy </del>reasonyng among <em>ser</em>va<em>n</em>tes off the wych dyd also<br />aryse mych debate &amp; stryffe) a <em>com</em>motyo<em>n</em> wold or myght be amo<em>n</em>g the people<br />yn thys shyre by such evylles not the<em>n</em> thorowly lokyd on. They therfor<br />as I herd say wold put to the yndustry &amp; dylygence to extyrppe such evylles<br /><em>that</em> quyetnesse myght take place amo<em>n</em>g the people &amp; be yn dewe obedyence <br />to godhys lawys &amp; to the kynges but what they have don I knowe not ;<br /><br />$3$ To the thyrd I say <em>that</em> I do not know who hath byn boldyd off any ma<em>n</em> to <br />farder any matter nother wyth who<em>m</em> any ma<em>n</em> hath had <em></em><del data-tag="del"><em>con</em>fery <em></em></del><em>con</em>ference by wordes<br />wrytyng or otherwyse savyng <em>that</em> ones I dyd see a colleccyo<em>n</em> of certayn supposyd<br />abusys yn mr sentleger hys chambre, broght yn as I reme<em>m</em>bre by mr gardener<br />or mr shether &amp; yn that wer also the artycles <em>that</em> wer <em>pre</em>sentyd unto yo<em>ur </em>grace <br /><em>that</em> mr law<em>n</em>celet rydley &amp; mr scory prechyd ii yerys past But what that boke<br />ys don wyth I know not. yo<em>ur</em> grace knowyth <em>that</em> I was a wytnesse yn those artycles<br /><br />$4$ And to the iiiith I do say <em>that</em> I do not knowe what grou<em>n</em>de any ma<em>n</em> had to setforth<br />matters off <em>com</em>play<em>n</em>t or myght <add data-tag="add">have </add>except <em>that</em> the sowyng off sedytyouse doctryne<br />prechyd or tought (wych (as comy<em>n</em> voyce goythe) hath byn occasyo<em>n</em> off many evylles<br />shuld have movyd any ma<em>n</em> for quyetnesse sake amo<em>n</em>g the people. to offer<br />upp any matt<em>er</em>s off <em>com</em>play<em>n</em>t : wych sedycyous doctryne whether any <em>pro</em>moter<br />off matt<em>er</em>s had yt off <add data-tag="add">hys or</add> there owne knowlege or otherwyse I know not. as the <br />vth artycle askyth. <br /><br />$6$ And to the vith I say <em>that</em> I do not know whereyn any ma<em>n</em> shuld note yo<em>ur</em> grace to be<br />culpable yn any matter except that yo<em>ur</em> grace shuld have byn (as the rumor goyth)<br />remysse yn ponyshyng off those <em>that</em> the mor <em>par</em>t off the people wer offendyd wyth.<br /><del data-tag="del">yn </del>ther p<em>re</em>chynges as mr law<em>n</em>celat rydly &amp; mr scory. &amp; ponyshyd mr shether &amp; <add data-tag="add">dyd</add> put <br />mr serlys to troble wych ii hath the more <em>par</em>t off the people as well off the <br />cyte as off the cou<em>n</em>tre to testyfy off ther catholyke prechyng And to declare<br />farder unto yo<em>ur</em> grace (trustyng <em>that</em> yo<em>ur</em> grace wyll <em>par</em>do<em>n</em> <del data-tag="del">off</del> me &amp; be not dysco<em>n</em>tyd wyth<br />my sayyng. beyng reqyryd to say the troth) wheras certay<em>n</em> artycles wer<br />presentyd unto yo<em>ur</em> grace by mr sentleger &amp; mr p<em>ar</em>khurst co<em>n</em>cernyng the p<em>re</em>chyng off<br /><br /></body></xml>