<xml><body><div>$Injunctions$ It<em>e</em>m he hath taken away oute of the churche the</div>
<div>bible contrary to the kynges Inju<em>n</em>ctions and <em>pro</em>clamations</div>
<div>$holy wat<em>er</em>$ Item he badde one yong wiffe to take holy water and</div>
<div>other sorcery for the pyles</div>
<div>22 Septemb<em>ris</em></div>
<div>$Mr. drumme$ Mr. Drumme preacher of Canterbury, preachid on</div>
<div>$Images$ Witesonday last, that ymages were dangerously</div>
<div><em>per</em>mitted in the churche allegyng the texte deuteronomi</div>
<div>quarto, Ne errore decepti adoremus et colamus ea, </div>
<div>william hu<em>n</em>t, Edmu<em>n</em>de Shether, Siriaac petite be</div>
<div>witnes</div>
<div>Also that thei whiche went about to take awaye</div>
<div>the reading of the bible, did even go about to plucke</div>
<div>Christes wourde and the holy goste frome the people</div>
<div>as the bisshop of Rome hath don in tyme past, which</div>
<div>by restraynyng the people frome reading the bible toke</div>
<div>firste an occasion by that meane of his usurped powre</div>
<div>Witnes Syriaac petite. Edmonde Shether</div>
<div>Also the same daye he said that the holie goste was</div>
<div>neither in this place nor that as Christ was nev<em>er</em> in</div>
<div>Italy, nor nev<em>er</em> spake of Italy / But if thou wilte</div>
<div>have the holie goste, said he, seke hym in his worde</div>
<div>and in thy harte, Witnes Cyriaac petite, Willi<em>a</em>m</div>
<div>hunt Edmonde Shether</div>
<div>$Mr. Scorye$ About Christmas last whan there was gen<em>er</em>all</div>
<div><em>pro</em>cession co<em>m</em>manded by the kinges ma<em>jestie</em> Mr Scorye</div>
<div>$seditious$ preacher of Christes in Canterbury said theis wordes /</div>
<div>ev<em>er</em>y country hath a custume to chouse a pryvate patron</div>
<div>as England hath chosen S. George, Scotelande S</div>
<div>Andrewe, thinkyng the rather by the Intercession of</div>
<div>Saintes, to obteyne the victory of thair enemyes, but</div></body></xml>