<xml><body><div>Mr Shether</div>
<div>what tyme he made his reca<em>nt</em>ation or declaration, he</div>
<div>added thies wordes. Good christians I take god to recorde</div>
<div><em>that</em> I nev<em>er</em> p<em>re</em>ched any thynge to you in my life but the</div>
<div>$n$ truth. Mr Nevil. Mr Scory. Mr Toftes, Pet<em>er </em>kelsame,</div>
<div>George Toftes.</div>
<div>He p<em>re</em>ched <em>that</em> by <em>the</em> lawe of god no man ought to exco<em>mmun</em>icate</div>
<div>but only a preist.</div>
<div>Coxson peticanon of christes church</div>
<div>He made his testament by <em>the</em> advise of Mr <em>par</em>khurst, Mr</div>
<div>$+$ Sandwich and Mr Milles, and gafe and biquethed to ev<em>er</em>y vicar</div>
<div>of Christes church xxd, <em>that</em> had a payer of beades, &amp; wolde </div>
<div>$n$ say our lady psalt<em>er</em> for his sowle, which is thought</div>
<div>to be agaynst <em>the</em> kynges boke last set forth in <em>the</em> article</div>
<div>of prayer for <em>the</em> sowles departed. And this was exe-</div>
<div>cuted accordynge to the wil.</div>
<div>The <em>par</em>son of Alyngton</div>
<div><em>$the</em> busshope of Rome$ he nev<em>er</em> p<em>re</em>ched in his church of Alyngton nor Smeth</div>
<div>agaynst <em>the</em> usurped power of <em>the</em> busshope of Rome, nor</div>
<div>set forth <em>the</em> kynges sup<em>re</em>micie, accordynge to <em>the</em> kynges <em>pro</em>cla-</div>
<div>$n$ mations, letteres and iniu<em>n</em>ctions.</div>
<div>$pilgrimages$ he hath been a grete setter forth in his parish<in his="" parish=""> of the mayde of kent,</in></div>
<div>pilgrimages, fayned reliques, &amp; o<em>ther</em> such su<em>per</em>stitions, &amp; yet</div>
<div>nev<em>er</em> recanted &amp; reproved <em>the</em> same, accordynge to <em>the</em> kynges</div>
<div>majesties said inju<em>n</em>ctions.</div>
<div>$Inju<em>n</em>ctions$ he hath not declared to his <em>par</em>ishioneres <em>that the</em> eves of</div>
<div>such holy dayes as be abrogate, be no fastynge dayes,</div>
<div>accordynge to the kynges inju<em>n</em>ctions.</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ Opon the sondeyes <the sondeyes=""> candlemas day, Ashe wednesday, palme sonday,</the></div>
<div>and good friday he hath not declared <em>the</em> true use of the[se]</div>
<div>ceremonies used those dayes, accordynge to the kynges</div>
<div>iniu<em>n</em>ctions <em>pro</em>clamations. James Blechynden gent.</div>
<div>william Benefelde gentylmen. Mr Everynge, John knygh</div>
<div>James Toft w<em>ith</em> other.</div></body></xml>