<xml><body>@r259@<br />Int<em>er</em>ogatories ot Shether &amp; other<br />$1$ Inprimis whither they presented unto Tharchebisshop of Canterbury the<br />self same articles that be conteyned in the booke of complaint, or whither<br />there be moo, or fewer, or some altred by addition of any wourd<em>es</em><br />$2$ Item whither the witnes brought in did prove all thesaid Articles<br />$3$ <add data-tag="add">Item whefore they left out iii of tharticles that before were presented</add><br />$4$ Item whither tharchebisshop of Cant<em>erbury</em> did rebuke Serlis for that he<br />preached that ymages might be<em> per</em>mitted in the churche as representers<br />of saintz and not Idolles. <br />$5$ Item whither that Tharchebisshop of Caunterburie did speake openlye<br />before all the prebendaries and preachers there / and also openly in his <br />Consistory / that the kinges pleasure was to have three preachers <br />iii of the new lerning and iii of thold.<br />$6$ Item whither Serlis and Shether were accused by men whiche<br />were noted by co<em>m</em>men fame to be of evill opinion for preaching, and <br />who they were that accused them. <br />$7$ Item whether the honest of their audience offred them selfis to testifie<br />that they wer falsely accused / and that whiche was laide against<br />them was not true. And althoughe they were a great nomber<br />yet could <add data-tag="add">thay</add> not be admitted / and who they were that so offred themself<em>es</em><br /><add data-tag="add">And whether they offred theym selfes </add> Or serlis requirid them to be examyned, <add data-tag="add">&amp; cowde not have them admytted. <br /> </add><br />$8$ Item whither falce <em>per</em>sonnes men of evill fame for suspect opinions <br />though they were, but twoo or three were admitted <add data-tag="add">and by whom they were suspected</add> And whether<br />any obiection was made agaynst these suspecte <em>per</em>sons bifore the Jug<em>es</em><br />$9$ Item whither <del data-tag="del">they <add data-tag="add"></add></del><add data-tag="add">Serles and Shether</add> were Innocent preachers / and so being Innocent<br />were condempned, thone to prisone/ and thother to reade a declaration<br />of false surmised articles and by whome thone was co<em>m</em>mitted to prison<br />$10$ Item whether they that wold speake against evill opinions dare not, <br />for if they doo, they be complayned on / and called sedituouse <em>per</em>sones<br />stiring the people to co<em>m</em>motion / and by whome they be so called /<br />$11$ Item whither complayning to their ordinarye at his hand<em>es</em>, they<br />gett nothing but displeasure, and the <em>par</em>tie evill preaching<br />muche favo<em>ur</em> and boldenes./ And who hathe had displeasure of <br />the ordinarye for complayning against evill preachers. <add data-tag="add">And what <br />il precheres have had favour &amp; boldnes therin at thordinarye handes</add><br />$12$ Item whither twoo ymag<em>es</em> of Christ and twoo of o<em>ur</em> Ladye<br />wherunto was neither oblation doon, nor any light standing<br />were taken downe by Tharchebisshoppes co<em>m</em>maundement, bothe<br />by mouthe and by l<em>ett</em>res / and what theffect of the kinges <br />L<em>ett</em>res was./</body></xml>