<xml><body><div>
<div>$ceremonies$ he neither incensed <em>the</em> crucifixe in <em>the</em> roode loft, nor</div>
<div>any aultare in <em>the</em> church, except <em>the</em> high aultare, nor</div>
<div>distributed any holy candle amonge his<em> par</em>ochianes as</div>
<div>hath been accustomed. Willi<em>a</em>m Saunder. John Brown</div>
<div>Edmu<em>n</em>de purdue, will<em>ia</em>m Sacre. John Browne.</div>
<div><em>Sir</em> James Newname, &amp; one laurence</div>
<div>brother to Mrs. Mores</div>
<div>$Images$ Thay toke downe an image of o<em>ur</em> lady, to <em>the</em> which</div>
<div>was no offrynge (except candelles at <em>the</em> purification of</div>
<div>women) nor noted to be done ther any miracles by <em>the</em></div>
<div>said image. will<em>ia</em>m Saunder. cu<em>m</em> aliis qui supra.</div>
<div>The curate of Chartam <em>that</em> now is.</div>
<div>$holy water$ he casteth no holy wat<em>er</em> opon <em>the</em> crucifixe in <em>the</em> rode loft</div>
<div>nor opon any aultar in <em>the</em> church, except <em>the</em> high aultar</div>
<div>Saunder. cu<em>m</em> aliis qui supra</div>
<div>Scory.</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ he said <em>that</em> such su<em>per</em>stitions were used in <em>the</em> church, as makyng</div>
<div>of crosses opon palme sonday, settynge up of they<em>m</em> and blessyng</div>
<div>they<em>m</em> w<em>ith the</em> holy candle, ryngynge of belles in <em>the</em> thonder.</div>
<div>ffor. thynke you said he <em>that the</em> devil wil be afrayed or fle-</div>
<div>away crosse makynge, hurlynge of holy wat<em>er</em>, ryngynge</div>
<div>of belles &amp; such other ceremonies. whan he was not</div>
<div>afrayed to take Christ hy<em>m</em>selfe &amp; cast hy<em>m</em> on his backe,</div>
<div>&amp; set hym on a py<em>n</em>nacle</div>
<div>Those thynges <em>that</em> be good of they<em>m</em>selfes may not utterly</div>
<div>be put away, although they be abused. ffor than the</div>
<div>holy sacrament of the aultar sholde bet set a side,</div>
<div>which is dayly bought &amp; solde. Rich<em>ar</em>d <em>par</em>khurst <em>pre</em>sent</div>
<div>Bradkirke preist</div>
<div>Mr. Shether.<span style="white-space: pre;"> </span>witnesses</div>
<div>John Marden</div>
<div>Robert Colman.</div>
<div>Serles. d<em>o</em>m<em>ini</em>ca 8 post trinit<em>er</em>.</div>
<div>If the p<em>re</em>cher p<em>re</em>ch error. &amp; erronious doctrine, the simple ma[n]</div>
<div>though he receyve it &amp; bl bileve it, it doth not infecte</div>
<div>nor corrupt hy<em>m</em>. And this he repeted twise.</div>
<div>He said also that moises sent letters from hell to teache</div>
<div>the state therof, and howe men should lyve, And an other</div>
<div>Likewise oute of heaven</div>
<div>$sclaunderous$ It<em>e</em>m thei saye, seid he that only faith Justifieth, and that</div>
<div>it makith no matter howe we do lyve, Christe died for </div>
<div>us, and by his blode hath washed all our synnes awaye</div>
<div>Therfore what nedeth us to faste or praye</div>
</div>
<div></div></body></xml>