<xml><body>It<em>em</em> what wourde mr Bacar sent theym from London by Serls<br />It<em>em</em> what <add data-tag="add">booke </add>it was was that was laste sent to docto<em>ur </em>willoughby<br />by Shethers servante, what the mattier therof was, and whan<br />it was made and sent. <br />It<em>em</em> wherfore thei advised Shether to write to doctour willoughby<br />to gett hym oute of the waye, and to repayre to the Courte<br />or to some other of his ffrendes<br />It<em>em</em> what Inditment that was whiche Mr Parkehurste redde<br />one nyght at supper, whan thei talked of the sessions of the<br />vi Articles, whose Inditment it was and where he had it<br />It<em>em</em> <add data-tag="add">whither </add>Mr Bakar saied to parkehurste, Gardener and Shether<br />when thei were at London, that there shoulde be a Co<em>m</em>mission<br />in kent shortely<br />It<em>em</em> what names he wrote at the same tyme to be in the<br />Comission<br />It<em>em</em> whither Mr Thwaittes said at div<em>er</em>s tymes <del data-tag="del">about two lines deleted, illegible</del> <add data-tag="add">that </add>thei should still frome tyme to tyme marke<br />what was preachid and say nothing but note it and send it to <br />It<em>em</em> at what tymes the same was spoken, and whither he said<br />that it was maist<em>er</em> Bacars counsaile. <br />It<em>em</em> how many bokes were delivered to Petite<br />It<em>em</em> whither one boke was made wherin was this Article That<br />tharchebisshop did saye, that he wolde defende Scorye and <br />Ridleys opinions<br />Ite<em>m</em> where that boke ys become and what tyme it was made<br />It<em>em</em> whither Parkehurst and Gardener have co<em>mmun</em>ied with <br />Petite, that the Co<em>m</em>missarye and other of evill opynions<br />and dispicers of the laudable ceremonyes, wolde not have<br />ben so bolde, if thei had not ben conforted by my lorde. <br />It<em>em</em> Whither thei w<em>ith</em> Serls or Shether have com<em>mu</em>nied <del data-tag="del">to </del>Petite<br />being present, that Markeham Stewarde to tharchebisshop<br />was abiured, and what knowledge <del data-tag="del">Serls hath</del> <add data-tag="add">thei have</add> therof.<br />It<em>em</em> To whome thei sent to <em>pro</em>cure that tharchebisshop of Canter-<br />burye shoulde be no Comissioner, nor knowe the witnes<br />and wherfore thei so wrote or sent</body></xml>