<xml><body>@r295@<br />Mylles<br /><br />Wheras your grace hathe requyred me off myn allegyance to declare unto<br />yo<em>ur</em> grace my mynd on a certey<em>n</em> <em>com</em>playnt <em>that</em> shuld be made unto <del data-tag="del">your <br />grace</del> the kynges mayeste off yo<em>ur</em> grace. Thys shall be fyrst to <br />certyfy yo<em>ur</em> grace <em>that</em> I was nother off kowlege agreable or <em>con</em>sentyng<br />to any such byll off <em>com</em>playnt to be made or offeryd <del data-tag="del">off y</del> agay<em>n</em>st<br />yo<em>ur</em> grace to the kynges mayeste by any <em>par</em>tye. yet wheras yo<em>ur</em> grace<br />namyd one coxsu<em>n</em> unto me who<em>m</em> mr doctor lee notyd to be a besy<br />felowe) thys shall be to c<em>er</em>tyfy yo<em>ur</em> grace <em>that</em> at a c<em>er</em>tayn tyme he askyd<br />me thys questyo<em>n</em> whether <em>that</em> I herd yo<em>ur</em> grace saye yn the <em>con</em>systory<br /><em>that</em> the kynges mayeste had appoy<em>n</em>tyd vi p<em>re</em>chers iii off the olde &amp; iii of <br />the newe to <em>that</em> yntent <em>that</em> matters (at that tyme<del data-tag="del">) </del>yn <em>con</em>trov<em>er</em>sy) shuld<br />be reasonyd amo<em>n</em>gst the<em>m</em> selvys &amp; not to be p<em>re</em>chyd amo<em>n</em>g the <br />people to engendre scysme.  &amp; I sayd ye. &amp; aft<em>er</em> co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em> off other<br />tryflyng matters (nothyng ap<em>per</em>tayny<em>n</em>g to thys purpose) he sayd<br /><em>that</em> he was <del data-tag="del">f</del> sory for mr serlys &amp; Shether <em>that</em> yo<em>ur</em> grace shulde<br />be so sore agay<em>n</em>st <del data-tag="del">s</del> the<em>m</em> &amp; ponyshyd the<del data-tag="del">m</del> one <del data-tag="del">yn </del><add data-tag="add">by</add> declaryng to <br />the people <em><add data-tag="add">that </add>that</em> he nev<em>er</em> sayd upo<em>n</em> a stoole to hys rebuke. &amp; the<br />other to <del data-tag="del">by </del><add data-tag="add">be </add>cast yn to p<em>ri</em>son. Then sayd I <del data-tag="del">qu </del>yn late<em>n</em> que supra<br />nos nihil ad nos Then sayd he ; yn case you be callyd to <br />testyfy the trothe. wyll you not say as you k<em>n</em>owe yn thyes<br />matt<em>er</em>s. Then sayd I my lord spake the one thyng opy<em>n</em>ly<br />&amp; <em>that</em> must I wytnesse yff I be reqyryd by hyghere poore.<br />And to the other I sayd. for such <em>ser</em>mons as I herd <del data-tag="del">them </del>the<em>m</em> <br />make I ca<em>n</em> not say but <em>that</em> they p<em>re</em>chyd catholykly. &amp; so wyll I<br />testyfy whe<em>n</em> I schall be callyd ; but <em>(quod</em> I) yff they have p<em>re</em>chyd<br />otherwyse yn any other place (wych my lord knowyth yff<br />yt be so) I ca<em>n</em> say nothyng more I have not here off<br />matters <em>that</em> shuld be agay<em>n</em>st yo<em>ur</em> grace to my <del data-tag="del">rememory</del><br />reme<em>m</em>bra<em>n</em>ce. but <em>that</em> a remor was amo<em>n</em>g the people <add data-tag="add">yn </add><em>that</em> <add data-tag="add">that </add><del data-tag="del">re</del><br />mr launcelet &amp; mr scory was not lykwyse ponyshyd<br />for such matters as wer p<em>re</em>sentyd to yo<em>ur</em> grace off the<em>m</em></body></xml>