<xml><body><div>It<em>em with</em> Mr. <em>par</em>khurst I co<em>m</em>munyd off the boke subscr<em>i</em>byd: he</div>
<div>sayde thatt he reme<em>m</em>bryd nott wherunto he dyd subscr<em>i</em>be</div>
<div>and desyryd me to Instructt hym wherunto he had subscr<em>i</em>byd</div>
<div>I sayde In good ffaythe I know nott: he sayde I am</div>
<div>sewar you can: I sayd nay: and no more I ca<em>n</em>nott as</div>
<div>god schall save me: Thys day he askyd off me whether</div>
<div>hys name was unto <em>the</em> artyclye off serles <em>pri</em>sonme<em>n</em>tt. I sayd</div>
<div>ye &amp; he sayde nay: I <dyd> dyd styll affyrme hytt to be trew</dyd></div>
<div>I told hym <em>that</em> I wold cast hather<gathr> al dowttes uppon the boke soo nye</gathr></div>
<div>as I cowld: And I ffor my <em>par</em>tt wold make myne <answere> auswere as</answere></div>
<div>well as I mygth: And so I dyd to be the bett<em>er</em> avysyd</div>
<div>In myne answere makyng: I made myne answere</div>
<div>and he saw them &amp; sayde yow have gon thorowly me</div>
<div>thynkythe I lyke them well: wyll you send them unto</div>
<div>my lord: ye thatt I wyll. &amp; soo I dyd by<i> Mr. par</i>kehurst</div>
<div><em>ser</em>vantt I sentt them unto Mr. doctor ley and he askyd how I did</div>
<div>&amp; byd me be mery: I thanke hys m<em>a</em>stershypp hartely sayd I</div>
<div>It<em>em</em> as co<em>n</em>c<em>er</em>nyng the <communycatyon of="" the=""> communycatyon off the cumyng off my lord warden &amp; my lord cobbam</communycatyon></div>
<div>I reme<em>m</em>ber none off my trewgth: butt thys I askyd schall</div>
<div>we nott apere In the grett hawlle be ffore the lord<em>es</em>: I</div>
<div>thynke nott sayde Mr. <em>par</em>kehurst: I p<em>ra</em>y god we may nott</div>
<div>sayde I: other com<em>m</em>unycatyon then thys. I reme<em>m</em>ber nott</div>
<div>It<em>em</em> yest<em>er</em>day I reme<em>m</em>bryd thatt I co<em>m</em>munyd w<em>ith</em> Mr. myll<em>es</em></div>
<div>off Mr. rydleys artycle: saying: In good ffaygthe I wylnott <say> say</say></div>
<div>whet<em>er </em>hytt be good or badd well or evyll I sayde.<em> I am</em></div>
<div>butt a wytnesse: lett my lord Jugde</div></body></xml>