<xml><body>@r277@<br />The Awnsweres by me Rychard parkehurst clerke to my lord off<br />Caunt<em>erbury </em>upon<em> </em>thyse Interogatores here ffellowyng<br /><br />$1$ In p<em>ri</em>mis who was the Begynners of thyse Maters at london<br />To thys y Awnswere. as I Suppose. the Begynnyng was by Resone off<br />the Bookes delyv<em>er</em>ed to mr Thwayttes &amp; to doctor wyllowby / by mr Garden<em>er</em><br />$2$ It<em>e</em>m by whoys advyse &amp; Cowncell / it was set forward<br />To thys I sey. After that <em>the</em> Boke was made wyth owte my advyse<br />or Cowncell ther<em>e</em> off. mr Thwayttes mr Garden<em>er</em> mr Schether mr<br />Petyte &amp; I dyd kno off <em>the</em> settyng forth of the same.<br />$3$ It<em>e</em>m wyth whom they had co<em>n</em>ference &amp; who dyd Bolden &amp; Animate<br />the<em>m</em> yn the Same. &amp; yn what fowrme by woordes or wrytyng or othere wyse<br />To thys I sey that y doo not Remembre that any <del data-tag="del">men </del>had conference to Any man<br />that sholde Bolden or Anymat any man yn the same other by woordes<br />or wrytyng / a fore the Cu<em>m</em>yng up of mr Garden<em>er</em> mr Schether &amp; <add data-tag="add">of</add> me<br />to london to sir John Baker. wych dyd Anymat us to sey the Trewght seyng<br />ffere no ma<em>n</em>. seyng also I kno the kynges plesure<br />$4$ It<em>e</em>m what mat<em>er</em> they had at the Begynnyng for ther<em>e</em> ffundacyon or grownde <br />yn thyse Thynges<br />To thys I Awnswere as I suppose by cause <del data-tag="del">bycause </del>ther<em>e</em> was no ponyschment<br />had or done co<em>n</em>cernyng doctor lawncelett <add data-tag="add">Rydley </add>&amp; mr Scorys p<em>re</em>chynges but onely mr<br />Serlys &amp; mr Schether war ponysched. the one to declare hys <em>ser</em>mond sta<em>n</em>dyng<br />upon a Stole the other a grete seysen yn preson Thys y thynke suerly<br />was the occasyon ffundacyon &amp; grownde of makyng of the Booke. <br />$4$ It<em>e</em>m <add data-tag="add">if</add> they had any / whyther they had <del data-tag="del">byen </del>of <em>ther</em> owne knolege or by her<em>e </em>sey<br />To thys y sey y was not p<em>ri</em>vy to <em>the</em> Boke makyng unles <em>the</em> ffundacyon wer<br />as I have seyde yn <em>the</em> iiiith Arti<em>cle</em> I do not Esteme what hyt shold be other<br />of them selff or of other</body></xml>