<xml><body><div>$seditious$ thincking rather by intercession of saintz. to obtayne the</div>
<div>victory of their ennemyes / But good people</div>
<div>(q<em>uo</em>d he) forasmuche as saintes be circumscript, it is not</div>
<div>possible / for that saint that is in the northe</div>
<div>to heare the prayer that is made in the southe</div>
<div>nor that saint that is in the southe / to heare</div>
<div>the praier that is made in the northe</div>
<div>20 Septembre Anno 1543.</div>
<div>$Shether$ He preached in Sandwiche the xxiii day of June</div>
<div>$herecie$ $n$ Anno 1542. That baptyme taketh away but only</div>
<div>originall synne,</div>
<div>$Erro<em>ur</em>$ He preached at Sandwiche the 26(9) of July Anno 34</div>
<div>d<em>o</em>m<em>ino</em> n<em>os</em>tro R<em>eg</em>es. That every man syns the passion of </div>
<div>Christe: hathe asmuche liberty and free will of</div>
<div>as ev<em>er</em> Adam had in paradise before his fall</div>
<div>It<em>em the</em> same tyme &amp; place he p<em>re</em>ched, that <em>the</em> new p<em>re</em>cheres w<em>ith the</em> libertie of the</div>
<div>gospel hath caused our lyvynge to be worse than <em>the</em> Turkes.</div>
<div>It<em>e</em>m he said <em>that</em> zachary &amp; Elizabet his wife kept al <em>the</em> commaundmentes of god, &amp; <em>that</em> it</div>
<div>was a light thynge for ev<em>er</em>y man to kepe they<em>m</em>, if he wolde.</div>
<div>He preached the same day and place That Christ</div>
<div>and baptisme did nothing elles but washe awaye</div>
<div>o<em>ur</em> originall synne / and if that any man after</div>
<div>baptisme, did fall he must purchace remission of</div>
<div>his synnes by penaunce as mary magdalen did /</div>
<div>$pilgrimages$ It<em>em</em> he p<em>re</em>ched there <em>that</em> a certen kynge was sicke of a leprocie, &amp; had a vision to go to</div>
<div>Jordan to be baptized wasshed, &amp; sholde be hole. And as he was in his good intent goinge</div>
<div>thider., he thought <em>that</em> he had as good &amp; swete water in his own cuntray as <em>that</em> was. And so re</div>
<div>turned backe &amp; wasshed hy<em>m</em>selfe therin, but no thynge at al he therby me<em>n</em>ded. And than</div>
<div>he went to Jordan, </div>
<div>&amp; so was made hole.</div>
<div>In a Sermon he compared mannes conscience to</div>
<div>$Erro<em>ur</em> &amp; seditious$ a dogge / and said, that if a mans conscience</div>
<div>(which he called his dogge) did myslike the <em>ser</em>mon,</div>
<div>Biware of thies false p<em>re</em>cheres, which p<em>re</em>ch to you new fangelles. wil you</div>
<div>knowe how to discerne a true p<em>re</em>cher fro<em>m</em> a false. You have a dogge which</div>
<div>is yo<em>ur</em> co<em>n</em>science. Whan so ev<em>er</em> you shal com to any <em>ser</em>mon, aske yo<em>ur</em> dogge what</div>
<div>he saith unto it. If he say it be good, than folowe it. But if yo<em>ur</em> dogge</div>
<div>barke agaynst it, &amp; say <em>that</em> it is naught</div></body></xml>