<xml><body>It<em>em</em> whether thes wordes co<em>m</em>munyte off all thynges were p<em>re</em>sentyd or<br />nott : I doo nott reme<em>m</em>ber thatt thes wordes all thynges was p<em>re</em>sentyd<br />It<em>em</em> how many artyclys be addyd or dymyschyd : I know off none nor<br />reme<em>m</em>ber off none addyd or dymynyschyd : In the boke a yenst mr <br />rydley &amp; mr scory : savy<em>n</em>g one addyd : scz Ther ys none In hevy<em>n</em> butt <em>Chr</em>ist<br />In the boke p<em>re</em>sentyd a yenst my lordes g<em>ra</em>ce. I doo reme<em>m</em>ber thatt the<br />artycle of maner place also <add data-tag="add">off an</add> Indyffere<em>n</em>tt Jugde ar ou<em>t</em> off the boke<br />p<em>re</em>sentyd <add data-tag="add">unto sir Baker</add>, as I doo now reme<em>m</em>ber. <br />It<em>em</em> whet<em>er</em> thatt all thes artyclys were p<em>re</em>sentyd In w<em>ri</em>tyng<br />or noo : unto thys artycl mr sentleger &amp; mr <em>par</em>khurst p<em>re</em>senters<br />a yenst mr Rydley and mr scory : can make clerar answere then<br />I : yett by you<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ces ffavor. I schall make answere : as I have here<br />and know : mr sentleger and mr <em>par</em>khurst dyd nott<em> pre</em>sentt them In<br />writing all att one tyme : ffor one lakkyd : scz. Then ys none In<br />hevy<em>n</em> butt christ : Thatt artycle ffor lakk of wytnesse / as then &lt;was?&gt;<br />left out <add data-tag="add">but </add>aft<em>er</em>ward w<em>ith</em>in schortt space you<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce beyng att londo<em>n</em> and<br />heryng thatt suche a thynge was p<em>re</em>chyd : you<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce sentt unto us wy&lt;?&gt;<br />us to Inquyre : whet<em>er</em> hytt were p<em>re</em>chyd or noo : wher and by whom<br />and whatt wytnesse mygth be ffownd unto hytt ; We acco<em>m</em>panyd to <br />gyther mr sentleger w<em>ith</em> the rest. In ou<em>r</em> chapt<em>er</em>howse dyd examy<em>n</em> morden<br />and Colma<em>n</em> ii off ow<em>r</em> vycars : They herd hytt p<em>re</em>ched by mr scory at <br />sayntt alpheges In cant<em>erbury</em> : And uppo<em>n</em> ther testyffyng we sentt up <br />le<em>tter</em>s unto yo<em>ur</em> g<em>ra</em>ce theroff and the wytnesse names therwyth. <br />It<em>em</em> wher as mr serl<em>es</em> had p<em>re</em>chyd as was layde unto hym : thatt noe<br />ydolatrye : mygthe be unto an ymage off ou<em>r</em> lady etc. : ffor as mych<br />as all ymag<em>es</em> were rep<em>re</em>senters off sayntt<em>es</em> and noo ydoles : yow<em>r</em> <br />g<em>ra</em>ce nott co<em>n</em>tentyd w<em>ith</em> hym sayde thatt all ymages were ydoll<em>es</em> : [but]<br />sayde nay : whatt ys ydolu<em>m</em> sayde my lord unto serl<em>es</em> : serl<em>es</em> sayde<br />ydolu<em>m</em> niehil etc. : you<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce sayde thatt ydolu<em>m</em> &amp; ymago in g<em>re</em>ke was</body></xml>