<xml><body>@r325@<br />yo<em>ur</em> grace <em>com</em>mandyng me to opyn unto you what co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em> hath byn betwyxt mr parkhurst <br />&amp; men on mu<em>n</em>day co<em>n</em>cernyng the artycles thys ys to certyfy yo<em>ur </em>grace off so mych as<br />I ca<em>n</em> r<em>e</em>me<em>m</em>bre.<br /><br />ffyrst on mu<em>n</em>day yn the mornyng abowt ix off the clok yn mr <em>par</em>khurst cha<em>m</em>ber mr<br />garden<em>er</em> had a boke off thartycles yn hys hand wych when I dyd see the<em>m</em> and<br />rede <del data-tag="del">them </del>part off the<em>m</em>. I sayd I wold thys boke had byn on fyre whe<em>n</em> you broght yt<br />to mr sentleger &amp; to me yn to hys chambre to subscrybe to any artycles yn yt. Then <br /><em>quod</em> he tha<em>n</em>k doctor wyllyby for he dyd sett me a work. But now <em>quod</em> he yt ys don <br />god send us a quyet end off thys &amp; I wyll take hede off such an other. And so wyll I <em>quod</em> I<br />for I had rather begg my brede the<em>n</em> thus <em>con</em>tynew unquyetly. The<em>n</em> sayd he I ca<em>n</em> not <br />slepe nor I kow not how the worlde faryth wyth <del data-tag="del">hym </del>me. Then <em>quod</em> I take no thogt to<br />hurt yo<em>ur</em> sylff but me mery wyth sorow as I a<em>m</em> ; well <em>quod</em> he I have drawy<em>n</em> an a<em>n</em>swer<br />to all my artycles <em>that</em> I must abyde by. Then sayd I. I have also sent my <em>ser</em>va<em>n</em>t to <br />bekysborne wyth my delyberatyd a<em>n</em>swer &amp; I trust <em>that</em> my lord wyll favorably accept yt<br />Then sayd he I wold thys matt<em>er</em> wer at an end. And so wold I <em>quod</em> I. Then sayd he <br />thys boke agreyth not yn all poy<em>n</em>tes wyth the boke at londo<em>n</em> Then sayd I. I a<em>m</em> no wytnesse<br />to yo<em>ur</em> boke presentyd. for I knewe not off yt. The<em>n</em> sayd he yt ys but yn one artycle wher <br />I a<em>m</em> a wytnesse alone wych artycle ys not p<em>re</em>sentyd. or yn su<em>m</em> one word. And so he <br />de<em>par</em>tyd wyth the boke. And aft<em>er</em>ward mr <em>par</em>khurst rebukyd hy<em>m</em> for hys hasty wyllfulnesse<br /><em>that</em> he wold so sode<em>n</em>ly bryng a bok to hys <em>com</em>pany &amp; <del data-tag="del">enforce </del>cause the<em>m</em> to subscrybe w<em>ith</em>owt<br />delyberatyo<em>n</em> take<em>n</em> on the artycles. &amp; rebukyd hy<em>m</em>sylff &amp; other <em>that</em> then wer so folyshe <br />to subscrybe to such artycles <em>that</em> now he sayth standyng for the tryall off the trothe or<br />falsyte yn the<em>m</em>. The<em>n</em> sayd he ther ys no artycle ther but wyll be <em>pro</em>vyd. Then sayd<br />mr <em>par</em>khurst I p<em>ra</em>y god yt prove so &amp; the<em>n</em> I care not. Then sayd I. I wold the boke wer <br />on a fyre so yt came not by me. &amp; so sayd we all. And yn thys co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em>. as we<br />hartyly wyshyd for a quyet end. so we musyd wat the end shuld be. And thus we<br />ceassyd as I reme<em>m</em>bre. And the next day at dyn<em>er</em> we all desyryd my lord warde<em>n</em>s<br />chaple<em>n</em> to speke to hys mast<em>er</em> or su<em>m</em> other for hy<em>m. that </em>hys mast<em>er</em> myght speke to my lordes grace<br />for the delyv<em>er</em>ance off serlys. as he sayd he wolde. At what tyme <del data-tag="del">the parishe off esc</del> <add data-tag="add">syr Ygham</add><br />sayd to me. how chaw<em>n</em>syd brother <em>that</em> you wer not yn the compe ynclosyd w<em>ith</em> yo<em>ur</em> felows<br />The<em>n quod</em> I. I was not at londo<em>n </em>wyth the<em>m. </em>Meany<em>n</em>g <em>that </em>yff I had byn a setterforth off these  <br />matters ther I had byn lykwyse ymprysonyd. And the wedenysday I askyd &amp; m<em>ar</em>velyd <br />why we wer sworne. And no ma<em>n</em> kew the cause. The thursday mr garden<em>er </em>shewyd<br />me <em>that</em> he feryd shether mych to dyspayre w<em>ith</em> hy<em>m</em>sylff for ther was no myrth w<em>ith</em> hy<em>m</em><br />nother yn co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em> abrode (as he talkyd <em>with</em> hy<em>m</em> ov<em>er</em> evyn yn the garden) nother yet<br />at the table. And for <em>that</em> co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n that</em> I herd yest<em>er</em>day spokyn off mr shether to be<br />yo<em>ur</em> grace hys chaple<em>n</em>. I herd yt spoky<em>n</em> opy<em>n</em>ly at the table off doctor thornden hys mouth<br />who sayd <em>that</em> he kewe yt not (&amp; so I rehersyd yt) but yet he wold laye xx s<em>hillings</em> on yt<br />&amp; <em>that</em> yt shuld be so. &amp; so I told mr shether. Then sayd mr shether I kow yt not<br />But yff yt wer offeryd to me. off my lord. yt wer not my honeste to refuse hyse<br />grace hys offer. <br />And thys ys as mych as I ca<em>n</em> call to memory ;</body></xml>