<xml><body>@r199@<br />The teno<em>r</em> off the last l<em>ett</em>re sentt<br />by mr schether unto my lord off wynchest<em>er</em><br />Rev<em>er</em>end father : s : All drawythe now towardes a quyetnesse and I trust<br />thatt schortly my lordes g<em>ra</em>ce wyll sett all well : By the berar hereoff<br />mr schether he schall lerne the trewgthe as hytt ys here :<br />Off my co<em>n</em>scyence my lord I reme<em>m</em>ber nott the co<em>n</em>tenttes off thatt l<em>ett</em>re butt<br />off thys. I doo ensure you<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce : ther was noo word offensyve In hytt<br />yff I dyd reme<em>m</em>ber the l<em>ett</em>re thorowly : by god I wold w<em>ri</em>te hytt unto yo<em>ur</em> g<em>ra</em>ce<br />Butt off thys be you<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce assuryd ther was notte one word a mysse In hytt<br />thatt I doo know : And yff I had reme<em>m</em>bryd yst<em>er</em>day when I was<br />w<em>ith</em> you<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce. I wold have dysclosyd thatt l<em>ette</em>re unto yow (as I dyd <em>the</em> other<br />w<em>ich</em> I wrote In the ffavor off Serles &amp; schether : the co<em>n</em>tenttes wheroff I<br />wyll aft<em>er</em> declare &amp; that as trewely as god schall putt Into my reme<em>m</em>brance.<br />mr schether requyryd me to make c<em>er</em>ten notes<br />ffor hym : I sso dyd &amp; thatt unkyndly : yff<br />I had ysterday reme<em>m</em>bryd my selffe. I wold <br />have dysclosyd them unto yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce<br />$1$ Ero<em>ris</em> as yett be nott tryid &amp; correctyd : butt dylygentt Inquyry<br />ys made off the boke p<em>re</em>sentyd<br />$2$ Answere ys made <em>par</em>tly affyrmatyvely <em>par</em>tly negative : <em>par</em>tly dubitative<br />$3$ We be accusyd Indyfferently one w<em>ith</em> an other : soo <em>that</em> one : as we doo<br />suppose : may bere ow<em>t</em> the other : butt yff Inquyry be made emo<em>n</em>gst the <br />gentylme<em>n</em> yemen &amp; the honesty off the curattes : and nott all callyd<br />accuse whoo wyll. I thynke the ffaw<em>t</em> wold sone apere wher hytt ys<br />$Thatys$ I namyd mr yngh<em>a</em>m mr hardes mr Thawyttes gentylme<em>n</em> able to say su<em>m</em>whatt<br />as they have had g<em>re</em>ffe : butt I beseche yow my lord call them nott ffor<br />hytt : I namyd them none o<em>ther</em>wyse unto mr schether : butt thatt ther <br />were : thatt herd some hosle &amp; div<em>er</em>syte emongst the peple : I beseche yo<em>ur</em> <br />g<em>ra</em>ce to kepe thes moch sec<em>re</em>tte unto you<em>r</em> owne co<em>n</em>scyence they were never seyd<br />$4$ It<em>em</em> yow<em>r</em> lectures : whatt they were : w<em>ith </em>whom dyv<em>er</em>se were offendyd as the vycar off S pawles : The vycar of Story : my lord off thys<br />matt<em>er</em> I wyll schew yow more so sone as I am att lyberty and may<br />speke w<em>ith</em> yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce : yest<em>er</em> day I reme<em>m</em>bryd hytt nott. I wold I hadd<br />Other not<em>es</em> in good ffaygthe I doo<br />nott remember<br /></body></xml>