<xml><body>off mr scory &amp; mr law<em>n</em>celet yo<em>ur</em> grace doth knowe <em>that</em> mr garden<em>er</em> &amp; I wer callyd to wyth<br />yn those artycles wyth the wych the people the<em>n</em> were offendyd yet they nothyng were<br />ponyshyd. And wheras also mr garden<em>er</em> &amp; I dyd also wytnesse w<em>ith</em> mr shether yn hys<br /><em>ser</em>mo<em>n </em>made at norgate wher (as nere as I dyd here or bear away) he p<em>re</em>chyd all<br />catholyke. &amp; godly . &amp; yet was ponyshyd by declaryng on a stole <em>that that</em> he nev<em>er</em> spake<br />as I beare yt away. &amp; <em>that</em> on the the only testymony off <del data-tag="del">John toftes</del> <em></em><add data-tag="add"><em>par</em>son off say<em>n</em>t elphege</add> &amp;  george may<br />as mr shether sayd. &amp; owr testymony taken as nothynge. And mr serlys also<br />for whose p<em>re</em>chyng catholyk most me<em>n</em> <em>that</em> hath herd hym. wyll wytnesse w<em>ith</em> hym<br />but at <em>that</em> tyme certay<em>n</em> <em>that</em> came to testyfy wyth hy<em>m</em> could not be herd but they rather<br />that made agay<em>n</em>st hym off the wych ensuyd mych troble &amp; vexatyon to <em>that</em> ma<em>n</em><br />By the reason off wych ii <em>par</em>teys thus handlyd &amp; yntreatyd. yff they <del data-tag="del">ii </del>(wych I<br />know not) or any other off ther fryndes have <em>com</em>play<em>n</em>yd . or ca<em>n</em> note yo<em>ur</em> grace culpable<br />I suppose they wyll Declare the v<em>er</em>yte unto yo<em>ur</em> grace. <br /><br />$7.8.9.$ To the vii th &amp; to the 8th I answer <em>that</em> I do not knowe wyth what Justyces or ge<em>n</em>tlemen<br />any p<em>er</em>son hath had <em>con</em>ference nother what me<em>n</em> hath do<em>n</em> or spokyn yn any matter<br />nor to what thynges me<em>n</em> have <em>con</em>ducyd unto <em>con</em>cerny<em>n</em>g matters <em>that</em> shuld <em>pro</em>cede at<br />Ca<em>n</em>t<em>erbury</em> except as ys before rehersyd wych I know not certayly. Or els <em>that</em> I have<br />herd mych <em>comu</em>nycatyo<em>n</em> off ge<em>n</em>tleme<em>n</em> &amp; other off the delyv<em>er</em>ance off Jone baron. (at the <br />table) by yo<em>ur</em> <em>com</em>messary. wheras she nother wold <em>con</em>fesse <em>that</em> she had denyyd the<br />sacrame<em>n</em>t off the alt<em>ar</em> <del data-tag="del">nether </del>wherby she shuld have askyd the kynges mayeste hys<br /><em>par</em>do<em>n</em>. nother yet askyd <em>par</em>do<em>n</em>. but she havy<em>n</em>g a <em>par</em>do<em>n</em> yn her boso<em>m</em> was bed<br />delyv<em>er</em> yt (as she dyd) &amp; therby was delyv<em>er</em>yd. at the wych hath byn mych<br />&amp; many tymes <em>com</em>munycatyo<em>n</em> amo<em>n</em>g the g<em>en</em>tles &amp; other.<br /><br />$10$ what petyt hath sayd or don yn any matters co<em>n</em>cerny<em>n</em>g yndyteme<em>n</em>tes or the clerke<br />off the peace (wyth who<em>m</em> I was nev<em>er</em> yn <em>com</em>pany. but ons at yo<em>ur</em> gracehys last<br />syttyng on the vi artycles) or any other towardes the lawe hath don. or yn<br />any other matt<em>er</em>, or by whose cow<em>n</em>sell, I know not except <em>that</em> petyte dyd<br />shewe a byll opy<em>n</em>ly <em>that</em> he sayd he wold put up to yo<em>ur</em> cha<em>n</em>celour agayn one<br />bukmer <em>that</em> as he sayd had denyyd the sacrame<em>n</em>t off the alter &amp; escapyd<br />ponyshme<em>n</em>t (as he sayd) at doctor nevy<em>n</em>sons hand ; And at yo<em>ur</em> syttyng on <br />the vi artycles The clerk off the peace. dyd wryt one Artycle <em>that</em> <br />shuld have made agay<em>n</em>st mr scory wych was thys The supp<em>er</em> off the lord ys<br />not sacrifici<em>um pro</em> p<em>ecca</em>tis but hostia laudis, but yt was not p<em>re</em>sentyd to the quest<br />but wythdrawy<em>n</em>.<br /><br />$11$ To the xiith I say by cause <em>that</em> I do not know certay<em>n</em>ly who be the p<em>re</em>senters<br />off matters <add data-tag="add">I do not know</add> to what end or effect they yntendyd to bry<em>n</em>g matters But thys<br />I a<em>m</em> assuryd <em>that</em> I nev<em>er</em> herd ma<em>n</em> wyshe but for unyte peace <em>con</em>cord &amp; cheryte. <br />amo<em>n</em>g the kynges <del data-tag="del">lege</del> leage people &amp; <em>that</em> such a way myght be taken<br />&amp; <del data-tag="del">fownd </del>meane fownd <em>that</em> all herisys errors erroneous opynyo<em>n</em>s &amp; scysme<br />myght be expellyd &amp; cheryte wax plentyfull yn ther hartes.</body></xml>