<xml><body><div>@r7@ @n1@</div>
<div>Serles</div>
<div>What nombre of evyl p<em>re</em>chers he knoweth w<em>ith</em>in <em>the</em> dioces of</div>
<div>Cantorbery, &amp; what they have p<em>re</em>ched amys.</div>
<div>Whether <em>the</em> Co<em>m</em>missary in his visitations co<em>m</em>mawnded <em>that</em></div>
<div><em>the</em> wax candelles blessed opon ca<em>n</em>dlemas day shal not be</div>
<div>delyv<em>er</em>ed unto the people, &amp; whether he harde hy<em>m</em> so co<em>m</em>maund<and whether="" he="" harde="" hym="" so="" commaund=""></and></div>
<div>It<em>em that</em> holy wat<em>er</em> sholde not be borne and cast in menes howses.</div>
<div>It<em>em</em> whether in som churches by <em>the</em> co<em>m</em>missaryes co<em>m</em>maunde-</div>
<div>ment al <em>the</em> images were pulled downe &amp; hewed with</div>
<div>axes</div>
<div>It<em>em</em> whether the co<em>m</em>misary be most conv<em>er</em>sant wi<em>th</em> abjured</div>
<div><em>per</em>sons &amp; other suspecte of herecie, aidynge may<em>n</em>tenynge</div>
<div>&amp; supportynge the same.</div>
<div>It<em>em</em> whether Joh<em>a</em>na Bochier were delyv<em>er</em>ed by favo<em>r</em> of</div>
<div>the co<em>m</em>missary or by <em>the</em> kynges pardon.</div>
<div>It<em>em</em> whether Giles were a lay man or a preist, &amp; what</div>
<div>sedition or erro<em>ur</em> he p<em>re</em>ched </div>
<div>It<em>em</em> whether opon our lady day <em>the</em> assu<em>m</em>ption was xii month</div>
<div>he cam to Cantorbery in a courtieres cote and a berde, &amp; ther</div>
<div>logded tenne dayes, &amp; Mr. hardes a justice of peace co<em>m</em>playned</div>
<div>of hy<em>m</em> to <em>the</em> co<em>m</em>missary, but <em>the</em> co<em>m</em>missary dyd no thynge.</div>
<div>It<em>em</em> whether a Taylo<em>ur</em> in Cantorbery do reade &amp; expownde</div>
<div><em>the</em> bible in his own howse, wherunto is open resorte</div>
<div>suffered by <em>the</em> co<em>m</em>missary of <em>the</em> Commissaryes knowlege.</div>
<div>It<em>em</em> whether the mast<em>er</em> of saynt Johns in Cantorbery at</div>
<div>his deth refused to receyve &amp; dispised <em>the</em> most blessed sacra-</div>
<div>ment of thaltare, &amp; yet by <em>the</em> sufferance of the saide co<em>m</em>missary</div>
<div>both was buryed like a true christen man, &amp; also is of veray</div>
<div>many praysed for a good &amp; an holy man.</div>
<div>It<em>em</em> whether Mr. Blande p<em>re</em>ched <em>that</em> a  in co<em>mmun</em>ication w<em>ith</em> Mr.</div>
<div>Spon<em>er</em> Vicar of boughton denyed auricular co<em>n</em>fession to be</div>
<div>requisite &amp; necessary, &amp; delyv<em>er</em>ed his opinion to Mr. Spon<em>er</em></div>
<div>in wrytynge. which <em>the</em> co<em>m</em>missary herynge, desiered Mr. Spon<em>er</em></div>
<div>to let hy<em>m</em> se <em>the</em> wrytynge, swerynge <em>that</em> he wolde not kepe</div>
<div>it fro<em>m</em> hy<em>m</em>. But whan he had <em>the</em> bil, he put it in his</div>
<div>purse</div>
<div>It<em>em</em> whether <em>the</em> co<em>m</em>missary resigned a benefice to <em>the</em> said</div>
<div>Blande, byndynge <em>the</em> said Blande &amp; his successores by his wry-</div>
<div>tynge made under my lorde of Cantorbery &amp; <em>the</em> chapt<em>er</em> seale,</div>
<div>to pay unto hy<em>m&amp;</em> his assignes <em>the</em> grett<em>er</em> parte of <em>the</em> clere yerly</div>
<div>value for many yeres.</div></body></xml>