<xml><body>$13$ Item what wourde Mr bacar sent <del data-tag="del">there</del> from London by Serlis.<br />$14$ Item what <add data-tag="add">boke</add> it was that was last sent to doctour Willoughby by <br />Shethers <em>ser</em>v<em>au</em>nt. What the matier thereof was/ and whan it <br />was made and sent<br />$15$ Item wherefore they avised Shether to write to Docto<em>ur</em> Willughby<br />to gett hym out of the waye/ and to repaire to the Courte, or to<br />some other of his freendis.<br />$16$ Item What Inditament that was whiche Parkhurst red one night<br />at supper whan they talked of the cessions of the vi articles<br />whos Indictament it was and where he had it<br />$17$ Item <add data-tag="add">Whether </add>Mr bacar saide to Parkehurst Gardiner and Shether whan<br />they wer at London that there shulde be a Commission in kent<br />shortelye<br />$18$ Item what names he wrote the sametyme to be in the co<em>m</em>mission <br />$19$ Item whither Mr Thwaites said as divers tymes <del data-tag="del">to Parkhurst<br />Gardiner and Shether or at the least to Parkhurst and <br />Gardiner</del> that they shuld still from tyme to tyme marke<br />what was preached and say nothing but note it <add data-tag="add">&amp; send<br />it to hy<em>m</em></add><em></em><br />$20$ Item at what tymes thesame was spoken. and whither he said <br />it was maister bacars counsaill<br />$21$ Item how many bookes were <del data-tag="del">del </del>delivered to Petit<br />$22$ Item whether one booke was made wherin was this article<br />That tharchbisshopp did say that he wold defende<br />Scory and Ridles opinions<br />$23$ Item where that book is becom and what tyme it was made<br />$24$ Item whither Parkehurst and Gardiner have co<em>m</em>moned w<em>ith</em><br />Petit that the Comissary / and other of evill opinions<br />and dispisers of the laudable ceremonies. wold not have been<br />so bold if they had not been comforted by lorde<br />$25$ Item whither they w<em>ith</em> Serlis and Shether have co<em>m</em>muned, Petit <br />being p<em>res</em>ent, that markcham stuarde to tharchebishop was <br />abiured / and what knouledge <del data-tag="del">Serles hath</del> <add data-tag="add">they have</add> thereof<br />$26$ Item to whom they sent to procure that Tharchebishop of Cant<em>erbury</em><br />shuld be no Commission<em>er</em>, nor know the witnes. / and<br />wherefore they so wrote or sent.</body></xml>