<xml><body>@r225@<br />Rythe worschypfull master docto<em>ur</em> : Att my last beyng <br />w<em>ith</em> my lord: I receyvyd c<em>er</em>ten Int<em>er</em>rogatoreys att hys <br />handes : And hys g<em>ra</em>ce wylled me Immedyatly uppo<em>n</em> the<br />receptt off them : to make answere unto them: And <br />so dyd I : Butt now sethe<em> that</em> tyme. I have reme<em>m</em>bryd<br />thatt c<em>er</em>ten off them conc<em>er</em>nyd the boke p<em>re</em>sentyd unto<br />whom my hand ys sett: Good Mr docto<em>ur</em>: unto all the <br />artyclys thatt my hand ys sett : I must off my co<em>n</em>scyence<br />and wyll stond unto <add data-tag="add">as I may</add>: Butt unto how many I have <br />sett my hand unto. I doo not reme<em>m</em>ber as yett: I <br />have cast In my mynd dyv<em>er</em>se tymys and oft: how many <br />I have wytnessyd unto: And yett I ca<em>n</em>nott call unto my <br />reme<em>m</em>brance: the trowzthe off hytt: I thynk <em>that</em> I have nott<br />subsc<em>ri</em>byd unto so many : as the boke schewythe: w<em>hich</em> my<br />lord<em>es</em> g<em>ra</em>ce : layde be ffore me: Good Mr docto<em>ur</em> seying thatt<br />the tyme was very schortt: when I made myne answer<em>es</em> unto<br />the last Int<em>er</em>rogatoreys: and also <em>that</em> I was fforgotfull and slakk<br />off memory: : now havy<em>n</em>g bett<em>er</em> reme<em>m</em>brawnce off <em>the</em> Int<em>er</em>rogatoreys<br />than then I had. I schall desyre yow (and I trust w<em>ith</em><br />yow<em>r</em> ffavor) thatt <em>that</em> answere cassatt: yow wyll acceptt thys<br />now sett : ffor my full and delyberatt answere : thatt<br />unto ev<em>er</em>y thyng wherunto my hand schall apere to be sett<br />unto. I must &amp; wyll stond: And I trust (no thyng unto <br />my gracyusse lord<em>es</em> dysplaesure: ne<em>ther</em> yett unto my hynderawnce<br />Jhe<em>sus</em> kepe yow<em>r</em> mast<em>er</em>schypp <br />yow<em>rs</em> Willi<em>a</em>m<br />Gardn<em>er</em></body></xml>