<xml><body>@r263@<br />Edmo<em>n</em>d Schethers Answer unto. <br />2 &amp; 3 I can not depose by <em>the</em> relation of Mr <em>par</em>krst selle<em>ger</em> &amp; o<em>ther</em><br />$1$ To <em>the</em> first I know not <del data-tag="del">but by relation of</del> <add data-tag="add">whether </add>Mr <em>par</em>kurst &amp; Mr senlleng<em>er </em>p<em>re</em>sented the <br />same articles or no or whether they be fewr or alterd. but by ther own relatio<em>n</em>.<br />$2$ I did not here the witnes published but I hard the witnes say that<br />thei wold depose in them if thei wer examened. I know not.<br />$3$ <del data-tag="del">I say as to the first article</del>.<add data-tag="add"> I know not. </add><br />$4$ I hard him <add data-tag="add">my lordes grace</add> Rebuke mr serles for that he hadd preached so much of ymages<br />and <add data-tag="add">my lord<em>es</em> grace</add> said that idolu<em>m</em> &amp; imago was one for <em>the</em> one was the grek woord<br />&amp; <em>the</em> other the laten./ otherwise I know not <em>that</em> he did rebuk him.<br />&amp; I hard not my lord<em>es</em> grace rebuke him for thos woordes.<br />$5.$ I hard his grace say in his chamber befor many p<em>re</em>bendaris &amp; p<em>re</em>chers <em>that</em><br />the kyng<em>es</em> ple<em>sur</em> was to have .3. prechers of the new lerni<em>n</em>g &amp; iii<br />of the old but I hard not thes woordes spoken in the consistory. <br />$6$ I know not who accused them <del data-tag="del">&amp; therfor I can not depose of the article</del> <add data-tag="add">nor whet<em>her</em> thei wer suspecte for ewell opynions</add><br />$7$ I did se .3. w<em>hich</em> cam voluntaryli to testifie for Mr serles w<em>hich</em> could not be<br />admitted <add data-tag="add">as master serles said</add> Also I req<em>ui</em>red that the vicar of northgat &amp; mr garden<em>er</em> mast<em>er</em><br />selleng<em>er</em> coxston might be examened in my first article w<em>hich</em> wer<br />redy but by reson of delay the said vicar was wered &amp; not examened<br />&amp; whether the other wer examyned or no I ca<em>n</em> not tell.<br />$8$ In the deposition of my first article then obiected was admitted <br />george may &amp; Sir hu<em>m</em>frey cherdayn <em>par</em>sons suspecte for evell opynions <add data-tag="add">by common fame as I herd</add><br />and certayn w<em>hich</em> deposed aga<em>n</em>st mr serles wer likwise suspecte <add data-tag="add">And befor<br />sente<em>n</em>s I desired my lordes grace to have respect to the <em>par</em>sons that did depose.</add><br />$9$ I thinke them innocent p<em>re</em>chers And I <add data-tag="add">did</add> redde a declaration of articles<br />w<em>hich</em> wer surmised aganst me : but by whome serles was co<em>m</em>mitted to<br />p<em>ri</em>son I can not tell<br />$10$ By reison <em>that</em> I and serles wer willed to redde declarations in the <br />w<em>hich</em> it was me<em>n</em>tioned that that which we said was seditiously<br />spoken I thinke the occasion of <add data-tag="add">our</add> my accasation did rise &lt;&gt;<br />that I somtymes spak aganst evell opynio<em>n</em>s by the which <add data-tag="add">wherfor</add> &lt;&gt;<br />have spoken the lesse aganst the same bicause I wold &lt;&gt;<br />like occasion. &amp; further I can not say in the article. <br />$11$ <em>Sir</em> bland mr scory sir turn<em>er</em> have be noted much bolder syn&lt;&gt;<br />of the said accusation vpon what occasion <add data-tag="add">ells </add>I can not a&lt;&gt;<br /><add data-tag="add">hath hadd disple<em>sur</em> for co<em>m</em>plani<em>n</em>g I know not. </add><br />$12$ I know nother of the ymages nor of the letters.<br />$13$ mr baker sent woord (as I reme<em>m</em>ber) <em>that</em> he m<em>er</em>veled I tar&lt;&gt;<br />did not bring the book <em>per</em>fectly maid &amp; sent no other &lt;&gt;<br />know.</body></xml>