<xml><body><div>@r53@ @n18@</div>
<div>$M<em>ist</em>res. Starkey$ She spake that it was Iod Idolatrye to crepe</div>
<div>to the Crosse. She being examyned denyed <em>the</em> same</div>
<div>$Marget Toftes thelder$ Marget Toftes thelder among other wourdes said</div>
<div>whan my lorde of Canterburys grace com<em>m</em>yth down</div>
<div>to Canterbury, we truste to have adaye againste</div>
<div>you, and div<em>er</em>s other threpenyng wourdes</div>
<div>She said that she wolde speake to Mr. Comissarye</div>
<div>to Comande all the curates in Canterburye to reade</div>
<div>the Bible as thei have of late don, Bradkirke</div>
<div>saying, he shall then do contrary to the kyng<em>e</em>s ordyn<em>a</em>nces</div>
<div>acte and Inj<em>u</em>nctions, She said againe yt ys the</div>
<div>more petie, that goddes wourde shall so litle be sett by</div>
<div>that it may not be redde openly</div>
<div>Testes</div>
<div>Thomas Bredekyrke</div>
<div>Roger mantell</div>
<div>$n$ Jo. Boydon</div>
<div>$To Hasylden Tlunestede$ He spake contemptiously againste the kynges Inj<em>u</em>nctio<em>n</em>s</div>
<div>$Injunctions$ $n$ saying a farte for theym</div>
<div>$offensive$ He asked why he shoulde do more reverence to the</div>
<div>Crucifix than to the galouse</div>
<div>he said that he knewe his wourdes shoulde be disclosid</div>
<div>and he wolde come to his answer</div>
<div>It<em>e</em>m he said that and he coulde lyve w<em>ith</em>out synne, he were</div>
<div>as good as god</div>
<div>$Images$ he was co<em>m</em><hewas co="">maunded by Sir Thomas moyle to set up images which he had taken downe</hewas></div>
<div>&amp; to garnish they<em>m</em>. he hath set they<em>m </em>up, but not garnished they<em>m</em> </div>
<div>$Bett$ Hamonde Bett said That when soev<em>er</em> he died, that</div>
<div>$offensive$ he wolde neither have ryngyng nor syngyng, ne</div>
<div>any man<em>er</em> of Almes dede to be don for his sowle</div>
<div>And careth not / though he were buried in a diche</div>
<div>or els where /</div></body></xml>