<xml><body>@r229@<br />than sayde Garden<em>er</em> plesyth you<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce : I thinke nay: ffor an ydoll<br />ys thatt thyng w<em>hich</em> hathe gevyn unto hym suche hono<em>ur</em> as ys dew<br />unto god: or unto <em>the</em> sayntt: Then sayde my lord you know<br />nott <em>the</em> greke: ffor In <em>the</em> greke: ydolum &amp; Imago ar all one : My <br />lord sayde Gardn<em>er</em> : although I know nott <em>the</em> g<em>re</em>ke yett I trust <br />I know the trezthe. &amp; thatt by sayntt paule : rehersyg Roman 1°.<br /><br />It<em>em</em> vi p<em>re</em>chers iii off the old iii off the new : <em>etc.</em> :Then sayd gardn<em>er</em>: My <br />lord thatt ys a maene to sett us att varyance / My <br />lord sayd: the kyng<em>es</em> plesure ys to have hytt soo: We therw<em>ith</em><br />were co<em>n</em>tentyd: // My lord when I was last w<em>ith</em> yo<em>ur</em> grace &amp;<br />made ansere unto <em>this</em> artycle yo<em>ur</em> g<em>ra</em>ce sayde unto me : Thatt you<br />sayde thus: I have schewyd the kyng<em>es</em> g<em>ra</em>ce whatt I hadd don<br />and he was well plesyd: Thes word<em>es</em> now last rehersyd<br />I wrote in myne answere <add data-tag="add">att thatt tyme</add> : butt <add data-tag="add">yet</add> nott denying the o<em>the</em>r w<em>hich</em> I have<br />now rehersyd beffore: ffor off my co<em>n</em>scyence you dyd speke then<br />And therffor althoghe I dyd nott putt them Into myne answere <add data-tag="add">then</add><br />yett. I trust you wylnott soo take me : nor ca<em>n</em>nott so take<br />me: that I deny thatt :: I <add data-tag="add">did</add> putt <em>the</em> word<em>es</em> w<em>hich</em> yo<em>ur</em> g<em>ra</em>ce sayd : <em>that</em><br />you sayde: nott denyng the o<em>ther:</em> to co<em>n</em>tentt you<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>c<em>es</em> mynd: ffor<br />almost they be one in effectt :<br />It<em>em</em> I call the<em>m</em> inoce<em>n</em>tt p<em>re</em>chers: a yenst whom noo ffaw<em>t</em> justly can<br />be ffound ffor p<em>re</em>chying : butt as ffor thes iii serles &amp; schether <em>ser</em>mons<br />w<em>ith</em> us In our churche p<em>re</em>chyd : the most off o<em>ur</em> church wyll testyffye to be <br />good godly &amp; quyet : : In the co<em>n</em>tre also wher they have have byn ther<br />audyence have lykewyse reportyd off them bothe by word also by<br />w<em>ri</em>tyng : Wherffor seying they have p<em>re</em>chyd soo : thatt <em>ther</em> audyence ys godly<br />edyffyd by them &amp; the kyng<em>es</em> ordynance quyetly sett forthe : we doo<br />name them Innoce<em>n</em>tt p<em>re</em>chers w<em>ith</em>owt ffaw<em>t </em>ffor ther p<em>re</em>chyng</body></xml>