<xml><body><div>Shether</div>
<div>$Seditious$ That there was one straite waye to the truth in w<em>hich</em> waye</div>
<div>all men have gone a long tyme, saving a fewe nowe of late</div>
<div>not being content to folowe that trade, hath wandered in div<em>er</em>s</div>
<div>path waies to seke a nerer waye unto the truth, but</div>
<div>thei arr like unto one, that being cleane loste, was fayne</div>
<div>$n$ to aske, whiche waye he myght goo to thende of his jorneye</div>
<div>And to suche it was answered, you be cleane oute of the</div>
<div>waye, and there is none other meane for you, but even to</div>
<div>turne backe agayne, and to begynne your jorney againe</div>
<div>where you lefte, Nothing attall admonishing the people of</div>
<div>the waye whiche men had loste by defending and reteynyng</div>
<div>the usurpac<em>i</em>on of Rome, Nor of no mention that the kinges</div>
<div>Ma<em>jestie</em> hath reformed the abuses of su<em>per</em>sticious Religion, but</div>
<div>even as one, that wold have all thinges honestely reformed</div>
<div>to reverte againe into thair su<em>per</em>stic<em>i</em>on for the maynten<em>a</em>unce</div>
<div>of all blindenes and errou<em>r</em>, comanded ev<em>er</em>y man to turne</div>
<div>backe, and to begynne where thei lefte. Dr. Nicolas Rydley.</div>
<div>Dr. Lancelot Ridley. Mr. Drumme, Mr. Scory, Mr. Broke. Mr.</div>
<div>Nevil, Toftes, Kesham.</div>
<div>$n$ Browne of Charteham</div>
<div>He <em>pro</em>mised unto James Terrey a lease of his house for x</div>
<div>$the kynges su<em>pre</em>micie$ yeres, and after Indentures made dischargid hym, for none oth<em>er</em></div>
<div>cause, but that the said Terrey founde fawte w<em>ith</em> the Indentures</div>
<div>that the kynges title of supremecie was left oute, S<em>ir</em> Richarde Turner</div>
<div>James Terrey and Badcocke.</div>
<div>$offerynge of candelles$ It<em>e</em>m at Candelmas was xii moneth. he for hym and his wife</div>
<div>alone offered Candelles unto the Roode contrary unto the</div>
<div>kynges Inju<em>n</em>ctions, witnes the hole parishe</div>
<div>He will not pay his tythes as he hath used to do in tymes</div>
<div>past Sir Richard Turner</div>
<div>Item he repyneth at the collection, for the aide againste</div>
<div>the Turkes, witnes Mr. Evias and Mr. hedde,</div></body></xml>