<xml><body>@r327@<br />$1$ To the fyrst ynterrogatory I say <em>that</em> I have had no co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em> wyth any <em>that</em> hath cu<em>m</em> to<br />offer themselvys for shether nother for serlys yn to testymony except <em>that</em> one day at<br />the fyrst cu<em>m</em>yng off yo<em>ur</em> chau<em>n</em>celars co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em> was <del data-tag="del">the </del>off a certay<em>n</em> off lena<em>m</em> off mr serlys<br />s<em>er</em>mo<em>n</em> ther last made <del data-tag="del">wych</del> wych <em>con</em>cernyd the mylk off o<em>ur</em> lady. <em>that</em> she had yt not<br />as other men have bycause she <em>con</em>ceyvyd not by the <em>com</em>pany off ma<em>n</em>. Those wordes<br />wer spokyn yn mr p<em>ar</em>khurst chambre by one wyllyams off lana<em>m</em> John p<em>ar</em>khurst fryer &amp; <br />other <em>that</em> dyd cu<em>m</em> at <em>that</em> tyme fro<em>m that</em> <em>par</em>yshe.<br /><br />$2$ To the 2d I say <em>that</em> I do know no ma<em>n</em> to have had co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em> wyth yo<em>ur</em> grace yn the passyo<em>n</em> <br />weke. But ons I herd mr garden<em>er</em> say <em>that</em> he beyng wyth yo<em>ur</em> grace at la<em>m</em>byth yo<em>ur</em> grace<br />sayd <em>that</em> he was accusyd to you to have prechyd sedytyously <del data-tag="del">&amp; </del><br /><br />$3$ <del data-tag="del">The </del>To the thyrd I say <em>that</em> mr sentleger mr <em>par</em>khurst &amp; other hath sayd <em>that</em> they have fearyd<br /><em>that</em> they had yo<em>ur</em> grace hys dyspleasure &amp; as he reportyd yo<em>ur</em> wordes <em>pro</em>frryd unto hy<em>m</em><br />at fe<em>vers</em>ha<em>m</em> ex<em>pr</em>essyd the same. wych wordes wer <em>that</em> ther was a bond <del data-tag="del">ffers</del> amo<em>n</em>gst us<br />wych yo<em>ur</em> grace wold breke. These wordes grevyd hy<em>m</em> &amp; causyd hy<em>m</em> <em>per</em>adve<em>n</em>ture<br />&amp; other to thynk <em>that</em> yo<em>ur</em> grace yntendyd dyspleasure to hy<em>m</em> &amp; other ; And they knewe <br />no cause why ? except yt wer for offery<em>n</em>g co<em>m</em>playntes off certey<em>n</em> thynges p<em>re</em>chyd, wych<br />co<em>m</em>play<em>n</em>t to offer up to yo<em>ur</em> grace. they <em>that</em> dyd yt wer <em>com</em>pellyd by yo<em>ur</em> grace as I was<br />to be a wytnesse. And me<em>n</em> hath musyd <em>that</em> thys eascapyd so lo<em>n</em>g no<em>n</em> ponyshment.<br /><br />$4$ I a<em>m</em> ygnora<em>n</em>t off the 4th for I have had no co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em> w<em>ith</em> doctor wyllyhby y<em>n</em> matt<em>er</em>s. <br /><br />$5$ To the 5th I say <em>that</em> my lorde wardens chaple<em>n</em> was wyshyd to have byn p<em>re</em>bendary<br />here &amp; he sayd <em>that</em> he was well rydd off yt. for yff he had byn one off us he sayd<br /><em>that</em> <em>per</em>adve<em>n</em>ture he had byn the<em>n</em> as fast as su<em>m</em> other hath by<em>n</em> &amp; wheras he was spoky<em>n</em> unto <br />for to speke to hys m<em>aste</em>r for serlys <em>that</em> yo<em>ur</em> grace shuld be good to hy<em>m</em> he sayd he wold.<br /><br />$6$ what co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em> hath byn off any boke <em>pre</em>sentyd to yo<em>ur</em> grace syth yo<em>ur</em> cu<em>m</em>yng to ca<em>n</em>t<em>erbury</em><br />I reme<em>m</em>bre not. but <em>that</em> I herd mr <em>par</em>khurst say <em>that</em> he delyv<em>er</em>yd yo<em>ur</em> grace a boke yn<br />the cloyst<em>er</em>. &amp; mr garden<em>er</em> sayd <em>that</em> he had sent an other <em>that</em> dyd declare the truth as he<br />sayd off matt<em>er</em>s. but what yt was I knowe not. &amp; as they sayd they had <del data-tag="del">sent</del> sent <br />&amp; delyv<em>er</em>yd the<em>m</em>. so they trustyd <em>that</em> yo<em>ur</em> grace wold favorably accept the<em>m</em>. <br /><br />$7$ what co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em> any ma<em>n</em> have had or herd off scory serlys or shether <em>con</em>cerny<em>n</em>g these matt<em>er</em>s <br />I know not but I have herd the<em>m</em> dyv<em>er</em>s tymes comy<em>n</em> off ther artycles put up by ther <br />accusars &amp; off ther accusars &amp; wytnesse.<br /><br />$8$ To the viiith I say <em>that</em> I do know no ma<em>n</em> to have had <em>con</em>fere<em>n</em>ce w<em>ith</em> other upon matters<br />except the co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n that</em> mr garden<em>er</em> mr <em>par</em>khurst &amp; I had on mu<em>n</em>day (as I declaryd<br />by a byll sent to yo<em>ur</em> grace) wych co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em> I trust was not <em>con</em>trary to <br />o<em>ur</em> allegya<em>n</em>ce to the kynges mayeste.<br /><br />$9$ what I have kowy<em>n</em> off my owne kowlege p<em>re</em>sentyd agay<em>n</em> yo<em>ur</em> grace to be true<br />off thartycles. I ca<em>n</em> not answere : bycause I was nev<em>er</em> off kowlege or cow<em>n</em>sell off <br />any such boke put up or to agreable ther unto. Althoge at the suggestyo<em>n</em> of mr<br />gardyn<em>er</em> ? mr sentleger &amp; I dyd rashly subscrybe to certay<em>n</em> artycles wych whether<br />they be p<em>re</em>sentyd or not I know not but by heresay. And at such tyme as we dyd subscrybe we knewe nott off any off ther such goynges abowt : But what yn the<br />boke off thartycles <em>that</em> shether delyv<em>er</em>yd to yo<em>ur</em> grace I thoght to be true I exp<em>re</em>ssyd<br />yn my a<em>n</em>swer to yo<em>ur</em> <del data-tag="del">ynterrogaty </del>ynterrogatorys fyrst sent to me.</body></xml>