<xml><body>@r265a@<br />$13.$ mr baker sent me woord (as I reme<em>m</em>ber) <em>that </em>he m<em>ar</em>veled I tared so long--<br />and did not bring the book <em>per</em>fectly mayd &amp; he sent no other woord<br />that I know.<br />$14.$ The same book w<em>hich</em> was delyv<em>ered</em> after to petit co<em>n</em>tayni<em>n</em>g many articles<br />un<em>pro</em>ved And this book was sent mr williby to shew my lord of<br />wynchest<em>er </em>about corpus chri<em>sti</em> day.<br />$15.$ By the advice of Mr <em>par</em>kurst &amp; garden<em>er</em> (I wrot that day <em>that </em>doctor<br />cockes last de<em>par</em>ted from cant<em>erbury</em>) to Mr willibye that he shuld<br />absent him selfe so <em>that</em> he shuld not be spoken w<em>ith</em> all for to know by<br />him the author of the book And that if he wer examened of the<br />said book that he shuld say <em>that</em> it was of coxstons doing And<br />bycause many articles of the book concerned my lordes grace<br />him selfe thei willed him to absent him selfe.<br />$16.$ Ther was A copy of an Endightme<em>n</em>t redde one night at Mr parkhurst<br />at sup<em>per</em> by petite with out ony name but wherfor I know not.<br />$17.18.$ I hard him affirme no co<em>m</em>mission to be sent but he noted many<br />gentle mens names whome I know not saving mr moyle Mr grene<br />Mr twatt<em>es</em> (as I reme<em>m</em>ber)<br />$19.20.$ I hard him not say so. <br />$21.$ I delyv<em>er</em>ed one book to petite by thadvice of mr garden<em>er</em> w<em>hich</em> booke<br />(as I have said) was of coxtons hand &amp; drawght and co<em>n</em>tayned<br />many articles un<em>pro</em>ved<br />$22.$ I think <em>the</em> same articles was in it in such forme as is in the <br />book of the articles writon <em>with</em> my brothers hand. <br />$23.$ It was maid aft<em>er</em> that I was w<em>ith</em> mr baker the second tyme<br />but wher the book is I know not but petit said he wold n[ot]<br />delyv<em>er</em> it but only show it &amp; send it agayn<br />$24.$ I haue not hard them co<em>m</em>myn of it. <br />$25.$ I hard not of it nor know whether it be so or no. <br />$26.$ They desired the same of mr baker by me bycause many <br />articles towched my lord. <br />$27$. I know not <em>the</em> day but it was about rogatio<em>n</em> weke as I think<br />$28.29.$ It was not one book for ther was certayn articles towch[ing]<br />t<em>he</em> co<em>m</em>munycation betwext my lordes grace &amp; mr garden<em>er</em> le[ft]<br />owt bicause it was only oone mans sayng.<br />$30.$ It is in doctor london is hand (as I think) for I did but se&lt;&gt;<br />$31.$ I know not wher petit hath done it nor what is co<em>n</em>tayned<br />therin for coxston noted many articles w<em>hich</em> I know not <br />I thinke it was delyv<em>er</em>d petit about t<em>ri</em>nite sonday last</body></xml>