<xml><body>@r293@<br />Sentleger<br /><br />$ff$. To the first article I say. that in the booke of complaint is one<br />article added, whiche nevertheles was spoken of to my lord<br />but because there was but one witnes, it was not presented<br />in writing / and iii articles be left out, and in one article<br />whiche maketh mention of co<em>m</em>itie be added thies wourdes,<br />of all thinges. <br />To the second, witnes was brought in / but what was <em>pro</em>ved<br />I knowe not. <br />To the thirde, I know not the cause, why iii articles<br />wer lefte out / nor I nev<em>er </em>herd the book thoroughly red.<br />To the iiiith. I do not remembre that my lord rebuked<br />Serlis for thies wourdes / <add data-tag="add">but </add>my lord said : that all<br />ymages wer Idolles. for the greke wourd idolu<em>m</em> and<br />ymago were all one.<br />To the vth. I say. that my lord said / that he had<br />put in three of the new lernyng / and iii of thold / and<br />declared the same to the kinges grace / who was pleased<br />therew<em>ith</em> all.<br />To the vi. I know nothing. <br />To the vii. I can say nothing, saving that I herd saye<br />I cannot tell of whome / that certaine of hothefild<br />and som of Caunterburie offred them selfes to testifie<br />for mr Serlis. / But how many they were that<br />offred them self<em>es</em> or of whome I <del data-tag="del">offr </del>hard that any <br />offred them self<em>es</em> I know not. <br />To the viiith I know nothing<br />To the ix I hard no preaching of them but well, to my<br />Judgement. But Shether made a declaration to c<em>er</em>tain<br />articles. Whither they wer falcely surmised or no, I <br />know not. / And by whome Serlis was co<em>m</em>mitted to prison<br />I know not / but that it was by the counsaill.<br />To the xth I know no suche thinge. <br />To the xi. I know no suche thinge<br />To the xii. the rood of the northe dore was taken downe<br />by my lordes co<em>m</em>maundeme<em>n</em>t / as Mr Comissary repoarted<br />And further I ca<em>n</em>not say in this Article. <br /><br />By me Arthur sentlager</body></xml>