<xml><body>@r311@<br />Cock<em>es</em><br />iido die mens<em>is</em> Novembris An<em>no</em> Regni xxxvto<br /><br />Will<em>ia</em>m Cock<em>es </em>being examyned of such wourd<em>es</em><br />and co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on as hath ben hadd at any tyme before this p<em>rese</em>nt <br />daye in the chamber of Mr parckhuste prebendary <br />of Christes church in Canterbury, by Mr Willoughby<br />vicar of Chilham mr Sandewiche Mr Mylles<br />Mr hadeley Mr parkehurste or any other <em>per</em>son <br />concernyng doctrine, preaching, the kinges highnes<br />proceding<em>es</em>, or any other thing <add data-tag="add">towching </add>kyng<em>es</em> maiestie <br />or any alterac<em>i</em>on don of late yeres by the kinges g<em>ra</em>ce<br />or his counsaile in this Realme againste the bisshop<br />of Rome or otherwaies / Saieth that about <br />lent paste, by reason of co<em>mmun</em>icac<em>i</em>on had among the company<br />$D. willoughby$ there, before dyner, he harde Mr Willoughby vicar<br />$n$ of Chilham saye, That what soev<em>er</em> thei were, that wold<br />take payne in the bissynes wherin doct<em>or</em> london was<br />settawo<em>r</em>ke by the kinge in bultyng oute of this newe<br />fasshion of doctrine, sholde not only receyve <add data-tag="add">re</add>ward<br />at thande of god and thank<em>es</em> of the kinges maiestie<br />but also afterwarde temporall proffitt<br />Item the said vicar reported at that tyme that doctour<br />London was very busely occupied in thexamynac<em>i</em>on of <br />the busynes and mattiers of wyndes<em>er</em>.<br /><br />It<em>e</em>m this said depone<em>n</em>t saieth that after Christmas was<br />xii monethes, being in Mr parkchurstes chamber, there were<br />deliv<em>er</em>ed l<em>ett</em>res frome doctour Champion unto Mr parkehurst<br />w<em>hich</em> l<em>ett</em>res were reported to come frome my lordes grace<br />and Mr deane concernyng the taking down of <br />an ymage of o<em>ur</em> Ladie. At whiche tyme one said unto<br />this deponente whose name he cannot remember. Sir <br />nowe ar you discharged for taking down of <del data-tag="del">this </del>the <br />ymage, wherfore will you testifie nowe that my lorde<br />hath com<em>m</em>andid that this ymage shoulde be taken down<br />Wherapon this deponent seyng and beholding my lordes<br />hande there represented in a le<em>ttr</em>e saied I will testifie<br />the same and did put his hande unto a paper; <br /><br />Be me sir William cockes prest</body></xml>