<xml><body><div>@r31@ @n7@</div>
<div>to the church for holy watter to cast about their howses</div>
<div>to dryve away il spirites and devilles, notwithstandynge</div>
<div>the kynges majesties proclamations to the contrary in the same.</div>
<div>$Injunctions$ he hath not red to theym the kynges injunctions as he</div>
<div>ought to do, by reason wherof the parish be blynde</div>
<div>&amp; ignorant in theym. witnes the parish.</div>
<div>Bartilmewe Joye</div>
<div>$confession$ he confessed to his curate in general, sayinge, I am a synner.</div>
<div>And whan the Vicar asked hym wherin he had synned,</div>
<div>he answered that he had confessed hym selfe to the lorde alredy</div>
<div>&amp; <that he=""> wolde make none other confession at that tyme, &amp; so</that></div>
<div>departed. william kempe vicarius</div>
<div>John Toftes. Christofor levenysh,</div>
<div>Bartylmewe Ioy 17 Nouenbrer Anno 30</div>
<div>$images$ Thay pulled downe al the pictures in the church of Northgate</div>
<div>in Cantorbery, except only the roode, mary &amp; John, the</div>
<div>xii apostelles, the picture of our lady &amp; saynt John Baptist</div>
<div>Item the iide of decembre anno 34. John Toftes dyd pul downe</div>
<div>the picture of our lady, &amp; had her &amp; the tabernacle home</div>
<div>to his howse, &amp; ther dyd hew her al in peces.</div>
<div>Item 15 Iuly ulter preterito, John Toftes openly &amp; with lowde</div>
<div>voice red the bible in English in the church to his wife,</div>
<div>Sterkeys wife, George Toftes wife, to the mydwife of the</div>
<div>same parish, &amp; to as many other as than were present.</div>
<div>Johanna Meryweder of saynt Mildredes parish.</div>
<div>$superstition$ ffor displeasure that she bare towardes <a younge="" maide="" named=""> Elizabet Celsay &amp;</a></div>
<div>$n$ her mother, made a fire opon the donge of the said Elizabet</div>
<div>$she dyd ytt not but sayd she wold do ytt$ and toke a waxe <holy> candle, &amp; dropped opon the said donge vii</holy></div>
<div>tymes. And she tolde unto her neighbures, that the said</div>
<div>inchauntment wolde make the cule of the said mayde to</div>
<div>divide into ii partes. presented by the olde scole master</div>
<div>Raufe the bel rynger of christes church</div>
<div>At the burial of Doctor Champion after the preist had sensed</div>
<div>grave, &amp; a boye was berynge away the censeres &amp; the cooles,</div>
<div>$n$ called agayne the boye, &amp; toke the censeres &amp; powred the hote</div>
<div>coles opon hym in the grave, to the grete sclaunder of the said</div>
<div>D. Champion, as though he had been an heretike worthy</div>
<div>burnynge. wytnes al the quere that were present.</div>
<div>$Images$ he said the kynge was content that al images sholde be honored as</div>
<div>they were wont to be. ffilpot</div></body></xml>