<xml><body>@r339@<br />Ad 4m<br /><br />Unto my lord wardens chaplen : I spake butt lytle : hys<br />co<em>m</em>munycatyon was most w<em>ith </em>other men : Butt thys I sayde<br />unto hym I p<em>ra</em>y yow : speke ffor me unto my lord yow<em>r</em> m<em>aster</em><br />ffor trewly : yff I were ons clere and uppo<em>n</em> evyn grownd att<br />lyberty I wold be ware : how I cam<em>m</em>e Into such a danger<br />a gen : And thys g<em>re</em>vythe me myche : In thatt : <em>that</em> I dyd nott <br />ffyrst co<em>m</em>playne co<em>m</em>playne unto my lord myne ordynary : beffore<br />thatt we dyd attemptt the matt<em>er</em> any hygher : well thys don<br />I trow I wylbe ware.<br /><br />Ad Vm<br /><br />W<em>ith</em> mr schether I had co<em>m</em>munycatyon In mr p<em>ar</em>khurst gardyn lame<em>n</em>ty<em>n</em>g<br />thys chawnce : off god desyryng to have an end : ffor we were<br />wery off thys troble : In mynd nev<em>er</em> to be troblyd ffor lyke matt<em>er</em><br />a gen : I askyd off hym : Thynke yow : <em>that</em> thend wylbe schortly <br />he sayde : yea I thynke be ffore chrystmasse : I p<em>ra</em>y god hytt<br />may sayd I : And soo : that my lord may take hono<em>r</em> by hytt<br />and we noo dyshonesty : I sayde Thynke yow that any grett<br />troble wyll cu<em>m</em>me unto us : Shether sayde : I ca<em>n</em>not tell : I<br />sayde : As plaesyth god so be hytt : I trust my lord wyll dryve <br />all unto a good end ; I sayde : I thank god : I ffynd my lord<br />good : soo doo I sayde schether : I am glad theroff sayde I : Then <br />sayde schether : I wold the matt<em>er</em> myghte be takyn upp a bove<br />&amp; ther an end made qwykly : well sayde I / as hytt plesythe<br />them to order hytt. I wylbe co<em>n</em>tentyd : I dystrust nott my lord<br />Off the boke delyv<em>er</em>yd unto my lordes grace : I dyd wonder thatt hytt <br />was nott delyv<em>er</em>yd all thys tyme : I told hym <em>that</em> I dyd see hytt<br />In hys chamber abowt thasu<em>m</em>ptyon tyme and then hytt was blottyd<br />he sayde hytt was ther : butt wher hytt was now he cowd nott tell<br />And styll we desyryd thatt In thend off thys matt<em>er</em> : yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce myghte have<br />hono<em>r</em> and we noo dyshonesty : Thys was oftyn tymes rehersyd.</body></xml>