<xml><body>@r335@<br />Interrogatories for Gardiner<br /><br />$1$ What co<em>m</em>municacion he had w<em>ith </em>Parkehurst or Mr Milles syns he<br />was put at libertie, or w<em>ith</em> anny other concerning them that / cam to offre<br />them selfis to testifie for Serlis and Shether.<br /><br />$2$ What co<em>mmun</em>ication he had or hard concerning his co<em>mmun</em>ication w<em>ith </em>tharchebishop <br />at London in passion weeke was xii mounethis<br /><br />$3$ what co<em>mmun</em>ication he had of any that had displeasure of thordinarye<br />for complayning of ill preachers. / or favo<em>ur</em> of hym toward is preachers<br /><br />$4$ What co<em>mmun</em>ication he had, or harde of docto<em>r</em> willoughby<br /><br />$5$ What co<em>mmun</em>icacion was had w<em>ith</em> my lorde wardens chaplen<br /><br />$6$ What co<em>mmun</em>icacion he had apon wedensdaye at night with Shether in the garden<br /><br />$7$ What he said of the booke, that he delivered to my lorde syns his commyng to canterburye<br /><br />$8$ What co<em>mmun</em>icacion he had or harde of Milles Skorye, Serles, Shether<br />or of any other<br /><br />$9$ What movid hym to have conference w<em>ith</em> other in theis matters co<em>n</em>trary<br />to his othe and allegiance<br /><br />$10$ what he knoweth to be true of tharticles presentid againste the <br />Archebisshop of Canterburye, of his awn knowledge<br /><br />$11$ Whither Mr Smyth p<em>ar</em>son of saincte Mary Mawdelens in Canterb<em>u</em>ry<br />had com<em>mu</em>nicacion w<em>ith</em> doctour Barbour in the north courte of christchurch<br />in Canterburye, the same daie that Serles and Shether were called <br />before my lorde and what <add data-tag="add">the</add> co<em>mmun</em>icacion was<br /><br />$12$ It<em>e</em>m why the same Smyth made as thoughe, he wolde have gone home<br />and then returned againe and went to Mr Parkehurste Chamber<br />there being Mr Parkehurst / Mr Garden<em>er</em> / Mr Milles / Mr Serles / Mr <br />Shether<br /><br />$13$ Item at that tyme when my lorde sent for Mr Serls, and Mr Shether<br />why thei denyed theym to be there, and what co<em>mmun</em>icacion thei harde at<br />that tyme /<br /><br />$14$ Wherfor he in his answere at tharchbusshoppes last co<em>m</em><br />mynge to Canturbery said that he wrote rather as <br />tharchbusshope said, than as his co<em>n</em>science iuged to be <br />true, &amp; what thynges they were <em>that</em> he so wrote <br />agaynst his co<em>n</em>science.</body></xml>