<xml><body><div>@r61@ @n22@</div>
<div>thought wourthy of reformac<em>i</em>on other in hym or</div>
<div>in any other, by reason of whiche facte and wourd<em>es</em></div>
<div>of the said Mr. Batterste, it is thought that other</div>
<div>do feare the rather to shewe thair mynd<em>es</em> to speake in</div>
<div>like causes and specially now at this tyme</div>
<div>As one ffather hardes the kinges beademan ending</div>
<div>his praier said Jesus Christe very god and man:</div>
<div>$herecie$ one tolde hym, that Christ was nat man, and in</div>
<div>farther reasonyng said that Christ appering after</div>
<div>his resurrection was but a spirite, This tale the said</div>
<div>$n$ father herd<em>es</em> hath shewid secretely to Mr. Shether</div>
<div>And it is to be feared (if it be true) that the <em>par</em>son</div>
<div>w<em>hich</em> rehersid it ones hath rehersid it oftener /</div>
<div>$Mr. Commis<em>ser</em>$ Mr. Comissary docto<em>ur</em> Nevenson rebuked on Lent</div>
<div>was xii moneth Sir John write preist dwelling</div>
<div>$co<em>n</em>fession$ in S. Alpheges because he wolde not absolve</div>
<div>Barthelmew Joy w<em>ith</em>out any confession made of ony</div>
<div>cryme or fawte as the said Sir write can testifie</div>
<div>$George hard<em>es</em>$ James Hardes exa<em>min</em>ed saith, that george Hard<em>es</em> about</div>
<div>vii monethes past in the quire of <em>Christ</em>e churche at <em>the</em></div>
<div>elevacion of the chalice said to this Inquisite prayng thus</div>
<div>Almyghtie god my blessid savio<em>ur</em> both god and man <em>preser</em>ve</div>
<div>me this day and ev<em>er</em> frome my mortall enemy the devill</div>
<div>At whiche prayer george Herd<em>es</em> standing by said to this</div>
<div>$herecie$ depone<em>n</em>t, what Cosen, why pray you so far, He is </div>
<div>$n$ god and no man, why q<em>uo</em>d he, what make yo<em>u </em>of <em>Christ</em>e,</div>
<div>did he not rise both god and man, No q<em>uo</em>d george, He</div>
<div>rose god, but not man, for he rose but in spirite</div>
<div>wherunto I answered I beleve that he rose both god</div>
<div>and man, nullo alio pr<em>ese</em>nte</div></body></xml>