<xml><body><div>@r13@ @n4@</div>
<div>M<em>emorandum</em> to examyn <em>the</em> Doctor of Chilham, Du<em>n</em>dy <em>that</em> was an</div>
<div>ob<em>ser</em>vant frear, Mr Sentliger, Mr Parkehurst, and other, Gardin<em>er</em>,</div>
<div>A bricklayer called Burgrave, Browne of Chartam, of</div>
<div>articles co<em>n</em>teyned in a shete of paper. wrytten <em>with</em> myn own hande, begy<em>n</em>ninge</div>
<div>The Doctor of Chilham.</div>
<div>$n$ Sandwich bifore ca<em>n</em>delmas was xii month.</div>
<div>$sclaunderous$ He made ii veray seditious <em>ser</em>mons in <em>the</em> chapter howse, callynge</div>
<div>the p<em>re</em>chers <em>that</em> were lately com hither waterlaggers. and that they</div>
<div>had taken away gooddes wourde from them. and that they shuld never be</div>
<div>$n$ ridde of them till they purged them w<em>ith</em> smoke and fire</div>
<div>$sclaunderous$ Uppon Easter day last past he did agayne inveye agayn against preachers.</div>
<div>beating unto the peoples heddes that somme had called our ladye a</div>
<div>saffron bagge. and that the woulde our lady to have no honour. and </div>
<div>that some did take apon them to mi<em>n</em>stre whiche were no preestis.</div>
<div>and that some did utterly deny absolution and then he made suche</div>
<div>exclamations / Crying out heretikes fagotts fire, as though</div>
<div>$n$ thies thinges had been co<em>m</em>mitted here agayn in dede D. Thornden</div>
<div>$sclaunderous$ The Second day of September last past he did agayn inveye</div>
<div>against preachers that had as he saied preached against Vocall</div>
<div>praier. by whos meanes the people had layde away their beades</div>
<div>and Laten primars, but he counsailled them to take them ageyn.</div>
<div>Milles</div>
<div>$sclaunderous$ In a <em>ser</em>mon made in <em>the</em> chapter howse bifore est<em>er</em> last past, dyd</div>
<div>invey agaynst <em>the</em> p<em>re</em>chers, <em>that</em> they dyd p<em>re</em>ch that agaynst vocal prayer</div>
<div>&amp; fastynge.</div>
<div>The Co<em>m</em>missary</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ Complaynt was made to hy<em>m that</em> the holy sacrament of the</div>
<div>aultare was not renewed in the church of Bucklande nere</div>
<div>ffev<em>er</em>sham by <em>the</em> space of ii yeres, but he passed ov<em>er</em> the cause</div>
<div>w<em>ith</em>out reformation.</div>
<div>Sandwich, Milles, Shether &amp; Serles</div>
<div>$n$ $<em>the</em> busshope of Rome$ Nome of they<em>m</em> have p<em>re</em>ched agaynst the usurped power of</div>
<div>the Busshope of Rome &amp; sett out the kynges maiestie sup<em>re</em>micie</div>
<div>accordynge to the kynges maiesties letteres i<em>n</em>ju<em>n</em>ctions &amp; <em>pro</em>clama-</div>
<div>tions.</div></body></xml>