<xml><body>Aft<em>er</em> this Mr dean of christechurch wrot to me <em>that </em>he was co<em>m</em>mawnded<br />by one of the kyng<em>es</em> prive cownsell to require Mr serles (if he wer<br />at cant<em>erbury</em>) &amp; me to come as secretly as we myght to london And <br />when I came to him to the kyng<em>es</em> courte I asked hym whether my <br />lordes grace of cant<em>erbury</em> did send for me or no &amp; he said nai, he knew <br />not of it And biddi<em>n</em>g me tary vnto that he hadd spoken w<em>ith</em> one<br />when he retoorned agayn to me he willed Mr <em>par</em>kurst Mr garden<em>er</em> &amp; me <br />to repare to Mr baker &amp; so we did / When we came to Mr baker he<br />said to vs thus : The kyng<em>es</em> grace hath delyv<em>er</em>yd me a booke which<br />he hath <em>per</em>used him selfe &amp; bicause <em>that</em> he <em>per</em>cevith <em>that</em> yow 3 (and <br />wisshed also for Mr serles) can say somwhat in it: he willith <add data-tag="add">yow </add>to<br />say what yow know fering no<em> per</em>son but to dread only one god<br />&amp; one kyng. Wheruppo<em>n</em> we took the book &amp; drew owt such articles<br />as we could witnes of And delyveri<em>n</em>g hym the book said <em>that</em> allthowh<br />we 3 present could not witnes in the articles he hadd delyv<em>er</em>d<br />us yet ther was in cant<em>erbury</em> <em>that</em> could witnes of them./ Vpon w<em>hich</em> woordes<br />he willed us to go to cant<em>erbury</em> &amp; me (bicause I was yongest) to retoorn<br />agayn aft<em>er</em> that I hadd maid the booke p<em>er</em>fecte in the day &amp; yere and <br />caused it to be subscribed &amp; to bring him the book agayn <em>per</em>fectly<br />maid. &amp; so we de<em>par</em>ting frome Mr baker went to the bisshope off<br />wynchest<em>er</em> &amp; shewed him what Mr baker hadd said to us And he <em>per</em>using<br />the booke we hadd maid (leving owt tharticles <em>that</em> wer towching <br /><em>the </em>co<em>m</em>munycation <em>that</em> was betwext my lordes grace &amp; Mr garden<em>er</em> only)<br />he said it was well ynowgh &amp; so badd us go agayn to Mr baker &amp;<br />tell him <em>that</em> <em></em> he said so. vpon w<em>hich</em> woordes we retoorned to Mr baker and<br />aft<em>er that</em> we hadd declared to him my lord of wynchesters mynd he<br />receved the book &amp; so we took o<em>ur</em> leve of him. <br /><br />At this tyme my lord of wynchest<em>er</em> asked me what the articles were<br /><em>that</em> my lord<em>es</em> grace of cant<em>erbury</em> obiected to me and I shewd him the articles<br />&amp; the declaration my lordes grace enioned me at the w<em>hich</em> he only <br />mused a season &amp; said nothing &amp; as he went to talke w<em>ith</em> other we<br />tooke o<em>ur</em> leve of him./.</body></xml>