<xml><body>$6$ Item yn what thyng or thynges they kno my lordes Grace Culpable yn / of <br />ther<em>e</em> owne knolege and how they dyd kno hyt<br />To thys I suppose. yff my lordes grace had at <em>the</em> fyrst begynyng ponesched<br />at such as were Culpable for <em>the</em> p<em>re</em>chyng of as mr Sayntlegeres &amp; I dyd <br />desyre hys grace to do at <em>the</em> puttyng up of owr<em>e</em> Booke. thys Busenes had<br />not be set forth but all shold have byn at a peace<br />$7$ It<em>e</em>m the lyke to be Mynstred for <em>the</em> <em>pro</em>cedyng of the same mat<em>er</em> at Cant<em>erbury</em><br />To thys I sey as y have <del data-tag="del">seyde </del>Awnswered yn the fformor <del data-tag="del">syxyth</del><br />syxth Arti<em>cle</em><br />$8$ It<em>e</em>m how manye Justyce of peace Gentylme<em>n</em> &amp; other <em>per</em>sons they have had<br />co<em>n</em>ference w<em>ith</em> / yn these mat<em>er</em>ys / And what they or other of the<em>m</em> have don <br />or ffavor yn the Same mat<em>er</em>ys<br />To thys I make Awnswere &amp; sey I Remembre not that they shold had any<br />co<em>n</em>ference to any Justyce of pece Gentylme<em>n</em> but onely to <em>sir</em> John Baker <em>sir</em><br />Thomas Moyle &amp; mr Thwaytes. &amp; what &amp; ev<em>er</em>y of the<em>m</em> hath don as <br />concernyng sir John Baker &amp; mr Thwayttes ther<em>e</em> doyng as mych as I do<br />remembre ys specyfyed a fore <add data-tag="add">at Bekes Borne</add>. as concernyng sir Thomas Moyle. I sewed yo<em>ur</em><br />grace that At Greye yn. when <em>the</em> Mat<em>er</em> was Shewed unto hym by mr<br />Garden<em>er</em> mr Schether &amp; me. by &amp; by he dyd remyt us to <em>sir</em> John Baker <br />a gayne<br />$9$ Item to what thyng they have cu<em>n</em>duced unto<br />To thys y sey I ca<em>n</em> not Shewe wherto or to <del data-tag="del">w</del> what thyng they have<br />co<em>n</em>duced unto. unles hyt be unto payne <del data-tag="del">&amp;</del> peneschment and to <br />unquyetnes</body></xml>