<xml><body><div>$Images$ Peple may knele bifore images w<em>ith</em> their bookes &amp; beads</div>
<div>kysse their feete, sence they<em>m</em>, &amp; offre to they<em>m</em>, so <em>that</em></div>
<div>they directe al this hono<em>ur</em> to the sayntes in heavyn.</div>
<div>$seditious$ As Christ was accused by ii or iii false knaves,</div>
<div>so a man may be accused by ii or iii false knaves,</div>
<div>&amp; <em>the</em> juge as false a knave as <em>the</em> best, &amp; so be co<em>n</em>de<em>m</em>ned</div>
<div>The next sonday aft<em>er</em>.</div>
<div>$Images$ I dyd <em>pro</em>ve by Ezechiel, hieremy, saynt Paule &amp;</div>
<div>Origene, <em>that</em> an image was none idole.</div>
<div>I called theym water laggers</div>
<div>$seditious$ You ar greved <em>with</em> me bicause I called they<em>m</em> wat<em>er</em>laggers</div>
<div>which have chaunged our good wyne into wat<em>er</em>.</div>
<div>Truly I cowde invent no fytt<em>er</em> name for they<em>m</em>, but</div>
<div>evyn as I said than, so I say agayne. I bishrewe </div>
<div>their hartes for me. Thay ar come hither &amp; have</div>
<div>corrupte our good wyne. I wolde thay wolde get</div>
<div>they<em>m</em> home agayne thither fro<em>m</em> whens they cam</div>
<div>But they must be smoked &amp; purged rownde about</div>
<div>w<em>ith</em> fire, or elles we shal nev<em>er</em> be rid of they<em>m</em>.</div>
<div>$seditious$ Som of you thought <em>that</em> som sholde have been</div>
<div>hanged, but if you had de<em>ser</em>ved no more to be burned</div>
<div>than thay have to be hanged, you sholde both do</div>
<div>wel enough.</div>
<div>plura quere fo. seque<em>n</em>te.</div>
<div>Shether. 23 Apriles in <em>the</em> chapt<em>er</em> howse.</div>
<div>$sclanderous$ Now a dayes good christians thay tech no thynge but</div>
<div>carnal libertie. No man doth teach you the commaund-</div>
<div>me<em>n</em>tes of god, no man doth p<em>re</em>ch unto you goddes lawes</div>
<div>yea no man dare do it, or rather wil do it not.</div>
<div>15 Maii at saynt Stevyns.</div>
<div>$sclanderous$ He made the people bileve w<em>ith</em> a grete multitude words</div>
<div><em>that</em> they had p<em>re</em>chers here which had p<em>re</em>ched agaynst a</div>
<div>vocal prayer, &amp; had called vocal prayer no thynge but</div>
<div>babelynge &amp; lippe labour.</div>
<div></div></body></xml>