<xml><body>Edmond Schethers answer unto 34 Articles.<br />$1.2.3.$ To the first, 2 &amp; 3. I can not depose in but by relation <add data-tag="add">of Mr <em>par</em>kurst<br />master sentlenger &amp; other.</add><br />$4.$ I hard my lordes grace rebuke serles for that he preiched somuch<br />of ymages &amp; my lord said that imago &amp; idolu<em>m</em> was one but I <br />reme<em>m</em>ber not that my lord<em>es</em> grace rebuked him for thes woordes <br />rehersed in the article<br />$5.$ I hard my lordes grace say in his chamber befor many his<br />prebendares &amp; preachers that the kyng<em>es</em> plesur was to haue .3.<br />preachers of the new lerni<em>n</em>g &amp; 3. of the old but I hard not thes<br />woordes spoken in the consistory<br />$6.$ I know not who accused them or whether thei wer suspect for<br />evell opynions<br />$7.$ I did se .3. w<em>hich</em> cam volu<em>n</em>tarily to testifie for mr serles w<em>hich</em> could not <br />be admitted as mr serles said Also I req<em>ui</em>red that the vicar of north<br />gat : mr selleng<em>er</em> : mr garden<em>er</em>: coxston might be examened in my first<br />article namly : but by reison of delay the said vicar was <br />wered &amp; not examened &amp; whether the other wer examened or no <br />I can not tell.<br />$8.$ In the deposition of my first article then obiected was admitted <br />george may &amp; sir hu<em>m</em>frey cherdeyn: <em>per</em>sons suspect for evell<br />opynions by co<em>m</em>myn fame as I hard And certayn other w<em>hich</em><br />deposed aganst mr serles wer likwise suspecte. And befor sente<em>n</em>s<br />I desired my lordes grace to haue respecte to <em>the</em> <em>per</em>sons <em>that</em> did depose.<br />$9.$ I think them innocent p<em>re</em>chers And I did rede A declaration<br />of articles surmised agaynst me: But by whome serles was <br />co<em>m</em>mitted to p<em>ri</em>son I can not tell. <br />$10.$ By reson <em>that</em> I and serles wer willed to rede declarations<br />in the which it was mentioned that thes wordes which<br />we said wer seditiously spoken : I think the occasion of my <br />accusation did rise bicause that I did somtymes speake aga<em>n</em>st<br />evell opynions And therfor I have spoken the lesse aganst<br />the same syns bycause I wold avoid like occasion &amp; further I<br />can not say in the article<br />$11.$ Sir bland: Sir t<em>ur</em>ner: mr scory have be noted much bolder syns<br />the tyme of the said accusation uppo<em>n</em> what occasion ells I know <br />not And who hath hadd <del data-tag="del">occasion</del> displesur for co<em>m</em>playni<em>n</em>g I can<br />not tell<br />$12.$ I know nother of the ymages nor of the letters.</body></xml>