<xml><body>quyetnesse : And so att the last : Syr Coxson one off the pety canons In <br />christes churche : (then levyng) dyd comyn w<em>ith</em> me. whatt was best to be<br />don : (ffor he had herd off doctor wyllybys beyng ther :) ffor thententt<br />to have an unyfforme : a quyett : and a godly p<em>re</em>chyng  w<em>ith</em>ow<em>t</em> all Jars :<br />In tyme cu<em>m</em>myng :. he det<em>er</em>myd to draw thys boke off my lordes co<em>m</em>munyca-<br />tyon. <add data-tag="add">when off partt was thatt we schuld nott make Invectyves in the polpett</add> on trinyte sonday : had emongst us p<em>re</em>bendarys : and the resydew <add data-tag="add">also he dye</add> : as hytt <add data-tag="add">her apperyth</add><br />followythe : butt nott all : ffor the artycle off ymages and the VI p<em>re</em>chers<br />I drew : Off thys drawgthe don by coxson no man dyd know butt I : <br />ffor he wold nott have hytt knowne : and unto thys tyme no man dyd<br />o<em>ther</em>wyse know : butt thatt hytt was my drawgthe : Thys drawgthe made :<br />and w<em>ith</em> my hand w<em>ri</em>tyn: I schewyd hytt unto mr Th<em>w</em>ayttes : butt he sagely :<br />$he namyd my lord of wynchester &lt;  &gt;or any other namy<em>n</em>g &lt;  &gt;man$<br />(as he ys a wyse man) wold thatt wyllyby schuld be ware : and aske<br />cowncell : off suche as knew best: whatt to be don. In soche matt<em>er </em>: ffor hytt<br />was a waygthy matt<em>er</em> :.: Unto thys boke coxson dyd adjoyne : the boke<br />In ffore tyme. unto my lordes g<em>ra</em>ce p<em>re</em>sentyd co<em>n</em>c<em>er</em>ny<em>n</em>g the p<em>re</em>chynges :: off mr Rydley<br />and mr Scory : he wrotte dyv<em>er</em>se coopys : and then hytt was nott knowne : thatt<br />any had hytt butt he : Thys boke drawne was delyv<em>er</em>yd unto doctor wylly-<br />by : hys bylles also were delyv<em>er</em>yd unto hym nott lokyd on : nor medlyd with<br />And so he havy<em>n</em>g the boke : whyther he wentt w<em>ith</em> hytt: unto whom he resor-<br />tyd. and shewyd the boke : In good ffayzthe I know nott : Butt unto <br />london he wentt : and ther beyng he sentt downe a copy off thatt boke :<br />by whoys motyon. I nor none off my co<em>m</em>pany doo know <add data-tag="add">as I can here off </add>: he wrotte thatt<br />he must nedes have hytt subscrybyd : We wentt to gyther and subscrybyd<br />the boke : thorowly : thatt was then newly made : Thes sett therunto<br />ther handes : mr Sentleger : mr <em>par</em>khurst : mr huntt: I willi<em>a</em>m Gardn<em>er</em> : mr mylles<br />mr Schether : Syr Coxson : Syr Coxx :. All thes nott subscrybyng unto ev<em>er</em>y<br />artycle : butt summe unto one : summe unto an other : as we knew them<br />trew : So thatt they all were subscrybyd unto : emo<em>n</em>gst us : : Mr Serles<br />subscrybyd nott : ffor he was then other In london : other I oxfford : whether<br />off bothe I am nott sewar : butt he was nott emo<em>n</em>gst us : and knew nott<br />then : off the boke made :. Thatt don. doctor wyllyby : had the boke a gen <br />unto whom he p<em>re</em>sentyd hytt: or dyd schew hytt : and w<em>ith</em> whom he hadd</body></xml>