<xml><body>@r303@<br />To the fyrst I do a<em>n</em>swer <em>that</em> I a<em>m</em> ygnora<em>n</em>t yn &amp; so to the 2 &amp; to the 3<br />To the 4 I say <em>that</em> yo<em>ur</em> grace yn co<em>mun</em>ycatyo<em>n</em> sayd <em>that</em> Idol<em>um</em> &amp; Imago yn<br />the greke wer all one more I rem<em>em</em>bre not.<br />To the vth I a<em>n</em>swer affyrmatyvely. <br />To the vith I say <em>that</em> shether was <del data-tag="del">accusyd </del>wytnessyd agay<em>n</em>st by <del data-tag="del">the </del><br />george maye off say<em>n</em>t Johns wych was by comy<em>n</em> fame notyd suspectyd<br />who accusyd serlys I kow not<br />To the viith I say <em>that</em> serlys sayd <em>that</em> certay<em>n</em> off hotfyld could not be<br />takyn to hys behalff yn testymony. to the resydew off thartycle I ca<em>n</em> <br />not a<em>n</em>swer<br />To the viiith I ca<em>n</em> not otherwyse the<em>n</em> to the vith artycle.<br />To the ixth I a<em>n</em>swer <em>that</em> forsomych as I could take off ther <em>ser</em>mo<em>n</em>s<br />they wer ynnoce<em>n</em>t. &amp; the one declaryd on a stole <em>that</em> that he <br />nev<em>er</em> p<em>re</em>chyd at norgate as I dyd beare away &amp; who put the <br />other to p<em>ri</em>so<em>n</em> I kow not<br />To the xth I say <em>that</em> have herd shether <del data-tag="del">&amp; serlys saye</del> <add data-tag="add">as I reme<em>m</em>bre</add> saye <em>that</em> yt ys<br />a wo<em>n</em>derfull world <em>that </em>me<em>n</em> dare not preche frely, but shall be accusyd<br />but to the resydew I ca<em>n</em> not a<em>n</em>swer, nother to xith.<br />To the xiith I say <em>that</em> ii ymagys off <em>Christ</em> &amp; ii pyctres off o<em>ur</em> lady wer pullyd<br />dow<em>n</em> <del data-tag="del">&amp;</del> but whether any oblatyo<em>n</em> hath byn unto the<em>m</em> I kow not<br />Doctor nevy<em>n</em>so<em>n</em> w<em>ith</em> a com<em>m</em>andeme<em>n</em>t fro<em>m</em> yo<em>ur</em> grace wyllyd mr setleger &amp;<br />other off the p<em>re</em>bendarys to pull downe owne &amp; the other <del data-tag="del">wil </del><add data-tag="add"> or su<em>m</em> off the<em>m</em> </add>wer<br />pullyd <del data-tag="del">by </del>dow<em>n</em> by yo<em>ur</em> gracehys l<em>ett</em>re as they say <em>that</em> wer at <del data-tag="del">hoe</del> home<br />I was not therfor I kow not the tennyre off the l<em>ett</em>re.<br />In the 13 &amp; 14th &amp; xvth. I a<em>m</em> ygnora<em>n</em>t, &amp; so yn the xviith<br />To the xvith I say that the yndyteme<em>n</em>t co<em>n</em>cernyd mr scorys p<em>re</em>chy<em>n</em>g<br /><em>that</em> the sup<em>per</em> off the lord was not sac<em>ri</em>ficiu<em>m</em> <em>pro</em> p<em>e</em>c<em>a</em>tis but hostia laud<em>is</em>,<br />&amp; he had yt off the clerke off the peace. <br />To the resydew off thartycles I say <em>that</em> I a<em>m</em> ygnora<em>n</em>t yn<br /><br />John myllys.</body></xml>