<xml><body>$8$ The last tyme I was at london w<em>ith</em> Mr baker <del data-tag="del">he badd me go and se a book<br />of articles that</del> <add data-tag="add">I went to</add> Mr moyle <del data-tag="del">hadd &amp;</del> to shew him also as to doctor london the<br />article of sir bland <em>quod</em> missa no<em>n</em> est sac<em>ri</em>fitiu<em>m pro</em> p<em>ec</em>c<em>a</em>tis And when I shewd<br />mr moile the said article he said : alas is then mor articles yet agaynst <br />him he hath to many all redy And by reson it was then night I d[id]<br />only drink w<em>ith</em> him &amp; he said he wolde helpe to a q<em>ui</em>etnes asmuch as in h[ym]<br />lay in thes matters &amp; so I de<em>par</em>ted frome hy<em>m</em>./ Also mr garden<em>er</em> shewed me that <br />$Mr Thwait<em>es</em>$ he hadd deliv<em>er</em>d certayn articles to mr thwatt<em>es</em> to whome I sent at <br />doctor cokes co<em>m</em>ming by <em>the</em> advice of Mr garden<em>er</em> to have a bill w<em>hich</em> thei of<br />s. georges hadd put up to him: to thintent it might be p<em>re</em>sented to doctor<br />cokes And he sent it me w<em>ith</em> mo billes w<em>hich</em> wer presented befor to the said<br />doctor cokes. As for any co<em>m</em>munycation I nev<em>er</em> hard them say but <em>that</em> th[ey?]<br />trusted we shuld have a q<em>ui</em>tnes in opinions &amp; <em>that</em> all thing shuld be w[ell?]<br />I know not w<em>ith</em> whome other have spoken in thes matters.<br />$9$ I know not to what thing<em>es</em> thei have conduced unto.<br />$Petitt$ I know nothi<em>n</em>g <em>that</em> petit hath done but <em>that</em> he delyv<em>er</em>d the book coxston wrot las[t]<br />&amp; gave it to mast<em>er</em> baker <del data-tag="del">co<em>n</em>strary <add data-tag="add"></add></del><add data-tag="add">contrary</add> to his p<em>ro</em>mys <add data-tag="add">maide</add> to mr garden<em>er</em> &amp; me w<em>hic</em>h told h[ym]<br />$10$ that it was un<em>per</em>fecte &amp; not <em>pro</em>ved in many poyntes. Also one night at Mr<br /><em>par</em>khurst<em>es</em> at sup<em>per</em> talking of the sessions of the 6 articles he redd a form<br />or copy of an endightment having no mans name Nor I know not whi<br />he redd it but only to shew (as I think) a forme of such endightme<em>n</em>t<em>es</em> as<br />wer used at the 6 articles<br />$11.$ I know no man that ev<em>er</em> entended ony other thing then to have a un[ite?] <br />&amp; quietnes in opinions and all co<em>n</em>tention to cease./<br />$12.$ I can not say of other me<em>n</em> but aft<em>er</em> that Mr baker willed me to note the che-<br />fist berers &amp; authors of thes new opynio<em>n</em>s we thowght I could do no bes[t]<br />but write such thing<em>es</em> as I harde And therfor I can say litle in this <br />matt<em>er</em> but as I se my writing to put in me in reme<em>m</em>bra<em>n</em>s. <br />Whether I spake of ony such thinge at chari<em>n</em>g I ca<em>n</em> <add data-tag="add">not </add>tell byt I reme<em>m</em>ber <em>that</em><br />$n$ at mr <em>par</em>kurst<em>es</em> table in cant<em>erbury</em> as one spake of preachi<em>n</em>g in thanet (I said) <br />(as it is trew in dede) <em>that</em> I was nev<em>er</em> ther syns I cam in to kent: but <br />bicause I hard the cowntrey so gretly co<em>m</em>mended. I said I longged to goe<br />thither: upon w<em>hich</em> woordes mr mylles (I think) said. whi let us. 4 Mr garde(ner)<br />I, mr serles and yow go thither one day And bicause ther be viii churches b[?]<br />us prech 2 <em>ser</em>mons a peice &amp; so in all the churches in one day And after<br />we will make myrry ther a bowt a day or 2 &amp; come home agayn<br />here is all the intent &amp; <em>pro</em>rses I know was hadd in the same not I nev<em>er</em><br />hard mor of it. Or if I spake of it at charing it was by reson th<em>a</em>t the <br />vicar of charing desired me to prech at his benefice ther: that I told<br />him what we talked of thanet one day / but I do not well reme<em>m</em>ber</body></xml>