<xml><body><div>@r57@ @n20@</div>
<div>good people forasmoche as sainctes be circumscripte, it ys</div>
<div>not possible for that saincte that is in the north to here <em>the</em></div>
<div>prayer that is made in the southe, nor the saincte that is</div>
<div>in the south to here the prayer that ys made in the northe</div>
<div>witnes william hunte, william gardener, Jo mylles</div>
<div>$+$ Robert Serles, Jo ffallowfelde</div>
<div>21 Septembr<em>is</em> 1543</div>
<div>$Strawghwyn$ He said in the wedensdaye of the Rogacion weke laste</div>
<div>paste at davyngton, you be not bounde <em>(quod</em> he)</div>
<div>to beleve any thing w<em>hich</em> is not written or co<em>n</em>teyned</div>
<div>in the holie scripture, Nor ought to beleve, any</div>
<div>other thing, than godes wourde founde in holie scripture</div>
<div>$prayinge to sayntes$ In the same sermon he said as towching praying to</div>
<div>sainctes I deny it quyete q<em>uo</em>d he knacking therat</div>
<div>his fyngers</div>
<div>It<em>e</em>m he said that sainctes can neith<em>er</em> helpe us / nor</div>
<div>here us / nor do nothing for us</div>
<div>He said that the holie water is no better than other</div>
<div>water / John Seth. Rich<em>ard</em> Dryland. laurence ma<em>n</em>by.</div>
<div>John hampton Nic<em>holas</em> Burdwash. Joseph Bev<em>er</em>slay. Tho<em>mas</em> Transam. John pelleyne.</div>
<div>Cleme<em>n</em>t Norton. Tho<em>mas</em> Deve. Tho<em>mas</em> Okinfeld. Raynold Becke. willi<em>a</em>m Amoore.</div>
<div>Ro<em>bert</em> ffynes. Rich<em>ard</em> Stickney</div>
<div>The vii daye of novembre A<em>nno</em> 1541</div>
<div>$George of Cant<em>erbury</em>$ I John tofere <em>par</em>son of S Georges in Canterbury did</div>
<div>$Co<em>m</em>missary$ write unto my Curate John Paris and the churche</div>
<div>wardens Mr. Rand and Mr. Bartilmewe to take down</div>
<div>$Images$ the ymage of S George at the co<em>m</em>mandment of Mr.</div>
<div>Comissarye being then in london, yf it be not don</div>
<div>before my co<em>m</em>myng home I will see it down myself</div>
<div>according to my masters l<em>ett</em>re / I and the cherche warde<em>n</em>s</div>
<div>did take it down the ymage. The fryday after Mr.</div>
<div>Comissary sent for the forsaid Jo paris curate and</div>
<div>the churche wardens aforsaid and asked, whither ye</div>
<div>have pulled down the ymage of s. george or no: thei made </div>
<div>answer and said yea, have ye cut it in pec<em>es</em>? thei said</div>
<div>no : than said the Comissarye. It is not only the kyng<em>es</em></div></body></xml>