<xml><body><div> @r9@ @n2@</div>
<div>Serles 2</div>
<div>The 26 of August last past in <em>the</em> chapt<em>er</em> howse</div>
<div>Ther be su<em>m</em>me sy<em>n</em>nes <em>that</em> can not be forgyven but by</div>
<div>fastynge &amp; prayer.</div>
<div>Good peple you have been deceyved w<em>ith</em> p<em>re</em>chers, but</div>
<div>$III$ if you have receyved any poyson &amp; lerned any false</div>
<div>doctrine &amp; byleved by ignorance, you be not to blame,</div>
<div>neither god is discontent w<em>ith</em> you.</div>
<div>$III$ In hel is burnynge of brymston, wilde fier, gu<em>n</em>powd<em>er</em>,</div>
<div>soden hete, soden colde. And we may be sure therof</div>
<div>bicause <em>that</em> David Moses &amp; <em>the</em> <em>pro</em>phetes, which taught</div>
<div>us those thynges, were in the paynes of hel, or in</div>
<div>$At Ashforth 12 Augusti: A<em>nno</em> 1543$ a kynde of hel which is limbo.</div>
<div>At layname</div>
<div>In the howse of Mary and or Martha he fownde a</div>
<div>certen man veray sicke and sore diseased, whose name</div>
<div>was Lazarus brother to thies ii virgyns.</div>
<div>Magdalen was a faire fyngered gentle woman.</div>
<div>$or religion$ Christ said to Martha. Thy busynes shal have an</div>
<div>ende, but thy sisteres busynes shal last &amp; nev<em>er </em>have ende.</div>
<div>Sandwich al<em>ias</em> Gardin<em>er </em>in <em>ser</em>mon in</div>
<div>Christes church <em>the</em> iiide sonday aft<em>er</em> xii day.</div>
<div>$seditious$ The peple have not had hitherto <em>the</em> good wyne of</div>
<div>goddes worde, but a day wolde com <em>that</em> they sholde have</div>
<div>good wyne agayne, B But good peple be co<em>n</em>tent, for</div>
<div>no<em>n</em>du<em>m</em> venit hora. the tyme is not yet come <em>that</em> you</div>
<div>sholde have good wyne.</div>
<div>$sclaunderous$ Of late dayes you have had here so many wat<em>er</em>laggeres,</div>
<div>which have turned yo<em>ur</em> good wyne into wat<em>er</em>, <em>that</em> you</div>
<div>cowde have no good doctrine taught ne preched<ne preched="">, unto you, but the</ne></div>
<div>phantasies of their own braynes.</div>
<div></div></body></xml>