<xml><body><div>@r87@ @n35@</div>
<div>$Raynold buckmer$ The saying and opinion of Raynold Bucker of</div>
<div>Boxley spoken and obstinately declared by</div>
<div>hym in the feast of thassumption of o<em>ur</em> lady</div>
<div>$d$ or the Sonday after in the xxxi yeres</div>
<div>of the king<em>es</em> ma<em>jestes</em> most noble Reign in the</div>
<div>$n$ hous of John Man of Boxley in the <em>pre</em>sence</div>
<div>and hearing of thesame John Man John</div>
<div>Todd and John Stockwell. whiche</div>
<div>Raynold Buckm<em>er</em> was abjured by the</div>
<div>lorde warham. late Archebishop of Cant<em>erbury</em></div>
<div>which abjuration Mr. Docto<em>ur</em> Leef, Mr.</div>
<div>of maidestone college can declare more</div>
<div>at length</div>
<div>$vi articles$ ffirst he said That the Sacrament of thault<em>er </em>was</div>
<div>$n$ breade as other breade was / and that the knave</div>
<div>preestis did receyve hym before none / and did pisse</div>
<div>and shit hym out at whores arsses at aft<em>er</em> none</div>
<div>Which accusation was taken before <em>Sir</em> Christofer</div>
<div>hailes knight deceased at maideston the xxii yer of the</div>
<div>king<em>es</em> moost noble Reign / and in writing deliv<em>er</em>ed to Mr.</div>
<div>Nevenson now Com<em>m</em>issarye by henry Cloake then servau<em>n</em>t</div>
<div>to thesame <em>Sir</em> Ch<em>rist</em>ofer, and also thesame henry Cloke</div>
<div>did heare thesame wourd<em>es</em> of buckm<em>er</em> rehersed by the</div>
<div>witnes aforesaid. and also declared it to the said com<em>m</em>issary.</div>
<div>And aft<em>er</em>ward the same <em>Sir</em> Chr<em>ist</em>opher sent for thesaid</div>
<div>Buckm<em>er</em> and the witnes to maidestone by Rauf Johnson</div>
<div>his <em>ser</em>vau<em>n</em>t / which Rauf deliv<em>er</em>ed thesaid buckm<em>er</em> to the</div>
<div>co<em>m</em>missary / and also the witnes, Where the co<em>m</em>missary</div>
<div>thretened the said John Todd as he saieth and will say.</div>
<div>and for a while thesaid buckmer was in my lorde</div>
<div>Archebishops palace as they said underward. But</div>
<div>he went at large and did pull hemp: And aft<em>er</em> the</div>
<div>death of the said <em>Sir</em> Chr<em>ist</em>ofer or a litle before, thesame</div>
<div>Buckmer was sent home ayen unponyshed contrarye</div>
<div>to the king<em>es</em> lawes. And thus bearing and favo<em>r</em></div>
<div>$n$ w<em>ith</em> suche like hath been courage o to other ill doers</div>
<div>co<em>n</em>cerning ill opinions</div></body></xml>