<xml><body><div>Int<em>er</em>rogatories for Doctor London</div>
<div>Whether he thretened Serles bicau co<em>m</em>mawnded Serles</div>
<div>opon palme sonday evyn to wryte such articles erroni[ous]</div>
<div>as had been p<em>re</em>ched in Kent.</div>
<div>Whether Serles brought <em>the</em> articles opon palme sonday</div>
<div>Whether he required Serles to go w<em>ith</em> hy<em>m</em> to the</div>
<div>councceil to p<em>re</em>sent <em>the</em> said articles, or elles to subscribe</div>
<div>they<em>m</em> w<em>ith</em> his hand, &amp; Serles refused so to do, bicause</div>
<div>they were not <em>pro</em>ved by witnes, but onely by hearesay</div>
<div>Whether he thretened Serles bicause he wolde not</div>
<div>sette his hande, notw<em>ith</em>standynge <em>that</em> Serles knewe they<em>m</em></div>
<div>not but by hearesay.</div>
<div>How Doctor london dyd fynde out Serles, &amp; how longe</div>
<div>he had enquered for hy<em>m</em> bifore he cowde fynde hy<em>m</em>.</div>
<div>Whether in <em>the</em> p<em>re</em>sens of Serles Doctor london d</div>
<div>penne they <articles> articles anewe otherwise than they were</articles></div>
<div>ted.</div>
<div>Whether Mr. Serles said than to Doctor willoughby</div>
<div>(whom D<em>octor</em> london had <em>per</em>suaded to go w<em>ith</em> hy<em>m</em> to <em>the</em></div>
<div>counseil.) beware what you do, for you shal nev<em>er</em></div>
<div>be able to <em>pro</em>ve they<em>m</em> of this sorte <em>that</em> Doctor london doth</div>
<div>now penne they<em>m</em>.</div>
<div>Whether beside the boke subscribed by div<em>er</em>se p<em>re</em>bendaries</div>
<div>&amp; other of Canturbery D<em>octor</em> london made an other</div>
<div>grete booke of many mo articles.</div>
<div>Where <em>that</em> boke is, &amp; of whom he had his instructions.</div>
<div>What matters he knewe agaynst tharchbusshope of</div>
<div>Canturbery or other in Kent<or others="" in="" kent="">, bifore palme sonday last past, when he</or></div>
<div>had articles of S<em>ir</em> Serles, &amp; of whom he had such</div>
<div>knowlege bifore before <em>the</em> said day.</div></body></xml>