<xml><body><div>w<em>ith</em>out any confession of her parte of her fawte, or</div>
<div>offensis, or w<em>ith</em>oute any requiring of her parte of any</div>
<div><em>par</em>don, you have a thing to sticke to, w<em>hich</em> may do you</div>
<div>good, I advise you to sticke to it, than did she bring</div>
<div>forthe the kyng<em>es</em> <em>par</em>don whiche was geven to the</div>
<div>$n$ Anabaptist<em>es</em> for thair delive<em>r</em>ance repentyng them</div>
<div>self<em>es</em>, which pardon what els it conteyned, be it</div>
<div>in your Judgeme<em>n</em>t</div>
<div>Also at that tyme Toft<em>es</em> the elder Stode in the</div>
<div>consistorye there pleading her cause for her</div>
<div>defence, where before he nev<em>er</em> was procto<em>ur</em> in that</div>
<div>Courte nother sythe</div>
<div>Also at that tyme came forthe to the courte the <em>par</em>son</div>
<div>of Westbere w<em>ith</em> ii honest men of the parishe, that</div>
<div>said that thei harde her husbande say that she was</div>
<div>abjured at Colchester, Than said Mr. Comissary do</div>
<div>you know it for trueth that she was abjured, No</div>
<div>said thei, but thus said her husbande, Than said Mr.</div>
<div>Comissary I tak you for no witnes in this poynt</div>
<div>and so deliv<em>er</em>ed her she requiring no <em>par</em>don nor</div>
<div>Confessing her offence why the<em> par</em>don sholde be</div>
<div>ministred to her</div>
<div><span style="white-space: pre;"> </span>Witnes to this John Mill<em>es</em> preiste</div>
<div>$+$ Also ther was one Jonas was maried at</div>
<div>Saincte Johns house w<em>ith</em>out Northgate to the dowght<em>er</em></div>
<div>of one Marshe of barham, he being a preiste as the</div>
<div>voice went, but the trueth is she is maried unto</div>
<div>an other and Jonas stale awaye /</div>
<div>$Scory$ Also one Mr. Store preachid in saincte Elphis</div>
<div>churche Apon Assention daye was xii moneth</div>
<div>saying, ye have a saying, The childe w<em>hich</em> is borne</div>
<div>betwene man and wife, it is borne in originall</div></body></xml>