<xml><body><div>The vicar of ffeversam.</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ $n$ $1$ He dyd not declare to hys parishoneres opon candelmas day</div>
<div><em>the</em> true use of berynge candelles as <em>that</em> day, nether of palme</div>
<div>sonday or goodfriday <em>the</em> true use of those dayes ceremonies</div>
<div>in beringe of palmes &amp; crepynge of the crosse, nether at</div>
<div>any tyme he hath declared <em>the</em> true use of holy brede or</div>
<div>holy wat<em>er</em>, as he is bownde to do by <em>the</em> kynges maiesties</div>
<div><em>pro</em>clamations.</div>
<div>$lent$ $2$ He co<em>m</em>manded <em>the</em> wife of one Newman a Ta<em>n</em>ner in</div>
<div>his parish, <em>that</em> she sholde not lie w<em>ith</em> her husbande du-</div>
<div>rynge the tyme of lent</div>
<div>$crysom cloth$ $3$ He co<em>m</em>manded <em>the</em> crysom cloth w<em>ith</em> a bel to be hanged out</div>
<div>uppon <em>the</em> dedication day, which hertofore was hanged</div>
<div>out to put <em>the</em> peple in reme<em>m</em>brance of pardon <em>that</em> they</div>
<div>sholde have <em>that</em> tyme</div>
<div>$pater nost<em>er</em> in English$ $4$ He moved in co<em>n</em>fession John Tacknal to use his pat<em>er</em> nost<em>er</em></div>
<div>in English no more, for he knewe not how soone <em>the</em></div>
<div>worlde wolde chaunge.</div>
<div>$5$ To like effecte he moved deacons wife &amp; Lambes wife</div>
<div>whan they were co<em>n</em>fessed</div>
<div>$Incontynencie$ $6$ He was taken suspiciously wi<em>th</em> a woman by iiii men,</div>
<div>so that he gave promised to iii of they<em>m</em> xx s to holde their peace.</div>
<div> $lent$ $7$ He said <em>that</em> if the Kynge were examined he wolde co<em>n</em>fesse</div>
<div><em>that</em> he gave no leave to eate whytmeate in lent, but</div>
<div>unto sicke <em>per</em>sons.</div>
<div>The <em>par</em>son of westbere</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ He hath not declared thuse of holy breade, holy water,</div>
<div>halowed candelles, asshes, palmes, &amp; crepinge the crosse.</div>
<div>He said <em>that</em> the<em>re</em> were iii hevyns, one for veray poore men,</div>
<div><em>the</em> seconde for men of a meane state &amp; co<em>n</em>dition, <em>the</em> iiide</div>
<div>for grete men.</div>
<div>He is a commn dice player, &amp; a commen hawnt<em>er</em> &amp; resorter</div>
<div>to tavernes &amp; ale howses.</div>
<div>Sir humfray Cotton chantry preist at Te<em>n</em>terde</div>
<div>He said <em>that there</em> be herecies in <em>the</em> bible.</div>
<div>He said <em>that</em> ev<em>er</em>y christen man beinge baptised &amp; holpen</div>
<div>by <em>the</em> grace of god, is in as ful state of fre wil, as Ada<em>m</em></div>
<div>was bifore his fal.</div>
<div>He hath a boke of <em>pro</em>phecies.</div></body></xml>