<xml><body><div>@r29@ @n6@</div>
<div>The <em>par</em>son of pluckley</div>
<div>Stevyn Giles said <em>that</em> he blessed hy<em>m</em>selfe dayly and nightly</div>
<div>sayinge In no<em>m</em>i<em>n</em>e patris et filii et spiriti s<em>anc</em>ti, And than he said</div>
<div>in <em>the</em> hono<em>r</em> of god and our lady &amp; al the co<em>m</em>pany of hevyn, </div>
<div>&amp; for al christen sowles <em>that</em> god wolde have prayed for,</div>
<div>a pat<em>er</em> nost<em>er</em>, an Ave &amp; a crede. To whom <em>the</em> <em>par</em>son of pluckley</div>
<div>said, <em>that</em> if he knewe it of truth <em>that</em> the said Stevyn</div>
<div>used the same forme of prayer, he wolde not acco<em>m</em>pany</div>
<div>hy<em>m</em>, nor ones drinke w<em>ith</em> hy<em>m</em> </div>
<div><em>Sir</em> hu<em>m</em>fray Chirden <em>par</em>son of S<em>aint</em> Elphyns.</div>
<div><em>the</em> first sonday in lent last past</div>
<div>If Judas had gone to god, &amp; co<em>n</em>fessed his fawte, sayinge</div>
<div>Peccavi, as he went unto <em>the</em> preistes, he had not</div>
<div>been da<em>m</em>ned.</div>
<div>Vincent Ingeam.</div>
<div>$Injunctions$ he co<em>m</em>mawnded in Est<em>er</em> monday <em>the</em> 33 yere of the kynges</div>
<div>reigne <em>that</em> no man sholde reade nor heare <em>the</em> bible</div>
<div>$ex$ $n$ red opon payne of imprisonment, &amp; cast ii in prison, </div>
<div>for <em>the</em> one for spekynge agaynst hy<em>m</em> therin, &amp; the other</div>
<div>for shewinge hy<em>m</em> the kynges inju<em>n</em>ctions co<em>n</em>cernynge the same</div>
<div>wytnes <em>the</em> hole parish of saynt peteres</div>
<div>$Images$ he co<em>n</em>tended ag repugned agaynst <em>the</em> doinge of <em>the</em></div>
<div>Co<em>m</em>missary, for takynge downe <em>the</em> image of saint John</div>
<div>by <em>the</em> kynges co<em>m</em>mawndment. witnesses Mr John mast<em>er</em></div>
<div>Thomas pynnocke. Peter holam. Daniel Cranm<em>er</em> et al</div>
<div>Christmas men.</div>
<div><em>Sir</em> Thomas Curat of Sholden</div>
<div>Thomas Sawier.</div>
<div>$Images$ have set vp agayne iiii images which by <em>the</em> kynges co<em>m</em>mawnd-</div>
<div>$n$ ment were taken downe for abuses by pilgrimages and offe-</div>
<div>rynges, <em>that</em> is to say, <em>the</em> image of s. Nicolas, s. Stevyn, s.</div>
<div>laurence &amp; our lady. wytnesses Thomas Southowsand.</div>
<div>william kenerdale. &amp; william Norres .</div>
<div>Thomas Bleane of north Mongeam.</div>
<div>$Images$ Whan <em>the</em> images ther sholde have been defaced for abuses <em>ther</em>of</div>
<div>he co<em>m</em>manded <em>the</em> preist &amp; church wardens to let they<em>m</em> alone</div>
<div>$n$ $+$ &amp; contynue a while, sayinge <em>that</em> such wayes sholde co<em>n</em>tynue but</div>
<div>a while, &amp; <em>that</em> they sholde see shortly. And an image w<em>ith</em> iii</div>
<div>crownes standeth nere unto his own seate tyl this day.</div>
<div>willi<em>a</em>m Norres and william ken<em>er</em>dale.</div></body></xml>