<xml><body>@r251@<br />In the name of god Ame<em>n</em>. I N. preacher of christchurch in cant<em>erbury</em> bownden to answer befor<br />yow most reverd father in god thomas archbisshop of cant<em>erbury</em> &amp; metropolita<em>n</em> of ingland or your <br />chawnsler or ony other co<em>m</em>petent iudge in <em>that</em> behalfe In a certay<em>n</em> cause as yet unde-<br />cited &amp; dependi<em>n</em>g co<em>n</em>cerni<em>n</em>g articles which be pretended: <del data-tag="del">(allthough untrewly) y (my</del><br />(allthowghe (my bow<em>n</em>de dewty allwais to yo<em>ur</em> grace <add data-tag="add">remembred</add> ) untrewly) to be preched by me<br />in yo<em>ur</em> gratiouse dioc<em>ese</em> of cant<em>erbury</em> ffor asmuch as yow most rev<em>er</em>end father in god do<br /><em>pro</em>ced against me in the same by <em>the</em> v<em>er</em>tew of yo<em>ur</em> office: I the befor named N. (savi<em>n</em>g<br />&amp; Reservi<em>n</em>g allwais all other lawf<em>u</em>le defens which I may at ony tyme or place<br />lawf<em>u</em>ly use &amp; poorpose) say &amp; alledge in this writi<em>n</em>g the co<em>n</em>trary <del data-tag="del">namly</del>  to<br />article or articles of heresy pretended And namly &amp; expressly aga<em>n</em>st this article which is <br />ministerd aga<em>n</em>st me (allthrough untrewly) in this forme: yow pr<em>e</em>ched etc. And<br />by all such circu<em>m</em>stans &amp; forme of law as I ca<em>n</em> or owght to do I say &amp; <br />poorpose aga<em>n</em>st the forme &amp; effecte of the same article &amp; any other na<em>m</em>ly t<em>hat</em> <br />is heretically (allthowgh untreuly) ministerd aga<em>n</em>st me: And I say <em>that</em> thowghe<br />I preached the day &amp; yere <del data-tag="del">as is</del> specified in <em>the</em> said p<em>re</em>tended (<del data-tag="del">allthough untrewly</del>)<br />article : at sandwich yet I preched not<del data-tag="del">that day</del> <add data-tag="add">as it is contened in your article that article</add> nor any other<br /><del data-tag="del">heretickal </del>hereticall <del data-tag="del">Notwithstandi<em>n</em>g that as towching this said article I preached</del> <br />woords so<em>m</em>what <em>per</em>tayni<em>n</em>g to <em>the</em> same <add data-tag="add">but I preched as concernyng that article the saide xxiiii day </add>under this forme followi<em>n</em>g or woords of <br />like sente<em>ns</em> &amp; effecte vz t<em>hat</em> not only such as wer baptised havi<em>n</em>g <em>the</em> use of reyso<em>n</em><br />wer p<em>ur</em>ged both fro<em>m</em> origenall &amp; actuall sy<em>n</em> but also infa<em>n</em>t<em>es</em> wer p<em>ur</em>ged fro<em>m</em> orige-<br />nall sy<em>n</em> by v<em>er</em>teu of <em>the</em> same sacrame<em>n</em>t so t<em>hat</em> aft<em>er</em> bapty<em>m</em> no sy<em>n</em> remaynith And<br />I preched no other <add data-tag="add">wise nor under other forme</add> things <del data-tag="del">as</del> in effecte as co<em>n</em>cerny<em>n</em>g that matt<em>er</em> as by lawf<em>u</em>le &amp; dew<br /><em>pro</em>ff shall appere <del data-tag="del">at the end of the <em>pro</em>rses</del> <add data-tag="add">in <em>this pro</em>rses</add>. Also I alledge t<em>hat</em> this article hath no<br />apparens of verite but is play<em>n</em>ly ymagened &amp; s<em>er</em>mysd aga<em>n</em>st me &amp; co<em>n</em>taynith<br />much craft &amp; s<em>u</em>btillty <del data-tag="del">in it</del> <add data-tag="add">&amp; is intricat obscure &amp; uncertaynly conceved</add> &amp; is such as I am not bownd by the law to<br />a<em>n</em>swer unto as doth &amp; shall appere at the end of this <em>pro</em>rses <add data-tag="add">wherfor I desire it may be playlen to me declared</add> : Also ther is<br />a co<em>m</em>myn voice &amp; fame <add data-tag="add">in the vill</add> of sandwich &amp; other places which use unto my <unclear data-tag="unclear">audres </unclear>do affirme this <br />that this my allegation to be iust &amp; trew. It. <em>that</em> ther wer any honest and descet p<em>er</em>sons<br />which wold have noted sone such a notoriose heresy it it had be spoken.</body></xml>