<xml><body>@r289@<br />M<em>emorandum</em> that my lord grace dyd send unto me a Booke of xxvi Arti<em>cles that</em> I sholde make<br />Awnswer unto them wyth spede. Trewly y had so lytyle a tyme for so mych As <br />my lord<del data-tag="del">es</del> <add data-tag="add">dyd</add> send unto me ii tymys yn a day for my Awnswer. ffor so mych as I had<br />so Evel tyme &amp; su<em>m</em>what I was desesed. I cowde not yn that space Cal to my Reme<em>m</em>brence<br />enly thyng. Wher for sync<em>e</em> that tyme. I have reme<em>m</em>bred Mor as hyt followyth yn the boke<br /><br />In primis as co<em>n</em>cernyng <em>the</em> 6 Art<em>icle</em> wher hyt <add data-tag="add">was </add>demawnded of me. whyther <em>the</em> honest off<br />ther Audyence offeryd them selvys &amp; s. <br />Thys I made Awnswer that ther<em>e</em> war dyv<em>er</em>se on &amp; I thynke browght yn by mayster<br />Serelys &amp; wer<em>e</em> not examened whether they offered them selvys to be sworne or<br />Any Requiryng for use to be sworne. y ame not seure ther<em>e</em> of. But ther<em>e</em> Certeyne<br />dyd Apere y thynke suerely for <em>that</em> purpose <br />Synnys that tyme I have callyd to my Rembrance thys thyng co<em>n</em>cernyng the same<br />Aft<em>er</em> that I was Examyned yn the Chapetre howse. A fore mayst<em>er</em> Comyssery<br />ordynary und<em>er</em> my lord. doctor Barber. doctor Taylyo<em>ur</em> &amp; Mayst<em>er</em> Smyth<br />beyng deputed by my lordes grace to Exame<em>n</em> not onely those that wer<em>e</em> off<br />owre howse. But also both off the Cytye of Cant<em>erbury</em>. &amp; of the Cu<em>n</em>trey / My exami// <br />nacyi<em>n</em> done. / Mr Co<em>m</em>myssary doctor Taylor &amp; I wer to gether almost at the <br />Chapytre howse dore. They desyryng me at that tyme. to pacyfy mayster<br /><add data-tag="add">Sayntleger </add>beyng <del data-tag="del">beyng </del>be fore me Examened &amp; owte of pacyens as they seyde <add data-tag="add">to me</add>. Then<br />I sayde a gayne. maysters I woolde ther<em>e</em> wer<em>e</em> an Indyfferency used Amo<em>n</em>gst<br />yo<em>u</em>. yo<em>u</em> have Examened Certeyne off othefylde. wych ca<em>m</em> ageynst meyster <br />Serlys as I und<em>er</em>stand of the wych one was Rychard Godffrey by ffame<br />A suspect persone. her<em>e</em> at <em>the</em> dore <em></em><add data-tag="add"><em>the</em> syght </add>ar browght yn iii or iiii <del data-tag="del">browgh yn</del>. y thynke<br />by mr Serlys. Thys not wyth standyng alle they were yn Syght they wer<em>e</em><br />not Callyd yn to Examynacyon<br /><br />Item whither they that woolde speke a gaynst Evyll opynyons. dar not for<br />yff they doo. they be co<em>m</em>playned on &amp; Callyd Sodycyowse <em>per</em>sons. Styryng<br />men to co<em>m</em>mocyon &amp; by who<em>m</em> they be so Called. <br />To thys I Awnssered that I dyd not <add data-tag="add">remebre</add> to kno of any Suych persens.<br />Symys that tyme. I have Callyd to Reme<em>m</em>brance <em>the</em> Seyng off mr Garden<em>er</em> beyng<br />at london yn the passyon weeke was xii Monethys. My lorde Seyng unto<br />$Gardin<em>er</em>$ the<del data-tag="del">y</del> sayde mr Garden<em>er</em>. yo<em>u</em> preched of late yn Crystes Church at Cant<em>erbury</em><br />as I am Credably Informyd. yo<em>u</em> dyd make a Seducyows <em>ser</em>mond wher<em>e</em> by <br />Su<em>m</em> of yo<em>ur</em> Audyence wer<em>e</em> moch offended / to Thys mr Gardener Awsweryd</body></xml>