<xml><body>@r357@<br />Most reverend father yn god my hu<em>m</em>ble dewty reme<em>m</em>bryd unto yo<em>ur</em> <br />grace. And I knowyng ryght well <em>that</em> yn <em>that</em> I subscrybyd unto certayn<br />artycles (thoze unadvydesly) have showyd gret unkyndnes unto your<br />grace yn my so doyng &amp; agayne for <em>that</em> have deservyd lytle kyndnes<br />at y<em>our</em> grace hys hand: &amp; now do suffer cold ymprysonent at y<em>our</em> grace<br />hys pleasyre wych ys very tedyouse pay<em>n</em>full unto me &amp; as I fere gret<br />dau<em>n</em>ger myght ensue unto me by augme<em>n</em>tyng t<em>hat</em> cold and couhge <em>that</em> I have <br />take<em>n</em> before &amp; now yncreasyth. bysyde the ynward pe<em>n</em>syffnes off hart<br />take<em>n</em> for thys my rashe fact at our other ma<em>n</em>hys lyght motyo<em>n</em> <add data-tag="add">as </add><del data-tag="del">wyth</del><br />other off my <em>com</em>pany <del data-tag="del">which I thynk</del> dyd wych now (I thy<em>n</em>k) lame<em>n</em>tyth<br />the<em>m</em> mych. ye so mych <em>that</em> at such tyme as I have byn yn <em>com</em>pany wythe<br />the<em>m</em> I have herd the<em>m</em> <del data-tag="del">they </del>say that they could not slepe nether eate <em>that</em> <br />thyng or dry<em>n</em>k <em>that </em>dyd do the<em>m</em> mych good. as I a<em>m</em> one of the<em>m</em>. wherfor<br />most gracyous lord these p<em>re</em>mysses and other <em>con</em>syderyd by the wych syknes off<br />body may encrese &amp; the hart wast Thys shall to hu<em>m</em>bly beseche yo<em>ur<br /></em> grace to m<em>er</em>cyfully yntreate me &amp; <em>that </em>now I may fynd su<em>m</em> dropp off m<em>er</em>cy<br />at y<em>our</em> grace hys hand for thys my y<em>m</em>prysoment. Assuryng y<em>our</em> grace<br /><em>that</em> I shall take thys ponyshment for my lernyng &amp; not at any tyme<br />hereaft<em>er</em> to be so lyghtly alluryd at any ma<em>n</em>hys motyo<em>n</em> to put to <br />unadvysedly my hand or co<em>n</em>sent to any such matt<em>er</em> heraft<em>er</em>.<br />Now gratyouse lord shew pyte &amp; m<em>er</em>cy unto me. wych I do<br />aske off yo<em>ur </em>grace &amp; do hirtly desyre yt. w<em>ith</em> wepyng eyye &amp; sorowfull <br />hart as knowyth god.<br /><br />By yo<em>ur</em> John Myllys</body></xml>