<xml><body><div>$Imag<em>es</em>$ He saied that the sight of the ymage of saint</div>
<div>Michaell w<em>ith</em> the balaunce is enowgh to</div>
<div>bringe a man to the deviull</div>
<div>$pray<em>or</em> to saintes$ That no man may pray to Sainctz for any thinge</div>
<div>$Co<em>n</em>fession$ He saied that it was not necessary nor convenie<em>n</em>t</div>
<div>that men shuld confesse their offenc<em>es</em> <em>par</em>ticulerly</div>
<div>but that is was sufficient to say I am a synn<em>er</em></div>
<div>and have offendid in thought wourde and dede</div>
<div>$Imag<em>es</em>$ He saied That, to knele or bowe unto a crosse,</div>
<div>yea though it wer the veray crosse that Christ</div>
<div>dyed on it was Idolatrie /</div>
<div>$seditious$ He saied that bisshoppes did make priest<em>es</em> for mony</div>
<div>yea although they could stantely reade, and he</div>
<div>knewe it so to be /</div>
<div>$candelles$ He saied that they did nought that did sett up or</div>
<div>offre any candelles before the sacrament. and if</div>
<div>they wer well taught they wold not use suche</div>
<div>superstition. John Seth. Richard Drylande. laurence manby.</div>
<div>John hampton. Nicolas Burdwashe. Josepth Bev<em>erl</em>ay. Th<em>omas</em> Cra<em>n</em>se</div>
<div>John pellayne. Clement Norton. Tho<em>mas</em> Deve. Th<em>omas</em> Okenfelde.</div>
<div>Raynolde Becke. william amoore. Ro<em>bert </em>ffynes. Rich<em>ard</em> Stickney.</div>
<div>He saied that the masse is no satisfaction for</div>
<div>synne, nor therefore offred</div>
<div>$Co<em>n</em>fession$ He preached in Lynsted churche on saint Mathues</div>
<div>day in Anno 1542./ that auriculier confession is not</div>
<div>in the scriptur<em>e</em> of god /. nor in the lawe of god.</div>
<div>I m<em>er</em>vaill<em>e quod</em> he / why, hit is used in the churche</div>
<div>also q<em>uod</em> he, it hath been often put down</div>
<div>William Alban. Hugo Cru<em>m</em>pton preist Thomas ffarrer.</div>
<div>Raff Vouldegate. Rich lashforde. Antony Browne.</div></body></xml>