<xml><body><div>@r157@</div>
<div>Int<em>er</em>rogatories for Doctor willoughby</div>
<div>$1$ What tyme he first knewe of thies matter<em>es</em> &amp; by whom.</div>
<div>$2$ what co<em>mmun</em>ication he had w<em>ith</em> Serl<em>es</em> opon palme sonday</div>
<div>$3$ whether Doctor london dyd pe<em>n</em>ne the articles new</div>
<div><em>that</em> Serl<em>es</em> brought to hy<em>m</em>, &amp; altered <em>the</em> articles.</div>
<div>$4 3$ Whether Serl<em>es</em> said to this depone<em>n</em>t, beware what</div>
<div>you do, for you shal nev<em>er</em> be able to <em>pro</em>ve they<em>m</em> aft<em>er</em> this</div>
<div>sorte <em>that</em> Doctor london doth nowe<doth nowe=""> hath penned theym.</doth></div>
<div>whether <em>the</em> word<em>es</em> were spoken openly <em>that</em> D london</div>
<div>myght heare they<em>m</em>.</div>
<div>$4$ whether this deponent said to any <em>per</em>son <em>that</em> the Busshope</div>
<div>of wynchest<em>er</em> wolde gyve VIm li to plucke downe tharch-</div>
<div>busshope of Cantorbury.</div>
<div>$5$ whether <em>the</em> next day Serl<em>es</em> wrote to this deponent</div>
<div>to <em>pro</em>cede ernestly &amp; boldely w<em>ith</em> Doctor london as he had</div>
<div>bygonne.</div>
<div>$6 4$ what tyme it was <em>that</em> he said to Gardin<em>er that</em> he wolde</div>
<div>take opon hy<em>m</em> to be the only doer in this matt<em>er</em>.</div>
<div>$7 5$ whatt he dyd w<em>ith</em> the copie of <em>the</em> articles that were</div>
<div>delyv<em>er</em>ed to hy<em>m</em> the same tyme</div>
<div>$8 6$ whether he shewed <em>the</em> last booke <em>that</em> Shether sent</div>
<div>to hy<em>m</em> by his <em>ser</em>vant, to <em>the</em> busshope of winchest<em>er</em> or not</div>
<div>$9 7$ which of <em>the</em> cownceil dyd alowe hy<em>m</em> for puttynge up</div>
<div>of the boke, sayinge <em>that</em> he was a good catholicke man,</div>
<div>&amp; dyd animat hy<em>m</em> to be bolde to p<em>re</em>sent mo such</div>
<div>accusement<em>es</em>.</div>
<div>$10 8$ what co<em>n</em>fortable word<em>es</em> the counseil gave hy<em>m</em> to go about</div>
<div>thies matter<em>es</em>.</div>
<div>$11 9$ who informed hy<em>m that</em> a co<em>m</em>mission sholde com down into</div>
<div>kent, &amp; <em>that</em> <em>Par</em>kehurst, milles &amp; Gardin<em>er</em> sholde be co<em>m</em>missioner<em>es</em></div>
<div>$12 10$ what co<em>mmun</em>ication he had w<em>ith</em> Mr. ffoggre of a ser lecture which</div>
<div><em>the</em> Archbusshope sholde reade of <em>the</em> sacrament of thaultare,</div>
<div>&amp; who were p<em>re</em>sent, &amp; what was said of ev<em>er</em>y man.</div>
<div>$11$ how many were named to be co<em>m</em>missioneres.</div></body></xml>