<xml><body>@r197@<br />off hym why hys g<em>ra</em>ce dyd so hardly bere me In tymes past : he sayde : <br />yow were co<em>m</em>playnyd on unto me by a c<em>er</em>ten p<em>er</em>son : and thatt a tale was<br />browghte unto hym a yenst me : Then sayde I : my lord I wyll declare<br />the tale and the p<em>er</em>son unto yow<em>r </em>g<em>ra</em>ce : thatt made the tale : And so I dyd<br />And now all ys well. I thanke god : and so well : thatt my lordes<br />g<em>ra</em>ce wyllyd me to resortt unto hym boldly : and so schall I doo by my<br />ffaygthe : ffurther more mr Copyn sayde : By my trowgthe I dare say :<br />my lord ys noo berar In thes matt<em>er</em>s : They be o<em>ther</em> ewysse sayde mr copyn :<br />And namyd none : butt keptt all sec<em>re</em>tte ffrom me : glad thatt he was<br />In soche ffavor w<em>ith</em> my lorde : And so de<em>par</em>tyd ffrom me. <br />$m$ My lord : yff thatt Syr John Baker knythe had nott sentt ffor us<br />unto london : And Incoragyd us by thes wordes : ffere no man : butt<br />god and the kyng : And the kynges hygnesse wyllythe yow to ffere<br />none butt hym : We wold nev<em>er</em> attemptyd so ffarr In the matt<em>er</em> as<br />we have don : And besydes thatt he wyllyd us to resortt unto my lord<br />off Winchest<em>er</em> wher as also we <em>per</em>ceyvyd noo re<em>pro</em>che unto ys gevyn ffor<br />ow<em>r</em> dede : ffor yff by any off thes or any other off the cowncell we<br />had byn rebukyd ffor ow<em>r</em> doynges (as I wold we had) And the <br />danger schewyd unto us : wheroff we had noo knowlege : ffor my<br /><em>par</em>tt I say off my co<em>n</em>scyence. I wold have gon home a gen nott <br />medlyng : Wherffor my good ffather (Althowghe I drew ii off the <br />Artyclys p<em>re</em>sentyd (and noo moo as god schall save me) I can doo <br />noo lesse then to blame them or hym thatt sentt ffor us : thatt w<em>ith</em><br />wordes beffore rehersyd dyd Incorage us : w<em>ich</em> were ignora<em>n</em>tt off the danger<br />off the ffacte : And dyd <add data-tag="add">nott </add>rather re<em>pro</em>ve us : sayng thatt they or he<br />had knowlege off the danger And nott wee : Gentyll ffather<br />ponder myne ignorawnce : and as yow have <em>pro</em>mysyd fforgeve unto me<br />my trespasse<br />I reme<em>m</em>ber thatt att c<em>er</em>ten tymys : I wrote c<em>er</em>ten artyclys : suche (as men<br />sayde) they ffownd them selffe g<em>re</em>vyd w<em>ith</em> : And toke ther handes or sygnes<br />unto the artyclys : I beseche yow<em>r</em> g<em>ra</em>ce : blame nott me ffor hytt : butt<br />$mr Twaites$ mr Thwaytes w<em>ich</em> soo to doo movyd mr <em>par</em>khurst and me : : mr thwaytes</body></xml>