<xml><body><div>Edwarde Dyngleden of Rolvynden.</div>
<div>$pilgrimages$ he hath forsaken his own parish church at <em>the</em> tyme of</div>
<div>Est<em>er</em> thies ii yeres togither, &amp; hath gone to walsyngam</div>
<div>&amp; wolde at no tyme shewe to <em>the</em> Vicar a lawful certi-</div>
<div>$n$ ficate <em>that</em> he had receyved <em>the</em> blessed sacrament at <em>the</em></div>
<div>tymes co<em>m</em>monly accustomed as a christen man ought to do</div>
<div>$pat<em>er</em> nost<em>er</em> in english$ he obstinatly refuseth to lerne his pat<em>er</em> nost<em>er</em>, Ave, Crede and</div>
<div><em>the</em> x co<em>m</em>maundme<em>n</em>tes in English, accordynge to <em>the</em> kynges</div>
<div>inju<em>n</em>ctions. The curate of Rolvenden, &amp; he can declare other</div>
<div>wytnes.</div>
<div>Sir Edwarde Spon<em>er</em> vicar of Boughton.</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ he hath not declared to his <em>par</em>ishioneres <em>the</em> right use of</div>
<div>ceremonies, neither shewed <em>the</em> difference bitwene they<em>m</em></div>
<div>&amp; workes co<em>m</em>maunded by god, as he is co<em>m</em>maunded by <em>the</em></div>
<div>$n$ kynges <em>pro</em>clamations</div>
<div>$<em>the</em> busshope of Rome$ he hath not p<em>re</em>ched agaynst <em>the</em> bisshope of Rome his</div>
<div>usurped power, &amp; set furth <em>the</em> kynges sup<em>re</em>micie, as he</div>
<div>is bownde by <em>the</em> kynges inju<em>n</em>ctions &amp; o<em>ther</em> his <em>pro</em>cedynges.</div>
<div>he hath not p<em>re</em>ched his quart<em>er</em> <em>ser</em>mons, neither at</div>
<div>Boughton, nor at his benefice in <em>the</em> marshe.</div>
<div>$proclamations$ he nev<em>er</em> declared <em>that the</em> evyns of such sayntes whose holy</div>
<div>dayes be abrogated, be no fastynge dayes. Witnes Mr</div>
<div>hawkyns with other of both his parisshes.</div>
<div>Archdiacon<em>us</em> Cantuarien<em>sis</em></div>
<div>$Images$ The morowe aft<em>er the</em> Ascension was iii yeres he toke out</div>
<div>of the church of saynt Andres in Canturbery iii lampes</div>
<div>taperes bre<em>n</em>nynge bifore the sacrament, &amp; a cote from a roode</div>
<div>&amp; dyd violently breake <em>the</em> armes and legges of <em>the</em> roode.</div>
<div><em>Sir</em> Willi<em>a</em>m kempe Vicar of Northgate</div>
<div>he hath not red the bible syns pentecost as he was co<em>m</em>maunded</div>
<div>by <em>the</em> ordinary</div>
<div>$ceremonies$ he doth not declare <to his="" parishioneres=""> to his parishoners the right vse of holy water, holy breade,</to></div>
<div>berynge of candelles opon candlemas day, gyvynge of Ashes, berin[ge]</div>
<div>of palmes, crepinge of <em>the</em> crosse. ffor lacke wherof <the most="" part=""> many yn most part of the</the></div>
<div>said parish be as ignorant in such thynges as ev<em>er</em> they were</div>
<div>&amp; many of theym do abuse the same holy wat<em>er</em>, In so much <em>that</em></div>
<div>agaynst tempestes of thonder &amp; lightenynge many do ru<em>n</em>ne</div></body></xml>